<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book review on Byte Geek</title>
    <link>/tags/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book review on Byte Geek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Habits by James Clear:Book Review</title>
      <link>/posts/atomic-habits-by-james-clear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/atomic-habits-by-james-clear/</guid>
      <description>This is a legendary book, its reputation proceeds it. All the productivity greats like Thomas Frank and Ali Abdaal have recommended it…so this month I have decided to check it out.
And boy, does it deliver.
Core ideas First, I think we should define what an “Atomic Habit” really is. Many of us think that to be successful, we should do great feats…but in fact, that is not true at all!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Minimalism by Cal Newport: Book Review</title>
      <link>/posts/digital-minimilism-by-cal-newport-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 16:06:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/digital-minimilism-by-cal-newport-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Yet Another Cal Newport Review, ay? You may be beginning to notice a pattern here. But seriously, The man is such an intuitive and practical writer.
If you are anything like me, you may find that a lot of precious time gets sucked away by the internet, or digital world. In fact, this has become such a problem that 92% of teens go online daily, and 24% say they go online “almost constantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work by Cal Newport:Book Review</title>
      <link>/posts/deep-work-by-cal-newportbook-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 11:57:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/deep-work-by-cal-newportbook-review/</guid>
      <description>Productivity books, we all read them kinda is becoming my guilty pleasure at this point. However, I have to give the book “Deep Work” some credit. Although this is my second reading, I still find enormous meaning from it.
The book is a non-fiction thesis on how “knowledge work” is valued in the economy, and how top achievers actually succeed. It also tackles the idea of “information overload” in our modern digital age.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
