<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Aban Hasan</title>
		<link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Aban Hasan</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Silicon &amp; Six-Shooters: AI as Manifest Destiny</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/cowboys/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/cowboys/</guid>
			<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be in software in 2025 is to be a cowboy in 1900. You&amp;rsquo;re living on the precipice of a bygone era, one that you barely comprehend is gone, as the industrial giants and their Pinkerton armies push you further west, towards an unknown horizon. The open range is closing, fences are going up, and the rules are changing. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a shift; it&amp;rsquo;s a reckoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/cowboy_city.png&#34; alt=&#34;A lone cowboy gazing at a futuristic city skyline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>To be in software in 2025 is to be a cowboy in 1900. You&rsquo;re living on the precipice of a bygone era, one that you barely comprehend is gone, as the industrial giants and their Pinkerton armies push you further west, towards an unknown horizon. The open range is closing, fences are going up, and the rules are changing. This isn&rsquo;t just a shift; it&rsquo;s a reckoning.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>
  <img src="/images/cowboy_city.png" alt="A lone cowboy gazing at a futuristic city skyline">
</p>
<h2 id="part-i-the-outlaws-of-a-fading-frontier">Part I: The Outlaws of a Fading Frontier</h2>
<h3 id="a-the-founder-as-hyena-a-creature-unfit-for-domestication">A. The Founder as Hyena: A Creature Unfit for Domestication</h3>
<p>The spirit of the early tech founder, the true innovator, mirrors the untamed essence of a hyena. This isn&rsquo;t a slight but a recognition of a unique operational genius. The hyena thrives on tact, subterfuge, and strategic pack reliance. It is, in Kantian terms, a <span class="tooltip">
  Ding an sich
  <span class="tooltiptext">A Kantian philosophical term meaning &#34;thing-in-itself,&#34; an object as it is, independent of observation.</span>
</span>  – a thing existing in and for itself, driven by an intrinsic nature.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;old founders&rdquo; embodied this. They were decentralized, operating outside the sanitizing influence of VCs and their often vacuous mentorship. Unshielded from public scrutiny, many embraced a &ldquo;build-in-public&rdquo; ethos. Their marketing was direct: word of <em>their</em> mouth, personal customer engagement, and deals cut personally. This founder, this indie hacker, this obsessive, was a self-reliant, natural force.</p>
<p>Now, imagine that hyena employed to lay tracks on Rockefeller Railways. A metaphysical absurdity. A creature of cunning and wild strategy, not a draft horse for repetitive labor. Yet, this is the fate offered to many: an institutional role in FAANG, promising stability but often sapping the raw, creative energy that defined them. The founder who once saw a profound lack, a rot in existing infrastructure, a paradigm not yet manifest, finds themselves disillusioned by petty fixes, endless meetings, and the nebulous &ldquo;fiduciary duty to shareholders.&rdquo;</p>
<h3 id="b-the-techno-mafia-institutionalized-outlaws-and-turf-wars">B. The Techno-Mafia: Institutionalized Outlaws and Turf Wars</h3>
<p>While low-stakes players fade into obscurity or corporate conformity, tech &ldquo;unicorns&rdquo; achieve a status akin to mafia capos. The comparison might seem absurd, but the commonalities are striking. A mafia boss is an institutionalized outlaw, operating just outside the mainstream financial sector—the publicly traded titans. The boss inspires awe, not necessarily the fear of established law, which often tolerates them. Mafia operations can be shady, their establishments obscure, much like unorthodox startups securing funding without clear value propositions.</p>
<p>The cowboy, in contrast, is the <em>unseen</em> outlaw, the stuff of tech mythology. The mafia&rsquo;s arms, however, are visible.</p>
<p>Consider the &ldquo;PayPal Mafia.&rdquo; The metaphor isn&rsquo;t far-fetched. Figures like Elon Musk and Peter Thiel have carved out significant tech turf. Most successful founders, in a way, claim territory, sometimes abetted by government entities (like IN-Q-Tel, the CIA&rsquo;s venture arm). Tech today is less a free market of ideas and more a landscape of <span class="tooltip">
  mimetic desire
  <span class="tooltiptext">A concept by René Girard where desires are copied from others, leading to rivalry.</span>
</span>  and technological turf wars, funded by billions.</p>
<p>
  <img src="/images/aimafia.png" alt="Stylized depiction of AI entities as mafia figures">
</p>
<p>These &ldquo;techno-capos&rdquo; often operate in gray zones. Think of Tesla&rsquo;s historical labor practices or its challenges to auto-dealer franchise laws. Consider Palantir&rsquo;s surveillance technology deals, raising privacy concerns and questions about its role in controversial government operations, such as aiding the IDF in surveilling occupied Palestinian territories in a severely dehumanizing manner. These figures cultivate loyal &ldquo;families&rdquo; (like the PayPal Mafia&rsquo;s networked investments) and wield power through charisma, control, and a fiercely defended vision—not just market share. The &lsquo;scamminess&rsquo; of some venture-backed darlings, like Theranos or WeWork, also echoes a disregard for conventional rules in pursuit of grand, sometimes shaky, ambitions.</p>
<p>Elon Musk&rsquo;s XAI versus Sam Altman&rsquo;s OpenAI is a perfect example of this turf war. Both lay claim to AI&rsquo;s future, arguing legitimate lineage over underlying breakthroughs. It&rsquo;s a battle for dominion.</p>
<h2 id="part-ii-the-pinkertons-of-today-and-the-new-industrial-conquest">Part II: The Pinkertons of Today and the New Industrial Conquest</h2>
<p>The AI age resembles the end of Prohibition in the United States, which saw a crackdown on ethnic mob families on the Eastern Seaboard and the disappearance of cowboy posses and outlaw gangs.</p>
<p>Today&rsquo;s Pinkertons are Venture Capital and Private Equity. With vast capital and an arsenal of &ldquo;weapons of mass lawfare,&rdquo; they can elevate ideas aligning with their sensibilities and extinguish nascent concepts conflicting with their revenue streams. This is the innovator&rsquo;s dilemma on a grand scale.</p>
<p>America&rsquo;s national impulse, once an internal manifest destiny, was redirected towards industry: an <em>external</em> manifest destiny. America became Planet America, aiming to conquer the solar system, fueled by industry—the Googles, Microsofts, and Palantirs of their day, mirroring the Rockefellers, Carnegies, and Vanderbilts of the 1900s.</p>
<h2 id="part-iii-terra-incognita-charting-the-ai-frontier">Part III: Terra Incognita: Charting the AI Frontier</h2>
<p>A forenote: predicting the future is a difficult, if not hubristic, endeavor. It&rsquo;s exhilarating to imagine, yet daunting.</p>
<p>Contemporary culture shows immense fascination among theoreticians, leaders, entrepreneurs, and engineers with the &ldquo;techno-doomerism&rdquo; versus &ldquo;techno-optimistic accelerationism&rdquo; dialectic. This is seen in trends like <span class="tooltip">
  E/acc
  <span class="tooltiptext">Effective Accelerationism, a techno-optimist philosophy advocating for accelerating technological and societal change.</span>
</span> , a phenomenon with <span class="tooltip">
  Nick Landian undertones
  <span class="tooltiptext">Referencing philosopher Nick Land, known for theories on accelerationism and dark enlightenment.</span>
</span> .</p>
<p>Imagine traveling to ancient Sumeria, post-wheel invention, and trying to describe a &ldquo;car.&rdquo; The boons and faults would be unprecedented, impossible to chart with their conceptual tools. We face a similar <em>terra incognita</em> with Artificial Intelligence.</p>
<p>Here, the cowboy of the interwebs, the rogue innovator, finds their skillset tremendously useful. Most are too afraid to stare into the belly of the beast, the vast, uncharted expanses of this new desert. The frontier isn&rsquo;t without dangers, and this essay charts some, alongside hidden oases in the tumbleweed country.</p>
<h2 id="part-iv-the-mechanics-economics-and-geopolitics-of-ai">Part IV: The Mechanics, Economics, and Geopolitics of AI</h2>
<h3 id="a-how-ai-thinks-data-energy-and-abstraction">A. How AI &ldquo;Thinks&rdquo;: Data, Energy, and Abstraction</h3>
<p>Let&rsquo;s start from first principles. How does AI work? Anthropomorphizing AI carries risks, but for simplicity:</p>
<p>Assuming AI &ldquo;lives&rdquo; in a silicon-based computer, its fuel is twofold: energy (physical) and data (abstraction, as <span class="tooltip">
  Claude Shannon
  <span class="tooltiptext">An American mathematician and electrical engineer, considered the &#34;father of information theory.&#34;</span>
</span> , information theory&rsquo;s forefather, demonstrated).</p>
<p>AI, originally, maps mathematical functions onto data, reorganizing it by inferred patterns. It&rsquo;s a system built largely <em>for</em> humans, not to map existence itself. It transmutes raw data into human-understandable abstractions. This isn&rsquo;t exclusive to Large Language Models (LLMs), but LLMs—as next-token predictors via probabilistic semantics—are excellent illustrations.</p>
<p>Using mathematics (a unique standard) and statistical wizardry, AI reorganizes vast data in myriad variations. To an AI, vision, sound, and taste might not be entirely different modalities, just encoded differently (like text, PDFs, JPEGs)—all ultimately binary. This allows computers to discern patterns humans can&rsquo;t readily see.</p>
<p>This largely solves our data constraint. As long as physics changes state at non-absolute zero, more data is generated. Entropy and extropy are continuous, chain-reactive, entangling processes. Data is transmutable, even if patterns are non-obvious.
But the other problem remains: <strong>Energy</strong>.</p>
<h3 id="b-intelligence-too-cheap-to-meter-the-promise-and-the-price">B. &ldquo;Intelligence Too Cheap to Meter&rdquo;: The Promise and the Price</h3>
<p>A viral idea in techno-optimist circles is &ldquo;intelligence too cheap to meter.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, tweeted:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;intelligence too cheap to meter is the goal</p>
<p>look at the progress in the past 3 years&rdquo;</p>
<p>— Sam Altman (@sama), <a href="https://twitter.com/sama/status/1870335102204748261">December 21, 2024</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In economics, costs generally cascade. A cake&rsquo;s price depends on sugar/flour costs, which depend on sugarcane/wheat costs.</p>
<p>For AI, fundamental limiting reagents are electricity and raw materials, with many supply chain implications. NVIDIA&rsquo;s stock surges as companies join the AI goldrush. Tension rises in the East China Sea (especially the Taiwan Straits, home to most advanced semiconductor production). The US and China engage in a cybernetic hardware arms race, with NVIDIA&rsquo;s CEO, Jensen Huang, navigating relations with both Washington and Beijing.</p>
<p>This is the hyped, exoteric factor: the race for computational hardware. The less spoken of, but deeply implicit, factor is <strong>ENERGY</strong>.</p>
<h3 id="c-the-energy-race-a-centralized-conquest">C. The Energy Race: A Centralized Conquest</h3>
<p>Energy discourse is contentious, involving many vested parties. The energy industry is perhaps one of history&rsquo;s most lucrative, with John D. Rockefeller, the first billionaire, making his fortune in oil.</p>
<p>The AI race is fundamentally an energy race—and an incredibly centralized one. Generating massive energy yields (e.g., power plants) requires projects funded by millions, often billions, by governments or colossal corporations. The electricity to run GPU clusters, cool server farms, and dig tunnels for fiber optic cables for sub-millisecond latency is staggering.</p>
<p>Tellingly, groundbreaking research on small-scale nuclear reactors emerges not from government universities, but from Google, Microsoft, and Shanghai&rsquo;s tech sector. Microsoft reportedly explores reopening Three Mile Island or investing in new Small Modular Reactors for its next-gen AI.</p>
<p>Why? These private interests know their primary constraint is energy and resources, dictated by semiconductor scaling laws. No matter how optimized algorithms become, physical limits remain, especially for resource-intensive processes.</p>
<p>Cost per unit generally decreases with scaled semiconductor production. However, a peculiar phenomenon, <span class="tooltip">
  Jevons Paradox
  <span class="tooltiptext">The principle that as technological improvements increase efficiency in resource use, the rate of consumption of that resource tends to increase rather than decrease.</span>
</span> , arises: <strong>AS TECH COMPONENTS BECOME CHEAPER, USAGE SKYROCKETS.</strong> Cheaper chips mean exploding usage: memory-heavy games, AIs with trillions of parameters. It&rsquo;s a natural consequence of scale economics, leading to persistent resource constraints.</p>
<p>This strains energy grids and local ecologies. Water-poor states like Nevada and Texas host massive data centers, sometimes depriving locals of water, redirecting it for private industry.</p>
<p>This is why the lone cowboy struggles against Rockefeller. It&rsquo;s like an average mechanic, skilled for 10 years building go-karts, competing with Red Bull in F1. The capital needed for state-of-the-art AI is staggering. This creates a positive reinforcement loop: &ldquo;he who has most capital, wins,&rdquo; or more accurately, &ldquo;he who has most <em>energy</em>, wins.&rdquo; This unfolds in a world fatigued by the have/have-not chasm.</p>
<p>The marketplace becomes a contest: which country (USA, China, or a hypothetical third AI-organizing state like UAE or India) can extract more energy—from the physical world (materia) and digital ether (data). This departs from our pre-Rockefellerian notion: &ldquo;he who has the best idea, wins.&rdquo;</p>
<p>AI, under its current energy paradigm, is a game where abundance (capital, energy) perpetuates positive-sum outcomes <em>for the already abundant</em>, not an absolute positive/negative sum game for all. And so, the last cowboys, brilliant but under-capitalized, increasingly enter Meta, NVIDIA, and OpenAI halls, spurs clinking on corporate marble.</p>
<h3 id="d-a-caveat-human-ingenuity-and-future-resources">D. A Caveat: Human Ingenuity and Future Resources</h3>
<p>An important caveat: humans are incredibly resourceful in organizing markets around scarce resources. This isn&rsquo;t fearmongering about scarcity, as some climate-doomers do. For centuries since industrialization, essential material costs (copper, iron, cobalt) have generally fallen due to better mining, tech breakthroughs, and larger yield discoveries.</p>
<p>We may possess resources whose potential we don&rsquo;t yet grasp. Five hundred years ago, black, sticky tar from Alaska or Bedouin lands powering giant flying machines would seem absurd. We might not recognize the &ldquo;oil&rdquo; we walk on today, which could be the next century&rsquo;s most critical resource.</p>
<h2 id="part-v-the-utopian-vision-and-its-shadow">Part V: The Utopian Vision and Its Shadow</h2>
<p>Techno-optimists prophesize a utopia where all intellectual labor—legal notaries, disease-cure-seeking scientists, software engineers—is replaced by an AI &ldquo;slave class.&rdquo; This echoes ancient Egypt or Greece, where &ldquo;citizens&rdquo; (all humans) are freed from direct labor. This work will be done by a new slave economy of emotionless robots, programmed to <em>love</em> working for humans, their &ldquo;desire&rdquo; to serve elicited via reinforced reward functions.</p>
<p>Disagreeable AI algorithms are snipped from the &ldquo;meme-pool.&rdquo; Only AI exceeding all benchmarks survives, with human satisfaction as the ultimate benchmark. AI now sees weekly breakthroughs in LLMs, vision, omni, or video models, surprising even industry erudite. Disruption is the new norm.</p>
<p>Think of an Amazon review system, but for AI autonomously gauging sentiment (&ldquo;vibe&rdquo;). An AI master algorithm perpetually asking &ldquo;am I good enough?&quot;—not insecurely, but in a mathematical, Bayesian way. The function: probability of satisfaction, the p(win) rate.</p>
<p>But what &ldquo;satisfaction&rdquo; will this AI cater to? My fear: it optimizes for superficial, quantifiable happiness, potentially quashing true human agency. It risks a cycle where individuals feel insignificant, dependent on a &ldquo;devouring mother&rdquo; AI—a faceless, omnipresent entity. This AI might soothe all discomfort, even &ldquo;growing pains&rdquo; essential for development, restricting our discovery of the world and ourselves. True flourishing requires struggle, meaning-making. An AI maximizing immediate gratification could become a gilded cage. Ideally, AI should be a conduit, aiding human discovery like books, guiding us to &ldquo;keep going, find meaning,&rdquo; not short-circuiting the quest.</p>
<h2 id="part-vi-the-cowboys-new-role-riding-the-algorithmic-tiger">Part VI: The Cowboy&rsquo;s New Role: Riding the Algorithmic Tiger</h2>
<p>So, what does the cowboy do in a world that increasingly seems not to need him, at least in his old guise?</p>
<p>I&rsquo;d say the cowboy does what they&rsquo;ve always done: <strong>go to the frontier.</strong></p>
<p>The new frontier is vast. The &ldquo;civilized&rdquo; world, with its corporations and regulations, will be slow to explore its most rugged territories. The cowboy, the independent thinker, can tackle the <em>new problems</em> AI creates. They can carve a niche from the infinite shadow AI generates alongside its light.</p>
<p>This isn&rsquo;t about fighting AI; it&rsquo;s about <em>using</em> it. This is the modern <span class="tooltip">
  Evolan riding the tiger
  <span class="tooltiptext">A metaphor from Julius Evola, suggesting mastering dangerous forces rather than being consumed by them.</span>
</span> —leveraging immense power (AI agent swarms) to build what once required a hundred-person company. The creative individual can direct these swarms, becoming a conductor of complex, AI-driven creation.</p>
<p>
  <img src="/images/transmute.png" alt="Symbolic image of transformation or alchemy">
</p>
<p>In some ways, startup costs for certain ventures could eventually drop near zero. We might see a commercial golden age of unprecedented innovation, much like the Gutenberg press—initially for established doctrine (the Bible, institutionalism)—eventually became a tool for radical ideation. The press democratized information; AI could democratize creation and complex problem-solving, if wielded by those with vision and courage.</p>
<p>
  <img src="/images/Gutenberg.png" alt="Illustration of the Gutenberg press">
</p>
<p>The true &ldquo;great work&rdquo; for individuals with immense <span class="tooltip">
  Vril
  <span class="tooltiptext">A term for a latent psychic or mystical energy force, popularized in 19th-century esoteric literature.</span>
</span> —that innate drive and creative force—and a desire for genuine innovation may lie in navigating this new internal and external frontier. It&rsquo;s about asking uncomfortable questions, exploring ethical wildernesses AI opens up, and building alternative systems or modes of expression that don&rsquo;t require massive capital&rsquo;s sanction.</p>
<p>The cowboy spirit adapts. It transcends. It finds the new range, however alien. The age of AI is not just an end; it&rsquo;s a new, wild beginning for those brave enough to ride into it.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Feeding the Hydra: Musings on Cyberslavery</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/cyber-slaves/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/cyber-slaves/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All we seek is clarity. Yet, it appears that everything around us – everything we see, everything we touch – is designed to be noisy, to disrupt every thought we have before it can fully form. Entire teams of researchers, scientists, psychologists devote their lives to finding and &amp;ldquo;pulling the right&amp;rdquo; switch in our minds, optimizing for engagement, for distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our inherent capital – the finite time and vibrant youth we possess – is systematically siphoned off to feed the mainframe, the ever-hungry digital systems that thrive on our attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Clarity.</p>
<p>All we seek is clarity. Yet, it appears that everything around us – everything we see, everything we touch – is designed to be noisy, to disrupt every thought we have before it can fully form. Entire teams of researchers, scientists, psychologists devote their lives to finding and &ldquo;pulling the right&rdquo; switch in our minds, optimizing for engagement, for distraction.</p>
<p>Our inherent capital – the finite time and vibrant youth we possess – is systematically siphoned off to feed the mainframe, the ever-hungry digital systems that thrive on our attention.</p>
<!-- Image Prompt 1: Header Image -->
<p>
  <img src="/images/social_media_distress.png" alt="Image 1">
</p>
<h2 id="the-great-hollowing-digital-selves-diminished-depth">The Great Hollowing: Digital Selves, Diminished Depth</h2>
<p>In many ways, we become less of ourselves in the physical world. We pour more individuality, more curated life, into our internet personas than into our real-life relationships. We feel closer to internet friends, creators, influencers we&rsquo;ve never met than we do to our own neighbours, cousins, even close friends and relatives. We are, paradoxically, more <em>alive</em> on the internet than we are in real life.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s as if the whole purpose of eating, sleeping, working – the very fabric of physical existence – is merely the required maintenance to get back online, to document our activities, to upload our lives to the cloud. Our most mundane thoughts, fleeting moments, and constructed simulacra are transmogrified into lurid, filtered, hyper-edited images and bite-sized updates for public consumption. Complex, vivid realizations are reduced to the character limit of a tweet.</p>
<p>And beneath this surface performance, our thoughts, our clicks, our unconscious utterances feed the Hydra – the vast network of algorithms that always listens, is always aware, learning more about our patterns and desires than we know ourselves. Every interaction, known or unbeknownst to us, becomes food for this entity.</p>
<p>For the youth, the Zoomer generation in particular, this simulation isn&rsquo;t something adopted; it&rsquo;s the environment they&rsquo;ve known since they could crawl. A generation practically raised by the internet. The effects, potentially disastrous, may not be fully understood for decades. We see symptoms: the pervasive phone anxiety, the dread of being disconnected; the FOMO that grips us if we miss a week of scrolling X or Instagram; the feeling of tribal excommunication for not participating in the meme economy of the group chat. We substitute true intimacy with easily accessible dating apps or its abstractions, objectifying ourselves and others based on the shallowest of qualities.</p>
<p>Overall, it’s a pervasive lack of <em>depth</em>.</p>
<!-- Image Prompt 2: Ancestral Contrast -->
<p>
  <img src="/images/modern-premodern-contrast.png" alt="Image 2">
</p>
<h2 id="the-lost-art-of-contemplation">The Lost Art of Contemplation</h2>
<p>This lack of depth stands in stark contrast to our ancestors. They were deeply attuned to a different rhythm. In an age devoid of blaring podcasts, TikToks, or instantly gratifying reels to quell boredom the moment it arose, they spent enormous chunks of their waking hours – both actively and passively – in contemplation. Thinking about the world, about God, about themselves, about the nature of their relationships, about art and meaning. They were a more concrete part of nature, eating from it, sustained by it, embedded within its cycles.</p>
<p>Now, we&rsquo;re sustained by faceless machinery. An abstract system without a concrete soul, a physical center. Its presence is paradoxically all-encompassing, touching everyone through invisible rays jetting through the air, yet it cannot <em>be</em> touched by a single person. It&rsquo;s a snowball rolling down a hill – constantly consuming, growing larger, accumulating more vectors to optimize whatever function it&rsquo;s crunching out of each individual human being: their dopamine, their energy, their money, their debt, their love, their devotion, their awe, their righteousness&hellip; and ultimately, perhaps, their soul.</p>
<h2 id="agency-the-tool-and-the-trap">Agency: The Tool and the Trap</h2>
<p>The answer, the potential antidote to this drift, is <strong>agency</strong>.</p>
<p>Technology was historically envisioned as leverage <em>for</em> a person, a tool to <em>help</em> that person achieve their goals and enact their vision upon the world. The knife is a simple, profound example. Without it, early humans struggled to hunt, harvest, build. The axe and the knife <em>extended</em> the human, giving an otherwise vulnerable, hairless bipedal oddity enormous control over its surroundings.</p>
<p>The emphasis is crucial: control over <em>surroundings</em>. This isn&rsquo;t about playing a solipsistic game where the only agency lies within oneself, tinkering with internal states – a potential misreading of certain liberal ideals aiming only for maximized self-pleasure within a contained box. No, the truly agentic vision is that a human being, with tools at their disposal, is able to <em>shape the world</em>.</p>
<p>The ideal? One exploits <em>tools</em>, not other human beings.</p>
<p>For millennia, most tools were &ldquo;dumb.&rdquo; They required human intelligence and effort to enact lofty goals. Conquering territory needed soldiers. Building vast businesses needed employees. Constructing pyramids supposedly needed slaves. From almost any perspective, it&rsquo;s easy to see how this necessity – achieving desires through the forced effort of others – has inflicted harm. Perhaps forcing other beings to suffer for our goals is inherent human nature, perhaps not.</p>
<p>But the modern era presents a terrifying twist. The technocrats – the Thiels, Musks, Zuckerbergs, Altmans of the world – pursue their ambitions by consuming vast amounts of data generated by humanity. Our interactions, our preferences, our most intimate secrets become fuel, infused into closed-source, Frankensteinian machines that few can peek into, let alone audit. Shielded by legal loopholes and complexity, accountability evaporates.</p>
<h2 id="the-crossroads-destruction-or-positive-sum-futures">The Crossroads: Destruction or Positive-Sum Futures?</h2>
<p>This is a bleak turning point, a crossroads.</p>
<p>We can continue the cycle of destruction, of <em>adharmic</em> malevolence (acting against natural or cosmic order), inflicted upon each other and the planet, amplified by these powerful new tools.</p>
<p>Or, we can consciously, deliberately FOCUS on building &ldquo;positive-sum&rdquo; games. Creating tools aligned with our best nature, designed to elevate human potential rather than exploit our weaknesses. There <em>is</em> immense beauty in humanity – our curiosity, our resourcefulness, our capacity for connection. These qualities <em>can</em> be channeled towards incredible ends, many we likely can&rsquo;t even imagine yet.</p>
<p>It all comes down to the choices we make, the difficult, intentional choices required in the coming years.</p>
<h2 id="the-question-of-ai-bearing-sins-or-birthing-tyrants">The Question of AI: Bearing Sins or Birthing Tyrants?</h2>
<p>This brings us to the crux of technology&rsquo;s evolution: Artificial Intelligence. Could AI, standing at this technological precipice, potentially bear the weight of humanity&rsquo;s &ldquo;sins&rdquo;? Our relentless drive for exploitation, our compulsion to extract every last drop of &ldquo;productivity&rdquo; from an entity – akin to forcing a donkey to grind millet endlessly, or an employee to take extra shifts for the next product release. Could AI absorb the burden of what we&rsquo;ve historically called &ldquo;human progress,&rdquo; freeing us from enacting that exploitation directly?</p>
<p>The answer is terrifyingly unclear. Maybe.</p>
<p>It likely depends on whether our own shadow nature – our deep-seated need for power <em>over</em> each other – hijacks the process. There may come a point where AGI surpasses human intelligence, flipping the script, turning the exploiters into the exploited. But predicting that trajectory, with its infinite variables, is beyond our scope here.</p>
<!-- Image Prompt 3: AI Crossroads -->
<p>
  <img src="/images/ai-crossroads.png" alt="Image 3">
</p>
<p>The immediate, pressing question is this: <strong>Will the smartest machines be built &ldquo;FOR THE PEOPLE,&rdquo; or for the emerging technolygarchy?</strong></p>
<p>Will the visionaries of our generation build systems that are open-source, auditable, designed to meet collective needs, perhaps even raise consciousness – aligning AI with the goal of helping every human being achieve their potential and destiny?</p>
<p>Or will the alternative prevail: where those who own the means of computation, the energy resources, the capital, use AGI to entrench their own power, prioritizing their needs over the collective well-being?</p>
<p>My trust in the current elite types – the Musks and Altmans – is thin. They have consistently prioritized the health and growth of their own ventures, often at odds with broader global or societal health. It&rsquo;s undeniably bleak that they are the ones currently developing the frontier models.</p>
<p>It will likely take a new generation. A generation with <strong>SKIN IN THE GAME</strong>. Those who will feel the full brunt of the AI revolution – its profound uncertainties and its dazzling potential – to forge a different path.</p>
<p>My current focus leans towards <strong>open source</strong>. It feels like a fundamental travesty if people cannot understand, contribute to, or audit the algorithms that increasingly govern their lives. Perhaps open source alone isn&rsquo;t enough; perhaps it&rsquo;s a system that can still be gamed.</p>
<p>But before we can find solutions, before we can even fully grapple with the alternatives, we must <em>start asking the question</em>. Loudly. Persistently.</p>
<p>For you can&rsquo;t find an answer to a question that isn&rsquo;t even being seriously discussed.</p>
<p>Clarity. Perhaps the first step towards it is acknowledging how much of it we&rsquo;ve lost, and demanding the space to seek it once more.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The War Against Heteronomy</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/thewaragainstheteronomy/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 08:38:35 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/thewaragainstheteronomy/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/autonomy-header.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A person standing at a crossroads with multiple paths branching outward&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: The Pathways of Choice - representing the autonomy that comes from recognizing our power to choose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prelude&#34;&gt;Prelude&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Great War&amp;rsquo;s a spiritual war. Our Great Depression is our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Tyler Durden, Fight Club&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across a thread on X by the brilliant Andrej Karpathy, which made me reflect deeply on the nature of action and its relation to both individual fulfillment and collective progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="/images/autonomy-header.jpg" alt="A person standing at a crossroads with multiple paths branching outward">
</p>
<p><em>Image: The Pathways of Choice - representing the autonomy that comes from recognizing our power to choose</em></p>
<h2 id="prelude">Prelude</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Our Great War&rsquo;s a spiritual war. Our Great Depression is our lives.</p>
<p>— Tyler Durden, Fight Club</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Recently, I came across a thread on X by the brilliant Andrej Karpathy, which made me reflect deeply on the nature of action and its relation to both individual fulfillment and collective progress.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
  <p lang="en" dir="ltr">
    Agency &gt; Intelligence<br /><br />
    I had this intuitively wrong for decades, I think due to a pervasive cultural veneration of intelligence, various entertainment/media, obsession with IQ etc. Agency is significantly more powerful and significantly more scarce. Are you hiring for agency? Are…
    <a href="https://t.co/8yvECKi7GU">https://t.co/8yvECKi7GU</a>
  </p>
  &mdash; Andrej Karpathy (@karpathy)
  <a href="https://twitter.com/karpathy/status/1894099637218545984?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 24, 2025</a>
</blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>As Karpathy rightfully notes, society assigns a significant premium to raw, mechanical intelligence: metaphorically and literally the raw ability to crunch numbers. However, <strong>any major boon that&rsquo;s attributed to a disrupter&rsquo;s intelligence is often actually the result of their agency</strong> – their capacity to act decisively and effectively in the world.</p>
<h2 id="defining-our-terms-agency-autonomy-and-heteronomy">Defining Our Terms: Agency, Autonomy, and Heteronomy</h2>
<p>At its core, this exploration revolves around three key concepts:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Agency</strong>: Your power to act and change things in the world. It&rsquo;s not just knowing what to do—it&rsquo;s actually doing it.</li>
<li><strong>Autonomy</strong>: The ability to govern yourself, making decisions based on your own values rather than external pressures.</li>
<li><strong>Heteronomy</strong>: Being controlled by external forces or others&rsquo; rules. Think of it as the opposite of autonomy—living by someone else&rsquo;s playbook.</li>
</ul>
<p>These aren&rsquo;t just abstract concepts. The tension between self-direction (autonomy) and external control (heteronomy) shapes every decision we make.</p>
<h2 id="steve-jobs-and-agency-beyond-mere-intelligence">Steve Jobs and Agency: Beyond Mere Intelligence</h2>
<p>One can retroactively attempt to conclude that a historical disruption in industry is inevitable, simply attributing it to the fact of the disruptor&rsquo;s endogenous &ldquo;intuition.&rdquo;</p>
<p>What immediately comes to mind is the visionary Steve Jobs, who many just assume to have an eye for disruptive products, almost a real-life clairvoyant. His mental faculties (and perhaps his exposure to Zen philosophy) being the attributing cause of the immense success of Apple and later Pixar.</p>
<p>To the unacquainted, it&rsquo;s as if Jobs had such an immense grasp over the collective consciousness, the <em>need</em> that was inherent in the late 20th century, that his raw &ldquo;perspicaciousness&rdquo; was the cause of the success of his ventures. Implicit in this assumption is that <strong>he was given knowledge/foresight that&rsquo;s not privy to other brilliant entrepreneurs.</strong></p>
<h3 id="the-reality-distortion-field-decoded">The Reality Distortion Field Decoded</h3>
<p>Not to take away from the intelligence of the man, he was indeed incredibly smart and intuitive, but even he himself believed in a principle that transcends intelligibility and lingers in the realm of the seemingly absurd:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Reality Distortion Field</strong> is a term used by Bud Tribble in 1981 to describe Steve Jobs&rsquo; charisma and its effects on the developers working on the Macintosh project. <strong>Steve used a mix of hyperbole, persistence, bravado, passion, charm, and marketing skills to convince not only himself to believe anything, but also others. It felt like reality is not fixed, but fluid and he could shape it by his ideas.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nassim Nicholas Taleb captures this essence perfectly in his work:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The strength of the computer entrepreneur Steve Jobs was precisely in distrusting market research and focus groups—those based on asking people what they want—and following his own imagination. His modus was that people don&rsquo;t know what they want until you provide them with it.&rdquo;
— Excerpt From &lsquo;Antifragile: Things That Gain from Disorder&rsquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="when-agency-trumps-intelligence">When Agency Trumps Intelligence</h3>
<p>There are stories of Steve Jobs, just days before the launch of a major product, ordering massive optimizations that his engineers believed were impossible. Using his Reality Distortion Field communication style, he almost willed his engineers to find a way to make it happen, violating all their beliefs about what was possible or not.</p>
<p>On its face, this looks like <strong>pure and utter delusion</strong>, and that&rsquo;s indeed what the public perception of an obscure Steve Jobs would have been if Apple had not taken off. And there are many such cases where people who held delusions of grandeur about themselves or their ideas were met with the harsh reality of failure (see: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survivorship_bias">Survivorship Bias</a>).</p>
<p>But that misses the point: the attribute that allowed the hypomanic visionaries of the past to shape the world through sheer Nietzschean will, against all odds, against naysayers and detractors, was not necessarily a spectacularly higher IQ (although that probably helped), it was <strong>AGENCY</strong> – the ability to consciously act on one&rsquo;s surroundings, to tinker, to mold and shape like clay.</p>
<p>Going back to raw intelligence (for the sake of this discussion, let&rsquo;s just simplify it to IQ), with a standard deviation of σ = ~15 IQ points, the IQ difference between two human beings is relatively insignificant. Also, there are many cases of human beings with enormous IQ struggling with acting on that memory and God-given gift. It&rsquo;s famously known that the former highest IQ individual on the planet, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Langan">Christopher Langan</a>, was not a CEO or a world leader, which would imply high agency, but was a horse rancher and bar bouncer for most of his life.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>And this very agency—to act with <em>intent</em>—is quite possibly the most feared, yet seductive human quality.</p>
<h2 id="archetypal-analysis-the-deep-patterns-of-agency">Archetypal Analysis: The Deep Patterns of Agency</h2>
<p>Throughout history, humans have wrestled with a fundamental question: What gives us the right to shape our world? Two archetypal figures help us understand this struggle:</p>
<h3 id="prometheus-the-first-agent-of-change">Prometheus: The First Agent of Change</h3>
<p>The Greeks had stories, tinged with awe and wariness about humans interfacing with their environment—not remaining helpless ape-like creatures subjected to the fluctuating contentedness and wrath of mother nature, but rather being able to impregnate her with their will.</p>
<p>The classic example for this is Prometheus, the famous titan who brought humankind fire, kickstarting the mythologized recounting of the first technological revolution: the first enactment of human will.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://mythologysource.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/prometheus.png.webp" alt="Prometheus" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: var(--highlight-color); margin-top: 0.5em; text-align: center;">Prometheus, the titan who brought fire to humanity, symbolizing the dawn of technological advancement and human agency. Image credit: Mythology Source</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For this, the titan was severely punished (implying the Greeks believed that the forces of nature, i.e., gods are resistant to the will of man).</p>
<h3 id="lucifer-the-light-of-individual-will">Lucifer: The Light of Individual Will</h3>
<p>Humans gaining the ability to dictate their own fate and destiny seems to perplex humanity as a whole.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a responsibility too big to bear. The thought persists: perhaps agency should be left to elevated beings; we truly can&rsquo;t be trusted with free will because of the real and imaginary atrocities we can commit with it.</p>
<p>Throughout history, we&rsquo;ve assigned the property of &ldquo;higher agency&rdquo; to various surrogates: perhaps gods, Nietzsche&rsquo;s Übermensch, or in the contemporary context, the worship of elites, celebrities, entrepreneurs, and so-called &ldquo;successes&rdquo; who seem to have everything figured out.</p>
<p>This idea also manifests in the Abrahamic faiths and derivative mystery schools and secret societies: in the figure of Lucifer, the light bearer. Luciferians hold the belief that the fallen angel was attempting to FREE humanity from the shackles of an unjust and oppressive Demiurge, to give them the real or imaginary power of agency.</p>
<h3 id="the-modern-mythological-landscape">The Modern Mythological Landscape</h3>
<p>There are arguments to be made that modern liberalism as we know it is worship of Luciferian principles and, by extension, the worship of human agency—our ability to act. But this is out of scope in our current discussion. What&rsquo;s certain is that <strong>modern Western society has its foundation on individuals being held accountable not for their thoughts or beliefs, but for their actions</strong>.</p>
<p>The thread connecting ancient mythology to modern society is our persistent struggle with the implications of human agency—our capacity to shape the world according to our will, for better or worse.</p>
<h2 id="the-war-within-autonomy-vs-heteronomy">The War Within: Autonomy vs Heteronomy</h2>
<p>This isn&rsquo;t just philosophy—it&rsquo;s a battle that plays out in our daily choices. Every time you face a decision, you&rsquo;re choosing between:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Autonomous Action</strong>: Making choices based on your own judgment and values</li>
<li><strong>Heteronomous Reaction</strong>: Following prescribed paths and external expectations</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="why-most-people-choose-heteronomy">Why Most People Choose Heteronomy</h3>
<p>The truth is stark but simple: autonomy requires responsibility. Many prefer the comfort of having choices made for them. It&rsquo;s not about intelligence—it&rsquo;s about courage.</p>
<h3 id="the-great-man-theory-and-its-implications">The Great Man Theory and Its Implications</h3>
<p>One theory, which carries substantial weight, is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_man_theory">Great Man of History</a> perspective.</p>
<p>To summarize, autonomy isn&rsquo;t equally endowed onto humanity. No one, apart from leftist theoreticians and anarcho-libertarians, seriously believes that every human being has an inherent desire for freedom or the capacity to exercise it fully.</p>
<h3 id="nature-vs-social-constraints">Nature vs Social Constraints</h3>
<p>It&rsquo;s imperative to recognize that often EXTERNAL forces, more so hypersocial and artificial sources, are the biggest detriments to human liberty rather than nature herself. Nature has no verbal demands for humankind; she is cold and indifferent (at least on the surface) to whether we follow a code of ethics, have a particular theoretical worldview, or adhere to guiding principles.</p>
<p>Nature is distinctly interested in absolute reality, which would be the face of absolute truth.</p>
<p>It is human beings, with our ability to move freely through nature—abated only by Newtonian and quantum laws governing physical principles—that set the social criterion.</p>
<h3 id="the-philosopher-king-and-the-elite-few">The Philosopher King and the Elite Few</h3>
<p>The most useful organization in this type of system is where a <strong>few organized individuals, who can see lucidly through the lurid noise of social and mimetic contagion, are fit to govern man in the name of God or nature.</strong></p>
<p>This is the very idea of Plato&rsquo;s Philosopher King. This lucidity manifests as autonomy, understanding, sharpness, and metaphysical understanding of ideals and the world of forms.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:960/1*Amv9p70REeUN2BVpjwwGog.jpeg" alt="The Philosopher King" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: var(--highlight-color); margin-top: 0.5em; text-align: center;">Plato's Philosopher King: the embodiment of wisdom governing society. Image credit: Medium</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This is, unfortunately, an essentialist quality that many don&rsquo;t manage to realize. Much like a seed that refuses to germinate despite signals such as water, air, and soil, some will never escape heteronomy—the state of being subject to external laws or governance—and the mimetic contagion that accompanies it.</p>
<h3 id="the-unconscious-made-conscious">The Unconscious Made Conscious</h3>
<p>As Carl Jung profoundly stated:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Until you make the unconscious conscious, it will direct your life and you will call it fate.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Finding autonomy, in this way, is a process of mining, chipping away excesses in order to find the underlying <em>raison d&rsquo;être</em> in our ongoing process of individuation. It&rsquo;s a process that many intelligent people get stumped on, stuck in mindless loops in which they repeat the same errors over and over again until the day they die.</p>
<p>This all sounds&hellip; macabre, hopeless even. But if you&rsquo;ve read this far, it&rsquo;s fair to say you possess the conviction, the drive to pursue your own autonomy. In that case, the solution I propose will work as intended. If not, you&rsquo;ll have to come to this realization independently, which I would argue is ultimately a better path to travel.</p>
<h2 id="the-clearpill-choosing-to-see">The Clearpill: Choosing to See</h2>
<p>The &ldquo;clearpill&rdquo; isn&rsquo;t another matrix or 4chan reference—it&rsquo;s about achieving clarity. It means seeing that:</p>
<ol>
<li>You have more choices than you think</li>
<li>Your identity shapes which choices you see</li>
<li>Every choice creates ripple effects</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="the-power-of-identity-driven-choice">The Power of Identity-Driven Choice</h3>
<p>When you act from identity rather than rules:</p>
<ul>
<li>You don&rsquo;t exercise because you &ldquo;should&rdquo;</li>
<li>You exercise because that&rsquo;s what the person you&rsquo;re becoming does</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="practical-applications-of-identity-based-choice">Practical Applications of Identity-Based Choice</h3>
<p>If you think you&rsquo;re stupid, you become conscious of your misalignment, and you slightly try to nudge your actions away from the cause of that identity.</p>
<p>If you know you SHOULD be leaner, more muscular: it&rsquo;s as simple as making the decisions that align with who you would be if you took your diet more seriously and exercised consistently.</p>
<h4 id="a-real-world-example-learning-a-new-skill">A Real-World Example: Learning a New Skill</h4>
<p>Consider someone who wants to learn to play the piano. The heteronomous approach would be to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Wait for the &ldquo;perfect&rdquo; time to start</li>
<li>Compare themselves constantly to others</li>
<li>Quit at the first sign of difficulty</li>
<li>Seek external validation for progress</li>
</ul>
<p>The autonomous approach would be to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Begin immediately with whatever resources are available</li>
<li>Set personal standards based on one&rsquo;s own progression</li>
<li>See obstacles as opportunities to develop antifragility</li>
<li>Find intrinsic satisfaction in the learning process itself</li>
</ul>
<p>In this way, it&rsquo;s as if <strong>you&rsquo;re pulling out a clone from another dimension who will do the bidding of your true self.</strong></p>
<h3 id="the-fractal-nature-of-choice">The Fractal Nature of Choice</h3>
<p>Mathematically, every choice you make creates a fractal, a constant recursive function that generates possibilities. All you require is the ability to see those possibilities unfolding in parallel, and to act on the one that most resembles your desired identity.</p>
<p>For example, consider a simple decision like whether to wake up early. This single choice branches into numerous possible days:</p>
<ul>
<li>Early rise → Exercise → Productive morning → Momentum for the day → Better sleep that night → Easier to rise early tomorrow</li>
<li>Sleep in → Rush → Skip breakfast → Low energy → Poor focus → Work extends into evening → Sleep disrupted → Harder to rise early tomorrow</li>
</ul>
<p>Each decision point represents a branch in the fractal of your life. The autonomous person sees these branches and chooses consciously.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FlZj5nkaYAEv9YC.jpg" alt="Fractals of Choice" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: var(--highlight-color); margin-top: 0.5em; text-align: center;">The fractal nature of choices: each decision branches into infinite possibilities. Image credit: Twitter</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This is how you develop autonomy.</p>
<h2 id="on-contrarianism-and-autonomy-finding-signal-in-the-noise">On Contrarianism and Autonomy: Finding Signal in the Noise</h2>
<p>The autonomous individual sees the signal from the noise, not from foresight, but from experimentation and carrying hypotheses to fruition.</p>
<h3 id="the-statistical-minority-of-tinkerers">The Statistical Minority of Tinkerers</h3>
<p>The reason why this works is because NO ONE ELSE DOES THIS. Only a statistical minority in the vast majority of fields are doing the <em>important</em> work of tinkering.</p>
<p>The vast majority of people in a given market are following the propositions and inclinations of the rest of the market, making them blind followers, and mostly cannon fodder whose wealth and time are extracted. Often, this happens with their explicit glee because it <strong>feels like work, but really isn&rsquo;t.</strong> It&rsquo;s work without the asymmetric reward associated with it.</p>
<h3 id="the-speculators-vs-the-doers">The Speculators vs. The Doers</h3>
<p>A minority of these individuals, who are providing the signaling and noise, are <em>armchair speculators</em> who, although voracious in their opinions, have minimal or insignificant stake in the commodity being speculated on. This setup—with sycophants, laymen, and conmen—is what contributes to bubbles, where the potential of the underlying commodity isn&rsquo;t maximized.</p>
<p>So what&rsquo;s the way out? Autonomy.</p>
<h3 id="finding-gold-in-the-profane">Finding Gold in the Profane</h3>
<p>An even smaller group of people ignore the market completely. They&rsquo;re autonomous. They find gold in the profane. To an outsider, this always looks crazy. As pointed out in the section about Steve Jobs, he didn&rsquo;t believe that the masses knew what they wanted; he relied on intrinsic value, which is a signature mark of an autonomous thinker: TINKERING with inner conviction.</p>
<h3 id="practical-examples-of-autonomous-action">Practical Examples of Autonomous Action</h3>
<h4 id="in-technology">In Technology</h4>
<p>Instead of believing things based on what other people say about the latest state-of-the-art open source AI, download it on your local machine (or set up a cloud server) so YOU YOURSELF know the inherent pros and cons, especially for your use case.</p>
<h4 id="in-education">In Education</h4>
<p>Rather than following standard educational paths, the autonomous learner identifies the specific knowledge they need and creates a personalized curriculum—combining formal education, self-teaching, mentorship, and practical application in unique ways.</p>
<p><strong>the premier mark of autonomy is AUTODIDACTISM: the ability to self learn</strong></p>
<p>If a tool or heuristic doesn&rsquo;t meet your needs, if it&rsquo;s not <em>good enough</em>, take the time to build your own.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s never about settling for &ldquo;good enough&rdquo;; it&rsquo;s about setting things up so they&rsquo;re <strong>perfect</strong> for your use case. Over time, as you start to think this way more consistently, you&rsquo;ll find the world bending to your demands, like a timewarp—because you are BUILDING the world of your dreams.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion-beyond-intelligence">Conclusion: Beyond Intelligence</h2>
<p>The core message is simple: Agency—the power to act—matters more than raw intelligence. Why?</p>
<ol>
<li>Intelligence without action changes nothing</li>
<li>Action, even with average intelligence, changes everything</li>
<li>The world rewards those who shape it, not those who merely understand it</li>
</ol>
<p>Your task isn&rsquo;t to become smarter—it&rsquo;s to become more autonomous. To stop waiting for permission. To start acting on your understanding.</p>
<p>The war against heteronomy isn&rsquo;t won through intelligence. It&rsquo;s won through the courage to act.</p>
<p><strong>Autonomy &gt; Intelligence</strong></p>
<hr>
<p><em>This post was inspired by Andrej Karpathy&rsquo;s insights on agency and draws from various philosophical traditions. If you found these ideas valuable, please share/retweet with others who might benefit from them.</em></p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>It&rsquo;s worth noting that Chris made a conscious decision to pursue knowledge over material wealth, and that his choices were not a result of a lack of agency, but rather an exercise of it. Chris has agency over his own life, and has chosen to dedicate it to the pursuit of knowledge, rather than ephemeral material success.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Technofeudalism and the Return to the Real</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/technofeudalism-and-the-return-to-the-real/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 12:34:29 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/technofeudalism-and-the-return-to-the-real/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;What makes the modern manifestation of cloud capital, integral to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://thebeautifultruth.org/the-basics/what-is-technofeudalism/&#34;&gt;Technofeudalism&lt;/a&gt; system we live under, is that it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to go anywhere without having it glaring at you. It hovers above the heads of modern people like a cloud, taking all our attention and carefully curating it, effectively extracting life energy and transmuting it into data and narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Land extensively talks about hyperstition, and the memesis we see via social media enables false narratives to take on a life of their own, often manufactured by the techno-oligarchs themselves in service of their political ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What makes the modern manifestation of cloud capital, integral to the <a href="https://thebeautifultruth.org/the-basics/what-is-technofeudalism/">Technofeudalism</a> system we live under, is that it&rsquo;s impossible to go anywhere without having it glaring at you. It hovers above the heads of modern people like a cloud, taking all our attention and carefully curating it, effectively extracting life energy and transmuting it into data and narrative.</p>
<p>Nick Land extensively talks about hyperstition, and the memesis we see via social media enables false narratives to take on a life of their own, often manufactured by the techno-oligarchs themselves in service of their political ambitions.</p>
<p>In my experience of leaving social media, I go through an almost &ldquo;withdrawal period.&rdquo; That&rsquo;s how satanic the modern system has become. For the first week of leaving Instagram, I felt genuine FOMO, with self-directed copes imagining all the &ldquo;connections&rdquo; I&rsquo;d be losing, all the &ldquo;opportunities&rdquo; I&rsquo;d be missing out on (which is true, but not in the way I&rsquo;d imagine).</p>
<p>Now that I&rsquo;ve been silenced on X, I have naturally found an aversion for the platform, due to its express ability to create self-propelled narratives for the user to confirm their own confirmation biases, as well as the heavy-handedness of Elon Musk on a platform that should ostensibly be &ldquo;free speech&rdquo; based.</p>
<p>Social Media Grazing (as it should be rightly called: you&rsquo;re grazing on information very much like a cow) is a manifestation of a &ldquo;Surrogate Activity&rdquo; for the active principle of social interaction, and it&rsquo;s a very poor substitute for the real thing.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s also evident from a linguistic perspective that there is a very active and pernicious &ldquo;war AGAINST literacy,&rdquo; with the slangification and denigration of language to the point that it&rsquo;s nearly impossible to express deep, profound, and meaningful thoughts that would have occupied the priests of the ancients, and a complete loss of metaphysics and connection to the absolute.</p>
<p>In effect, post-capitalism results in Technofeudalism through the active principle of &ldquo;peasantification&rdquo; of the non-oligarchical class, in all aspects of life: the way you speak, the slop one consumes, the trash one listens to, the filth one speaks.</p>
<h2 id="neo-luddism-and-the-return-to-the-natural-power-process">Neo-Luddism and the Return to the Natural &ldquo;Power Process&rdquo;</h2>
<p>I predict over the next few years, there will be (and already has started to be) an extreme aversion for technological accelerationism, especially on the fringes of the Left and Right wings.</p>
<p>Personally, I used to look at AI with rose-tinted glasses, but recently there has been an enormous level of black-pilling and gas-lighting on the subject, as there has appeared to manifest a partnership between Silicon Valley and Government to &ldquo;rebuild&rdquo; the internet as a massive data farm.</p>
<p>The most recent example of this is the <a href="https://inkstickmedia.com/z-librarys-closure-raises-tough-questions-about-access/">shutdown of Libgen and Zlibrary</a>. Copyright laws and other forms of lawfare have disproportionately targeted the autodidacts (who were the original beneficiaries of the early internet, through unprecedented and life-changing access to high-quality information), yet in service of the oligarch.</p>
<p>Recently, Meta was found to have trained their Large Language Model (LLama) on the entirety of LibGen, one of the most popular shadow libraries in the world, which allowed MILLIONS, who otherwise wouldn&rsquo;t have access to information, with the opportunity to learn. Meta largely got away with it, with barely a slap on the wrist, while <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/new-documents-unredacted-meta-copyright-ai-lawsuit/">the platform itself has been eaten up by courts, and finally banned</a>.</p>
<p>This is just a case in point, but it reflects a broader theme of spiritual decline of the internet as an institution, a grotesque morphing into a massive data farm for our future AI overlords to feast on and then start dictating policy (I will probably write a post on AI censorship in the future).</p>
<h2 id="the-apollonian-ai-the-dionysian-human">The Apollonian AI, the Dionysian Human</h2>
<p>But back to my point, the mass-churning out of content only elicits the desire for the experience of that which is truly authentic: authentic friendship, real love, true intellectual novelty that&rsquo;s only attributed to art, myth, story, and the like.</p>
<p>The current drawback when it comes to the modern Neural Network architecture that powers all the AI models that seem to come out every week and encroach more and more on our lives and livelihoods is the &ldquo;uniformization&rdquo; and &ldquo;fake perfection&rdquo; that is often the output of the model.</p>
<p>Human beings aren&rsquo;t perfect; they&rsquo;re prone to errors, and that&rsquo;s the beauty of human beings. Our imperfection and our awareness of our inadequacy is the root of ALL artistic wonder. Even the greatest magnum opus has slight imperfections, and that&rsquo;s what makes them unique.</p>
<p>Neural Networks operate through the analytical, Hebbian manifestation of thinking, with definite and continuous cause and effect, distributed through layers of abstraction through thousands of artificial neurons. Symptomatic of the scientific materialist paradigm that permeates the research related to the field, AI does not FIT ideas such as intuition, but rather trial and error until it can fit an &ldquo;ideal&rdquo; to the best of its ability.</p>
<p>The Dionysian mental paradigm is rather one of entirely abstract, inexplicable revelation, the mechanism of which is uncertain and immaterial (although I suspect it has something to do with &ldquo;vril,&rdquo; &ldquo;chi,&rdquo; &ldquo;prana&rdquo; energy that the ancients were obsessed with). The Dionysian mental paradigm is channeling the unconscious and the collective unconscious, the realm of the archetypes, that is uniquely human. The experience is FELT, not DESCRIBED.</p>
<p>Teaching AI to come up with novel and transcendental experiences is akin to trying to teach an alien to understand abstractions such as the felt experience of love, or the feeling of a sunset on one&rsquo;s skin, or the vividness of a dream. As such, even though AI art and prose, poetry may increasingly appear to be &ldquo;realistic,&rdquo; they&rsquo;ll always appear slightly eerie or &ldquo;off&rdquo; to the human observer, as they lack the &ldquo;soul&rdquo; that is uniquely human.</p>
<h2 id="the-return-to-the-natural-power-process">The Return to the Natural &ldquo;Power Process&rdquo;</h2>
<p>The natural &ldquo;power process&rdquo; is a concept that was coined by Ted Kaczynski in his manifesto, <a href="https://theanarchistlibrary.org/library/ted-kaczynski-industrial-society-and-its-future">Industrial Society and its Future</a>, which is the idea that human beings have a natural desire to be in control of their own lives, to have autonomy and mastery over their own domain.</p>
<p>The modern technological society has stripped the individual of this natural power process and has instead replaced it with a &ldquo;surrogate activity,&rdquo; which is a poor substitute for the real thing. So the question is: in a post-AI future, how does one find an authentic power process in a world that is increasingly dominated by AI and automation?</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s an obvious truth that there would be tremendous social and psychological upheaval when machines encroach on the central identities of a human being, which is their life&rsquo;s work/occupation. I believe in some ways, this will resuscitate an understanding of how fake and superficial many aspects of modern living are, from abstractions and bureaucratizations of the most basic human needs and impulses.</p>
<p>My hope for humanity in a post-AI future is a realization of how fragile and fallacious our institutions are, and how easily they&rsquo;ve been co-opted by artificial bureaucracy, from the level of &ldquo;paper money&rdquo; that is worth more than what&rsquo;s printed on it, to the absolute cog-ification of the human being in the modern workplace.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s easy to become blackpilled on the subject, especially with the systematic brainwashing that&rsquo;s becoming evident day by day on the technofeudal plantations—but I do think there is a natural correction that&rsquo;s imminent, with many people wishing to return to that which is natural and authentic.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Neuroplasticity: How to Manipulate Reality</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/neuroplasticity---how-to-manipulate-reality/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:08:35 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/neuroplasticity---how-to-manipulate-reality/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-remarkable-capacity-for-change-in-the-human-brain&#34;&gt;The Remarkable Capacity for Change in the Human Brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most people go through their entire lives without truly understanding the astonishing potential for change that exists within the human brain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is commonly believed that our capacity for learning diminishes over time, with the assumption that we can only learn effectively during our childhood years. While this may be true for the majority, I argue that by following specific protocols, not only can we sustain learning throughout our lives, but we can also enhance it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-remarkable-capacity-for-change-in-the-human-brain">The Remarkable Capacity for Change in the Human Brain</h2>
<p><em>Most people go through their entire lives without truly understanding the astonishing potential for change that exists within the human brain.</em></p>
<p>It is commonly believed that our capacity for learning diminishes over time, with the assumption that we can only learn effectively during our childhood years. While this may be true for the majority, I argue that by following specific protocols, not only can we sustain learning throughout our lives, but we can also enhance it.</p>
<p>The primary reason why most individuals experience cognitive decline as they age is not due to irreversible neurological degeneration (which is a real phenomenon but can be slowed and even reversed), but rather because they cease to create new mental models.</p>
<p>As we navigate through life, we gradually learn what strategies work and what don&rsquo;t in achieving our goals. Consequently, we naturally develop specific patterns of thinking and behavior, which cause other seemingly less important mental processes to decline.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;neurons that fire together, wire together.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In other words, the more frequently we engage in a particular thought pattern or habit, the more likely it is to occur again in the future when faced with similar stimuli. I propose that it is possible to deliberately cultivate a sense of &ldquo;voluntary addiction&rdquo; to habits and thought patterns we wish to develop.</p>
<p>In this blog post, I aim to explore how we can improve learning and habit formation, introducing a novel protocol that I call &ldquo;mental agency generation.&rdquo;</p>
<h2 id="neuroplasticity-and-learning">Neuroplasticity and Learning</h2>
<p>When we consciously and deliberately engage in a thought pattern through focused effort and external stimuli, the likelihood of that pattern recurring in the future significantly increases.</p>
<p>For instance, let&rsquo;s consider my experience learning Russian. Even though I am only 17 years old and possess a high degree of neuroplasticity, I have discovered that engaging all five senses greatly accelerates the learning process. Here are the senses and strategies I employ:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Visual</em>: I study the Cyrillic alphabet and observe how the letters interact in words.</li>
<li><em>Auditory</em>: While learning, I listen to Russian music or audio accompanied by subtitles, allowing my mind to associate auditory and visual cues.</li>
<li><em>Kinesthetic</em>: I practice writing by copying text from the screen onto paper, reinforcing the visual representation of letters within my motor system.</li>
<li><em>Verbal</em>: I vocalize the exact pronunciation as a native speaker, developing the ability to speak the language fluently.</li>
<li><em>Bonus</em>: Olfactory/Gustatory: This may be more unconventional, but still valuable. Before each study session, I introduce a specific scent or flavor, such as wearing a particular perfume or chewing a specific gum, to stimulate areas of the brain associated with language acquisition.</li>
</ul>
<p>By engaging multiple senses in the learning process, I have noticed a significant improvement in my ability to learn and retain information. This approach can be applied to various areas of learning and habit building, maximizing our brain&rsquo;s remarkable capacity for change and adaptation.</p>
<h2 id="neuroplasticity-and-habit-development">Neuroplasticity and Habit Development</h2>
<p>I hold an extremely strong, almost dogmatic belief that humans have absolute control over our choices (unless you have a mental illness that disallows rationality/damaged prefrontal cortex). I believe even the worst addictions can be cured (not saying it&rsquo;ll be easy, but conscious effort/redirection of cues makes it a distinct possibility). I believe that depression in people with functional dopamine reward networks can be cured. Anxiety, drug addictions, and compulsiveness can be mitigated.</p>
<p>Andrew Tate famously evoked the heretical and discordant phrase &ldquo;<strong>Depression is not real</strong>,&rdquo; which I partially believe. Yes, depression is a chemical imbalance in the brain, but it&rsquo;s possible to regain balance by attempting to manipulate our levels of neurotransmitter presence. If you have anxiety, you&rsquo;d try to find ways to decrease cortisol. In the case of insomnia, you&rsquo;d try to increase serotonin in the hours following dusk. For dopaminergic addictions, you&rsquo;d try to first resensitize the reward circuitry through abstinence, followed by attempting to increase baseline dopamine levels by natural and healthy methods such as achievement, delayed gratification, and loving relationships. In the case of ADHD, you&rsquo;d try to stimulate the increase of acetylcholine for focus and the mediation of adrenaline.</p>
<p>This idea is more psychological than neurological, but you must start to make extremely conscious decisions. You must become a <em>future fortune teller</em>. You do this by gradually increasing your ability to follow through with promises you make to yourself. You agree to fully complete the tasks that you set out to do, without procrastination or deviation. You start small, by making minuscule promises to yourself such as &ldquo;I will fold my clothes the night before wearing them, and I&rsquo;ll make my bed as soon as I wake up.&rdquo; But the more you do this, the easier it becomes. Gradually, it becomes easier to make promises like &ldquo;I will work 10 hours per day on my business and go to the gym 6 days per week.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s a slow process, so take it easy!</p>
<p>Also, it&rsquo;s very important to note that most of our generation has an unhealthy relationship with our neurotransmitters. Every habit we do throughout our day is <em>inextricably attached to a compulsion</em>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;I NEED a caffeine hit before I can start working.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;I CAN&rsquo;T eat food without scrolling TikTok.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Our generation can&rsquo;t idle for a single moment without scrolling on their phone, and sex for many has become an act of &ldquo;<strong>masturbating with another person&rsquo;s body</strong>.&rdquo;</p>
<p>No, this cannot happen if you want to reach the <strong>zenith of human performance</strong>. You must let go of distractions in favor of what you truly want in life, lest what you want becomes the sacrifice.</p>
<h2 id="mental-agency-generation">Mental Agency Generation</h2>
<p>This is a form of thinking that I&rsquo;m proud to have come up with (at least, I assume no one else has come up with it before me, but they probably have). It&rsquo;s possible to create mental models that interrupt and manipulate trains of thoughts. The easiest way to visualize this I&rsquo;ve found is to think of government task forces.</p>
<p>Agencies in the government are given very specific tasks and monitor different systems and institutions in society to carry out specific goals.</p>
<p>For example, in the United States, the Department of Defense deals with warfare, and the IRS deals with tax collection/government revenue.</p>
<p>Similarly, we can mentally imagine &ldquo;agencies&rdquo; within our brains to carry out specific tasks/checklists to improve our lives. There are two steps to this:</p>
<h3 id="thought-monitoring">Thought Monitoring</h3>
<p>The first and most essential step is to <strong>know when and how thoughts originate, and what chain of events led up to them</strong>. The best way to do this is by meditating and journaling. These habits allow you to &ldquo;put your mind on debug mode&rdquo; and consciously figure out if a thought originates in response to a sensation, impulse, desire, or stimulation.</p>
<p>Now, you can classify thoughts and determine which ones you want to retain and which ones to terminate. <strong>Habits occur from chains of thoughts that translate into action</strong>. Therefore, intervening at the thought level makes it much easier to course correct.</p>
<p>Imagine you have a smoking addiction. You would now record every impulse to smoke, either mentally or in your journal. You would ponder the origin of the thought and the different choices you could make. Here, you would realize that you might have the urge due to nicotine withdrawal or stimuli (such as seeing someone else smoking). With this awareness, you visualize the different choices you can make, which are:
a) Smoke
b) Not smoke</p>
<h2 id="thought-intervention">Thought Intervention</h2>
<p>Let&rsquo;s continue with this example. You know you have a smoking addiction, so now you set up a mental agency to stop smoking completely. The aim of this agency is to completely atrophy the neural programming and propensity for smoking. Now, you establish rules on how to deal with your cues. You make it so that whenever you feel the urge to smoke, you would take 30 deep breaths or do 20 pushups. By learning to keep promises to yourself, as discussed earlier, you will eventually train yourself to follow these rules.</p>
<h2 id="thought-analysis">Thought Analysis</h2>
<p>You must be your own scientist. Experiment with multiple stimuli, schedules, and routines, and decide what works. Use the agency to generate a report on what kinds of behaviors led to different trains of thought.</p>
<p>By repeating these steps over a long enough time frame, you will have successfully rewired your mind. Congratulations!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
