<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Byte Geek</title>
		<link>/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Byte Geek</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>The Practice of Journaling in Self-Improvement</title>
			<link>/posts/the-practice-of-journaling-in-self-improvement/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/the-practice-of-journaling-in-self-improvement/</guid>
			<description>“Fill your paper with the breathings of your heart.” – William Wordsworth
 I have recently taken to the habit of journaling. I have come to appreciate the process of putting your thoughts on paper, and I hope I can convince you to do the same 🧠 📄
Why Journal? Journaling as a practice has enormous benefits. The main one that attracted me, was that it helps declutter and lapidify your thoughts.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>“Fill your paper with the breathings of your heart.” – William Wordsworth</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have recently taken to the habit of journaling. I have come to appreciate the process of putting your thoughts on paper, and I hope I can convince you to do the same 🧠 📄</p>
<h2 id="why-journal">Why Journal?</h2>
<p>Journaling as a practice has enormous benefits. The main one that attracted me, was that it helps declutter and lapidify your thoughts.
In the modern internet age, there is a phenomena called <em>information overload</em>. If you don&rsquo;t actively preserve them, your thoughts end up fleeting, and you lose so many potentially incredible ideas.</p>
<p>Journaling also helps in reflection, which is important in having a healthy mind. Writing down your emotions makes you more mindful and less reactive.</p>
<p>Believe it or not,<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11561925/"> journaling is also known to boost memory and comprehension!</a>.after journaling consistently, you will be able to remember minor details about your day which may be cool to retrospect.</p>
<h2 id="what-do-you-need">What do you need?</h2>
<p>Not a lot. Just a book and a pen (you could also use a <a href="https://obsidian.md">note-taking app like obsidian!</a>)
The process is pretty simple. Set a time when you will write a few words, and then just do it every day.
It can be anything.</p>
<p>Here is a general rule-of-thumb you can use in your daily reviews</p>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> How did I feel today?</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> What cool experience did I have?</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> What did I learn?</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> How can I get better tomorrow?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="gratitude-journaling">Gratitude Journaling</h3>
<p>Your mindset is the most important thing you physically have.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How you do one thing is how you do everything.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have learned that writing down a thing that you are grateful for everyday generally improves your mood throughout the day, and also makes you more humble and content with the things you have</p>
<p>For example, today I am grateful for having access to the internet and interacting with like-minded people who make me better as a person.</p>
<h3 id="mind-on-paper-mentality">Mind-on-paper mentality</h3>
<p>This is a term that I like to use for putting emotions and experiences in a more permanent environment. If you have ever heard of the <a href="https://www.buildingasecondbrain.com">second brain</a>, Essentially it helps you to organize and manage your thoughts more efficiently.</p>
<p>You must understand that <strong>your mind is not made for storing ideas, it is made for making new ones</strong>. Journaling helps you keep track of everything you learn and keeps your mind free of the burden of remembering information.</p>
<h3 id="consistency">Consistency</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>“Success isn’t always about greatness. It’s about consistency. Consistent hard work leads to success. Greatness will come.” — Dwayne Johnson</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With every other self-improvement tool, journaling should become a <em>habit</em>. You must make it a point that no matter what, you must write a journal entry every day.
This helps build discipline as well.</p>
<h3 id="review">Review</h3>
<p>Reviewing past journal entries is highly recommended. It is really fun to do personally, as it is an indicator of how much I have grown as a person (which is my main motivation).
You can also do weekly and monthly review, where instead of thinking in the scale of days, you can review your entire week or month.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>How to Type Faster</title>
			<link>/posts/how-to-type-faster/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/how-to-type-faster/</guid>
			<description>Typing has become and exceedingly useful skill over the last few years. My journey started with a single link. A friend wanted to compare our typing speeds. At the time, i was pretty slow, having to look down at my keyboard every time I wanted to type a single character (I cringe at the thought, in retrospect). At the time, everyone were much faster than me, I was at a slow 25 WPM and didn&amp;rsquo;t care much about it.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="typing-has-become-and-exceedingly-useful-skill-over-the-last-few-years">Typing has become and exceedingly useful skill over the last few years.</h1>
<p>My journey started with a single link. A friend wanted to compare our typing speeds. At the time, i was pretty slow, having to look down at my keyboard every time I wanted to type a single character (I cringe at the thought, in retrospect).
At the time, everyone were much faster than me, I was at a slow 25 WPM and didn&rsquo;t care much about it.</p>
<p>However, in late 2020,I realized the importance of being able to type fast, and have been (and still am!) practicing every single day.</p>
<h2 id="why-type-faster">Why Type Faster?</h2>
<p>Typing faster, personally, has helped me a lot.
If you use your computer even remotely, every single day, typing faster will boost your productivity
Right now i am at around 75-90 WPM(words per minute) and I find that I am able to complete assignments and code much faster and efficiently.</p>
<p>It also really helps when i am trying to text someone and writing notes and blog posts</p>
<h2 id="touch-typing">Touch Typing</h2>
<p>There is a methodology to typing. To get faster, you should really learn to type without looking at your keyboard.
I recommend websites like <a href="http://typing.com">http://typing.com</a> and <a href="https://www.typingclub.com">https://www.typingclub.com</a>.
It may be really hard at first, but the most important thing that you should learn is the <strong>muscle memory.</strong></p>
<h2 id="what-kind-of-keyboards-to-use">What kind of keyboards to use?</h2>
<p>There are two main types of keyboards, <em>membrane</em> and <em>mechanical</em>. Although I will not be covering the differences completely, you can read more <a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/difference-between-membrane-keyboard-and-mechanical-keyboard/">here.</a></p>
<p>I have used both, and personally, i find mechanical keyboards to be a lot more useful for practicing.
However, the keyboard you use statistically doesn&rsquo;t matter, hence I recommend you use which ever type that you like!</p>
<h2 id="layouts">Layouts</h2>
<p>Layouts have become really controversial in the typing community. The one I use, and the one you are probably using too, is the American QWERTY layout. It is the most universal layout that you can find in almost all commercial keyboards.</p>
<p>There are some alternative layouts like COLEMAK or DVORAK.
I recommend researching them if you are really serious about increasing your typing efficiency</p>
<h2 id="websites">Websites</h2>
<p>There are a bunch of typing websites that are only a Google search away.</p>
<p>The websites i use the most are <a href="https://play.typeracer.com">typeracer</a> and <a href="http://monkeytype.com">monkeytype</a>.I usually switch between them every once in a while depending on the type of practice I want to do.</p>
<p>Fair warning though: switching between websites too often isn&rsquo;t that good either as you have to continuously adjust your typing style (different websites have different error counting mechanisms) and you wouldn&rsquo;t have a good general statistical growth of your typing sleep.</p>
<h2 id="practice">Practice</h2>
<p>This may be kinda cliché, but remember, <strong>practice makes perfect.</strong> Don&rsquo;t expect a 200 WPM+ right away. Practicing regularly over a long period of time is the only way to get really fast. Also,it is important to work on the accuracy.
I time block my calendar to do about 15 mins of deliberate typing practice every day, and it helps me get in the zone quickly</p>
<h2 id="other-resources">Other Resources</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ArVtCQqQRE">Ali Abdaal&rsquo;s video</a>, along with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oOdfefV2R1I">NoThisIsJohn&rsquo;s</a> provided me a solid foundation, with additional, more nuanced tips…if you want to learn more about the art of typing, be sure to head on there!</p>
<p>Remember,<strong>practice makes perfect!</strong></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Benefits of Cold Showers</title>
			<link>/posts/benefits-of-cold-showers/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/benefits-of-cold-showers/</guid>
			<description>Cold Showers are becoming cool again. From the lifestyles of US Marines, to the legendary Wim Hof (AKA the Iceman), cold showers have become synonymous with the Healthy Grind set. Many reports, backed by plenty of studies have found pretty eye-opening benefits from this seemingly trivial ritual. Some benefits often talked about are:
 Increased testosterone/alertness Stronger Immunity Faster Recovery after exercising Better Skin Quality Helps in burning fat  Sounds good… But why?</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="cold-showers-are-becoming-cool-again">Cold Showers are becoming cool again.</h2>
<p>From the lifestyles of US Marines, to the legendary Wim Hof (AKA the Iceman), cold showers have become synonymous with the Healthy Grind set.
Many reports, backed by plenty of <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5025014/">studies</a> have found pretty eye-opening benefits from this seemingly trivial ritual. Some benefits often talked about are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Increased testosterone/alertness</li>
<li>Stronger Immunity</li>
<li>Faster Recovery after exercising</li>
<li>Better Skin Quality</li>
<li>Helps in burning fat</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="sounds-good-but-why">Sounds good… But why?</h2>
<p>I think that the idea of cold showers is more of a mindset thing. In the current day and age, most of us take things for granted and become very <em>comfortable</em> with our lives. This is a problem because the moment we bask in the luxuries of modern living, we <strong>stop growing</strong>.</p>
<p>Cold showers, to me, is a metaphorical journey to <em>seek discomfort</em> (one of my favorite catch lines, well done yes theory).</p>
<p>Even if it may not theoretically offer any benefits, it&rsquo;s the way of the Stoic… Actively trying to feel uncomfortable in order to grow as a person.</p>
<h2 id="methodology-to-taking-cold-showers">Methodology to taking cold Showers</h2>
<p>There are three common ways of talking cold Showers</p>
<ol>
<li>transitioning from hot-to-cold</li>
<li>edging into the cold</li>
<li>jumping straight into the cold stream
It may be extremely uncomfortable for about 5 seconds, but the feeling passes soon after.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="my-experience">My experience</h2>
<p>At the time of writing this blog, i have personally taken cold showers every morning for a week. It feels absolutely brilliant with higher levels of motivation and alertness. This, along with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tybOi4hjZFQ">Wim Hof&rsquo;s breathing technique,</a> has given me days of more happiness, energy and confidence.</p>
<p>Step out of your comfort zone, and you shall do wonders.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Concept of Motivation:How to Always Get Things Done</title>
			<link>/posts/the-concept-of-motivationhow-to-always-get-things-done/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/the-concept-of-motivationhow-to-always-get-things-done/</guid>
			<description>Motivation has a shelf life. It changes like the weather. Although it is a seasonal phenomenon, it still carries a great deal of power.
In this blog post, I aim to explain how you can motivate yourself to do hard habits, even though you may feel low.
Step One: Genuinely be interested in whatever you want to pursue. You cannot be internally motivated to do anything when you do not like doing it.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="motivation-has-a-shelf-life">Motivation has a shelf life.</h2>
<p>It changes like the weather.
Although it is a seasonal phenomenon, it still carries a great deal of power.</p>
<p>In this blog post, I aim to explain how you can motivate yourself to do hard habits, even though you may feel low.</p>
<h2 id="step-one-genuinely-be-interested-in-whatever-you-want-to-pursue">Step One: Genuinely be interested in whatever you want to pursue.</h2>
<p>You cannot be internally motivated to do anything when you do not like doing it. If you pursue a skill or task that you generally like (or have a strong incentive to do), you are more likely to have the motivation to become very good at it.</p>
<p>If you are not sure on whether you actually like the task, It is a good idea to introspect and really think about it.<em>(noting down your thoughts in a journal or diary is super useful!)</em></p>
<h2 id="step-two-unlock-the-power-of-consistency">Step Two: Unlock the power of consistency.</h2>
<p>It is a common fallacy that to do difficult tasks, you need to take drastic measures. The greatest achievements come out of small actions done <em>consistently</em>.
If you have the dream of becoming a great magician, you don&rsquo;t have to do a show every day. This will actually <strong>drain</strong> your motivation since it is very intensive.</p>
<p>Instead, all you have to do is do a single trick a day, and when all those days compound, and you will find yourself at the top.</p>
<h2 id="step-three-fall-and-get-up-again">Step Three: Fall and get up again.</h2>
<p>In any journey, there will inevitably be rainy days. You may make mistakes while developing a habit, and that is absolutely okay.
Failure is an integral part of growth. What matters is that you continue doing it, even if you feel like giving up. <strong>Even doing 1% every day is enough to keep you going.</strong>
To give an example, today I feel particularly lethargic. However, I want to become a good blogger, so I wrote down the draft of this post even if I didn&rsquo;t feel like it. I know that once I finish this post I will feel a sense of accomplishment and that&rsquo;s what keep&rsquo;s me going.</p>
<h2 id="step-four-introspect">Step Four: Introspect.</h2>
<p>You may reach a point where you feel you have plateaued, or not progressing anymore. At this point, it is crucial that you analyze your techniques related to the habit. A few questions I like to ask myself when I plateau are:</p>
<ul>
<li>what have you been doing good?</li>
<li>Where could you possibly improve?</li>
<li>What new things (related to the habit) are you interested in learning/doing.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="bonus-step-get-an-accountability-partner">Bonus Step: Get an accountability partner</h2>
<p>I found it useful to have someone else who learns a skill alongside me. Be it a friend, family member or even some random people on discord. You could also share what you have learned with your partner, which helps in finding new ideas/concepts(Learn — Do — Teach paradigm). Accountability partners are a sure-fire way to up the stakes to keep yourself motivated to continue doing/learning a task.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Atomic Habits by James Clear:Book Review</title>
			<link>/posts/atomic-habits-by-james-clear/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/atomic-habits-by-james-clear/</guid>
			<description>This is a legendary book, its reputation proceeds it. All the productivity greats like Thomas Frank and Ali Abdaal have recommended it…so this month I have decided to check it out.
And boy, does it deliver.
Core ideas First, I think we should define what an “Atomic Habit” really is. Many of us think that to be successful, we should do great feats…but in fact, that is not true at all!</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="this-is-a-legendary-book-its-reputation-proceeds-it">This is a legendary book, its reputation proceeds it.</h2>
<p>All the productivity greats like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/electrickeye91">Thomas Frank</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/aliabdaal/videos">Ali Abdaal</a> have recommended it…so this month I have decided to check it out.</p>
<p>And boy, does it deliver.</p>
<h2 id="core-ideas">Core ideas</h2>
<p>First, I think we should define what an “Atomic Habit” really is.
Many of us think that to be successful, we should do great feats…but in fact, that is <strong>not</strong> true at all!
The Greatest achievements come from the smallest changes that are done <em>consistently</em>.</p>
<p>The Idea that stuck out to me the most was growing everyday by just <strong>one percent.</strong> It may not be that noticeable at first, but it is indeed meaningful in the long run.</p>
<p>If you improve by a single % every day for a whole year…you would be 365 (or 366!) percent better than you were at the start of the year!</p>
<p>Growth is not linear, it is compounded, which I genuinely find a good thing!</p>
<p>Even though you will find minimum results for your effort when you start, later on the curve you will find yourself gaining more out of less effort, which is truly amazing!</p>
<h3 id="systems-over-goals">Systems over Goals</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>the purpose of setting goals is to win the game. The purpose of building systems is to continue playing the game.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In habit building, there is no rigid end point.it is a continuous process of self-development and refining until you are the best you can be.
Therefore, looking for longevity rather than instant gratification in habit building proves more successful in the long run.</p>
<h3 id="habits-shape-your-identity">Habits shape your identity</h3>
<p>Why do you want to become fit? Why do you want to become better at drawing/cooking/playing a sport?
Identity matters when it comes to habit building. In case you want to start a new habit (such as eating healthier because you are becoming overweight), you should lean in to making the habit as a part of who you are, as it will make it more likely that it sticks.</p>
<ul>
<li>Whenever you write a blog post, you become a blogger</li>
<li>every time you exercise, you become a healthier person.</li>
</ul>
<p>Its constant self affirmation that brings you to whom you want to be.</p>
<ul>
<li>Habits are behaviors that when repeated, they become subconscious and automatic</li>
<li>the purpose of habits is to solve problems with as little effort as possible</li>
<li>the 4 steps of habits are cues, cravings, response, reward
<ul>
<li>To give an example, today I made my first <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B9QE3Snono8">YouTube video</a></li>
<li>cue: making a to-do and constant reminders from my dad</li>
<li>craving: actually starting my YouTube channel, linking it to my blog</li>
<li>response: learning to edit the best i can that future videos become easier</li>
<li>reward: I&rsquo;m going to order some food today :D (shawarma or pizza, haven&rsquo;t decided yet)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="the-4-laws-of-behavior-change">The 4 laws of behavior change</h3>
<ol>
<li>make it obvious
<ul>
<li>if I want to read a book, I should keep the books close to me</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>make it attractive
<ul>
<li>getting books that interest you to develop a habit of reading</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>make it easily
<ul>
<li>I don&rsquo;t like brushing manually, so an electric tooth brush helps me brush more regularly</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>make it satisfying
<ul>
<li>seeing that you are progressing as a person over time and logging it</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="now-for-the-most-powerful-idea">Now for the most powerful Idea,</h3>
<p>habit stacking.
In the pasts, I used to follow were rigid schedules/to-do lists.
Sure, I used to use them and all was fine for a few days but with life, changes always happen, and it gets difficult to stick to things after a while</p>
<p>Habit stacks are, less rigid, frameworks of how you want to go about your day. It is vague enough to allow distractions, but still asserts that you grow 1% in that day.</p>
<p>You put habits that you want to do in between a habit that you do regularly (waking up to taking a shower) and a habit that you enjoy (playing video games or playing with your dog)</p>
<p>The end of the book has a powerful line that I think sums up everything well,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>tiny changes, remarkable results. That&rsquo;s the power of Atomic Habits.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can find the book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Atomic-Habits-Proven-Build-Break/dp/0735211299">here</a> and I recommend everyone to at least give it a shot and watch your habits compound.</p>
<p>Happy reading!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Digital Minimalism by Cal Newport: Book Review</title>
			<link>/posts/digital-minimilism-by-cal-newport-book-review/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 16:06:37 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/digital-minimilism-by-cal-newport-book-review/</guid>
			<description>Yet Another Cal Newport Review, ay? You may be beginning to notice a pattern here. But seriously, The man is such an intuitive and practical writer.
If you are anything like me, you may find that a lot of precious time gets sucked away by the internet, or digital world. In fact, this has become such a problem that 92% of teens go online daily, and 24% say they go online “almost constantly.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="yet-another-cal-newport-review-ay">Yet Another Cal Newport Review, ay?</h2>
<p>You may be beginning to notice a pattern here. But seriously, The man is such an intuitive and practical writer.</p>
<p>If you are anything like me, you may find that a lot of precious time gets sucked away by the internet, or digital world. In fact, this has become such a problem that <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2015/04/09/teens-social-media-technology-2015/">92% of teens go online daily, and 24% say they go online “almost constantly.”</a>
The internet may be really useful, but if it manages to control US, we know that we are making some serious mistakes.</p>
<p>This great book aims to give us a solution to this problem, and bare with me… It is not as radical as it seems.</p>
<p>The main premise is to advocate a more mindful/intentional way of using the technology beaming into our faces, rather than cutting out the use of it completely.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Digital Minimalism: A philosophy of technology use in which you focus your online time on a small number of carefully selected and optimized activities that strongly support things you value, and then happily miss out on everything else.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It is brought to our attention that the big Social Media Conglomerates are manufactured with the intention to capture your screen time.</p>
<p>Think about it. How many times have you opened Reddit, Instagram, or YouTube and start browsing, browsing, browsing, and then notice that you have been looking at cat memes for about 4 hours!</p>
<p>Digital Minimalism offers extensive and practice solutions to this problem
to name a few, there are:</p>
<ul>
<li>embracing solitude (the book talks about how solitude is more important than it may seem)</li>
<li>participate in active leisure rather than passive leisure (i.e., it&rsquo;s better to play a sport with friends or learn a new skill than to binge-watch Netflix)</li>
<li>do a digital detox/declutter (refrain from non-essential internet use for a period of 30 days to reset your compulsive habits)</li>
<li>start active socializing (talking to friends face to face generates greater satisfaction and meaningful conversations opposed to low bandwidth text messaging)</li>
</ul>
<p>A digital minimalist values <em>benefit</em> over everything else. Its basic economics. If something doesn&rsquo;t give better returns on investment, it might as well be booted.
To put it simply, if something <em>costs</em> more than it <em>produces</em>, it is not worth your effort.
(cost doesn&rsquo;t necessarily need to mean <strong>money</strong>, it can also be applied to time or something valuable.)</p>
<p>The book promises that with mindful behavior regarding technology, your productivity, and wellbeing would increase exponentially more than if you took everything in the digital world at face value.</p>
<p>We are entering a new era, a strange era of massive amounts of information our primitive minds cannot handle.
If we are reasonable with this power, we will succeed as a species.</p>
<h3 id="footnotes">Footnotes</h3>
<p>Read the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digital-Minimalism-Choosing-Focused-Noisy/dp/0525536515">book</a>. Seriously.</p>
<p>Thank you to <a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/">cal&rsquo;s</a> and <a href="https://www.samuelthomasdavies.com/book-summaries/business/digital-minimalism/">Samuel D. Davis&rsquo;s</a> blogs for helping me consolidate my thoughts.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Importance of Sleep in Learning</title>
			<link>/posts/the-importance-of-sleep-in-learning/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/the-importance-of-sleep-in-learning/</guid>
			<description>I am writing this blog post at 11:55 AM out of a great need to express my thoughts about sleep,the tame death that envelopes us all.
I find that in our modern world,sleep is often put aside,or even overlooked. I have recently found a study by the american goverment that asserts that 1 in 3 adults are chronically sleep deprived. These numbers are shocking and should make us reconsider our view on sleep.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am writing this blog post at 11:55 AM out of a great need to express my thoughts about sleep,the tame death that envelopes us all.</p>
<p>I find that in our modern world,sleep is often put aside,or even overlooked. I have recently found a <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2016/p0215-enough-sleep.html">study</a> by the american goverment that asserts that 1 in 3 adults <strong>are chronically sleep deprived.</strong> These numbers are shocking and should make us reconsider our <em>view</em> on sleep.</p>
<h1 id="why-is-sleep-important">Why is sleep important?</h1>
<p>Sleep is your bodies way of winding down after a long day.
You may not know it,but there is a lot of wear-and-tear happening in your body every moment that you are alive.
hundreds of cells die and new cells <em>should</em> be able to regenerate in a healthy human being.</p>
<p>There is also a lot of hormones that flood your blood stream when you are in deep sleep.Melatonin and Growth Horomones that get released during deep sleep is essential for healthy body development.</p>
<h1 id="how-can-sleep-help-me-learn-stuff">How can sleep help me learn stuff?</h1>
<p>Imagine you had a test in 8 hours.Most people,in this situation(especially the people who didnt study!) would be inclined to stay up all night and cram as much difficult informaiton as they can.</p>
<p>But alas,this teqnique that has become commonplace today is in fact,doing more harm than good.</p>
<p>Sleep is a time where your brain consolidates information you gather throughout your day.Your brain processes your memories and makes it easier to recall difficult information</p>
<p>even short powernaps can have this effect. So if you were to be short on time,reading all the information and then having a nap is a thing i would advise.</p>
<p>Even if you werent technically &ldquo;<em>studying</em>&rdquo; &hellip;sleep definitely helps you understand a subject,or topic a lot better passively.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Deep Work by Cal Newport:Book Review</title>
			<link>/posts/deep-work-by-cal-newportbook-review/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 11:57:29 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/deep-work-by-cal-newportbook-review/</guid>
			<description>Productivity books, we all read them kinda is becoming my guilty pleasure at this point. However, I have to give the book “Deep Work” some credit. Although this is my second reading, I still find enormous meaning from it.
The book is a non-fiction thesis on how “knowledge work” is valued in the economy, and how top achievers actually succeed. It also tackles the idea of “information overload” in our modern digital age.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="productivity-books-we-all-read-them">Productivity books, we all read them</h1>
<p>kinda is becoming my guilty pleasure at this point. However, I have to give the book “Deep Work” some credit.
Although this is my second reading, I still find enormous meaning from it.</p>
<p>The book is a non-fiction thesis on how “knowledge work” is valued in the economy, and how top achievers actually succeed. It also tackles the idea of “information overload” in our modern digital age.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-deep-work">What is Deep Work?</h1>
<blockquote>
<p>“Professional activity performed in a state of distraction-free concentration that push your cognitive capabilities to their limit. These efforts create new value, improve your skill, and are hard to replicate.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Deep Work, in contrast to shallow work, is truly valuable in today&rsquo;s economy. For example, 30 minutes of coding is much more “valuable” than 30 mins of email/message responding.
Deep work is long, uninterrupted segments of intense focus that enables you to make quality work.
Deep work is the work that enables one to produce their Magnum Opus, or at least work that they would be proud of.</p>
<h1 id="how-did-the-best-become-the-greatest">How did the best become the greatest?</h1>
<p>One thing that really stood out to me while reading was the formula of work quality.</p>
<p>$$ \ Quality \ of \ work = \ Time \ spent \times \ Intensity \ of \ focus $$
Newport gives numerous examples of winners in the economy who are successful because of their <em>methodology</em> to how they carry about doing their work.
In this hyper-interconnected world, it happens that the achieves in their respective fields disconnect themselves for extended periods of time in order to satisfy this equation.</p>
<p>Cal denounces the culture of companies ordering their employs to maintain twitter/emails, and even open air offices, as they hinder in general productivity</p>
<p>Another interesting concept is the idea of <strong>attention residue</strong>. The book tells us that when we switch tasks in rapid succession, which has become the new normal in the multitasker-hustler fad we have today, is a terrible practice that both reduces attention, and quality of work.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-in-it-for-meyou">What is in it for me/you?</h1>
<p>So far, I have been a man of shallow work. This book really made me reconsider how I practice work.
I highly recommend the book to anyone who has the hunger for success in this ever-changing economy.</p>
<p>You can find the book on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00X47ZVXM">Amazon</a></p>
<p>Happy reading!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Learning to Hack: A Resource Guide</title>
			<link>/posts/learning-to-hack-a-resource-guide./</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 10:54:36 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>/posts/learning-to-hack-a-resource-guide./</guid>
			<description>Being a hacker sounds really cool. But how do you become one?
In this resource guide, i will try to tackle this question by identifying a few essential skills and websites that helped (and is continuing to help) me learn how to hack.
1. googling This is one of the most underrated and valuable skills to have as someone who works with computers. Being able to find information and research will certainly get you further in the cybersphere.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="being-a-hacker-sounds-really-cool"><strong>Being a hacker sounds really cool.</strong></h2>
<p>But how do you become one?</p>
<p>In this resource guide, i will try to tackle this question by identifying a few essential <em>skills and websites</em> that helped (and is continuing to help) me learn how to hack.</p>
<h1 id="1-googling">1. googling</h1>
<p>This is one of the most underrated and valuable skills to have as someone who works with computers. Being able to <em>find information</em> and <em>research</em> will certainly get you further in the cybersphere.</p>
<h1 id="2-linux">2. Linux</h1>
<p>Anyone who aspires to become a hacker <strong>must</strong> have at least a passable knowledge of Linux. Although you could work with operating systems like Windows or macOS, it is ill-advised because <em>most tools and framework</em> are made for Linux in specific.</p>
<p>Popular hacking (more commonly called as “pentesting”) frameworks like Kali Linux or Parrot OS have a lot of tools built-in, which is very convenient</p>
<h1 id="3-capture-the-flag">3. Capture the flag</h1>
<p>Now we are starting to enter the more interesting stuff!</p>
<p>Capture the flag (CTFs) are mini-games that are hosted on a platform to enable hackers to practice their skills in a safe environment.
Most CTFs have a system wherein you have to enumerate a system and find a certain file or so-called “flag”</p>
<p>one of my favorite CTF is the <a href="https://overthewire.org/wargames/">over the wire</a>, and it really helped me to start off</p>
<h1 id="4tryhackme-boxes">4.TryHackMe boxes</h1>
<p><a href="https://tryhackme.com/">TryHackMe</a> is an excellent website to start understanding tools and frameworks.
They have amazing rooms like the metasploit and nmap walkthroughs that really help you grasp how a tool or a framework works.</p>
<p>You can also go down one of their <a href="https://tryhackme.com/paths">learning paths</a>, which will have your understanding a concept at a deeper level.</p>
<h1 id="where-next">Where Next?</h1>
<p>Assuming you have done all the above, you can say with certainty that you have <strong>mastered the basics of hacking.</strong></p>
<p>🎊 congrats!
Your next step might be researching about fun domains like <strong>Bug bounties</strong> or <strong>freelance pentesting.</strong></p>
<p>else, you may also want to do rooms (similar to TryHackMe) on <a href="https://app.hackthebox.eu/">HackTheBox</a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
