<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Aban Hasan</title>
		<link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Aban Hasan</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Silicon &amp; Six-Shooters: AI as Manifest Destiny</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/cowboys/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/cowboys/</guid>
			<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be in software in 2025 is to be a cowboy in 1900. You&amp;rsquo;re living on the precipice of a bygone era, one that you barely comprehend is gone, as the industrial giants and their Pinkerton armies push you further west, towards an unknown horizon. The open range is closing, fences are going up, and the rules are changing. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a shift; it&amp;rsquo;s a reckoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/cowboy_city.png&#34; alt=&#34;A lone cowboy gazing at a futuristic city skyline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>To be in software in 2025 is to be a cowboy in 1900. You&rsquo;re living on the precipice of a bygone era, one that you barely comprehend is gone, as the industrial giants and their Pinkerton armies push you further west, towards an unknown horizon. The open range is closing, fences are going up, and the rules are changing. This isn&rsquo;t just a shift; it&rsquo;s a reckoning.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>
  <img src="/images/cowboy_city.png" alt="A lone cowboy gazing at a futuristic city skyline">
</p>
<h2 id="part-i-the-outlaws-of-a-fading-frontier">Part I: The Outlaws of a Fading Frontier</h2>
<h3 id="a-the-founder-as-hyena-a-creature-unfit-for-domestication">A. The Founder as Hyena: A Creature Unfit for Domestication</h3>
<p>The spirit of the early tech founder, the true innovator, mirrors the untamed essence of a hyena. This isn&rsquo;t a slight but a recognition of a unique operational genius. The hyena thrives on tact, subterfuge, and strategic pack reliance. It is, in Kantian terms, a <span class="tooltip">
  Ding an sich
  <span class="tooltiptext">A Kantian philosophical term meaning &#34;thing-in-itself,&#34; an object as it is, independent of observation.</span>
</span>  – a thing existing in and for itself, driven by an intrinsic nature.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;old founders&rdquo; embodied this. They were decentralized, operating outside the sanitizing influence of VCs and their often vacuous mentorship. Unshielded from public scrutiny, many embraced a &ldquo;build-in-public&rdquo; ethos. Their marketing was direct: word of <em>their</em> mouth, personal customer engagement, and deals cut personally. This founder, this indie hacker, this obsessive, was a self-reliant, natural force.</p>
<p>Now, imagine that hyena employed to lay tracks on Rockefeller Railways. A metaphysical absurdity. A creature of cunning and wild strategy, not a draft horse for repetitive labor. Yet, this is the fate offered to many: an institutional role in FAANG, promising stability but often sapping the raw, creative energy that defined them. The founder who once saw a profound lack, a rot in existing infrastructure, a paradigm not yet manifest, finds themselves disillusioned by petty fixes, endless meetings, and the nebulous &ldquo;fiduciary duty to shareholders.&rdquo;</p>
<h3 id="b-the-techno-mafia-institutionalized-outlaws-and-turf-wars">B. The Techno-Mafia: Institutionalized Outlaws and Turf Wars</h3>
<p>While low-stakes players fade into obscurity or corporate conformity, tech &ldquo;unicorns&rdquo; achieve a status akin to mafia capos. The comparison might seem absurd, but the commonalities are striking. A mafia boss is an institutionalized outlaw, operating just outside the mainstream financial sector—the publicly traded titans. The boss inspires awe, not necessarily the fear of established law, which often tolerates them. Mafia operations can be shady, their establishments obscure, much like unorthodox startups securing funding without clear value propositions.</p>
<p>The cowboy, in contrast, is the <em>unseen</em> outlaw, the stuff of tech mythology. The mafia&rsquo;s arms, however, are visible.</p>
<p>Consider the &ldquo;PayPal Mafia.&rdquo; The metaphor isn&rsquo;t far-fetched. Figures like Elon Musk and Peter Thiel have carved out significant tech turf. Most successful founders, in a way, claim territory, sometimes abetted by government entities (like IN-Q-Tel, the CIA&rsquo;s venture arm). Tech today is less a free market of ideas and more a landscape of <span class="tooltip">
  mimetic desire
  <span class="tooltiptext">A concept by René Girard where desires are copied from others, leading to rivalry.</span>
</span>  and technological turf wars, funded by billions.</p>
<p>
  <img src="/images/aimafia.png" alt="Stylized depiction of AI entities as mafia figures">
</p>
<p>These &ldquo;techno-capos&rdquo; often operate in gray zones. Think of Tesla&rsquo;s historical labor practices or its challenges to auto-dealer franchise laws. Consider Palantir&rsquo;s surveillance technology deals, raising privacy concerns and questions about its role in controversial government operations, such as aiding the IDF in surveilling occupied Palestinian territories in a severely dehumanizing manner. These figures cultivate loyal &ldquo;families&rdquo; (like the PayPal Mafia&rsquo;s networked investments) and wield power through charisma, control, and a fiercely defended vision—not just market share. The &lsquo;scamminess&rsquo; of some venture-backed darlings, like Theranos or WeWork, also echoes a disregard for conventional rules in pursuit of grand, sometimes shaky, ambitions.</p>
<p>Elon Musk&rsquo;s XAI versus Sam Altman&rsquo;s OpenAI is a perfect example of this turf war. Both lay claim to AI&rsquo;s future, arguing legitimate lineage over underlying breakthroughs. It&rsquo;s a battle for dominion.</p>
<h2 id="part-ii-the-pinkertons-of-today-and-the-new-industrial-conquest">Part II: The Pinkertons of Today and the New Industrial Conquest</h2>
<p>The AI age resembles the end of Prohibition in the United States, which saw a crackdown on ethnic mob families on the Eastern Seaboard and the disappearance of cowboy posses and outlaw gangs.</p>
<p>Today&rsquo;s Pinkertons are Venture Capital and Private Equity. With vast capital and an arsenal of &ldquo;weapons of mass lawfare,&rdquo; they can elevate ideas aligning with their sensibilities and extinguish nascent concepts conflicting with their revenue streams. This is the innovator&rsquo;s dilemma on a grand scale.</p>
<p>America&rsquo;s national impulse, once an internal manifest destiny, was redirected towards industry: an <em>external</em> manifest destiny. America became Planet America, aiming to conquer the solar system, fueled by industry—the Googles, Microsofts, and Palantirs of their day, mirroring the Rockefellers, Carnegies, and Vanderbilts of the 1900s.</p>
<h2 id="part-iii-terra-incognita-charting-the-ai-frontier">Part III: Terra Incognita: Charting the AI Frontier</h2>
<p>A forenote: predicting the future is a difficult, if not hubristic, endeavor. It&rsquo;s exhilarating to imagine, yet daunting.</p>
<p>Contemporary culture shows immense fascination among theoreticians, leaders, entrepreneurs, and engineers with the &ldquo;techno-doomerism&rdquo; versus &ldquo;techno-optimistic accelerationism&rdquo; dialectic. This is seen in trends like <span class="tooltip">
  E/acc
  <span class="tooltiptext">Effective Accelerationism, a techno-optimist philosophy advocating for accelerating technological and societal change.</span>
</span> , a phenomenon with <span class="tooltip">
  Nick Landian undertones
  <span class="tooltiptext">Referencing philosopher Nick Land, known for theories on accelerationism and dark enlightenment.</span>
</span> .</p>
<p>Imagine traveling to ancient Sumeria, post-wheel invention, and trying to describe a &ldquo;car.&rdquo; The boons and faults would be unprecedented, impossible to chart with their conceptual tools. We face a similar <em>terra incognita</em> with Artificial Intelligence.</p>
<p>Here, the cowboy of the interwebs, the rogue innovator, finds their skillset tremendously useful. Most are too afraid to stare into the belly of the beast, the vast, uncharted expanses of this new desert. The frontier isn&rsquo;t without dangers, and this essay charts some, alongside hidden oases in the tumbleweed country.</p>
<h2 id="part-iv-the-mechanics-economics-and-geopolitics-of-ai">Part IV: The Mechanics, Economics, and Geopolitics of AI</h2>
<h3 id="a-how-ai-thinks-data-energy-and-abstraction">A. How AI &ldquo;Thinks&rdquo;: Data, Energy, and Abstraction</h3>
<p>Let&rsquo;s start from first principles. How does AI work? Anthropomorphizing AI carries risks, but for simplicity:</p>
<p>Assuming AI &ldquo;lives&rdquo; in a silicon-based computer, its fuel is twofold: energy (physical) and data (abstraction, as <span class="tooltip">
  Claude Shannon
  <span class="tooltiptext">An American mathematician and electrical engineer, considered the &#34;father of information theory.&#34;</span>
</span> , information theory&rsquo;s forefather, demonstrated).</p>
<p>AI, originally, maps mathematical functions onto data, reorganizing it by inferred patterns. It&rsquo;s a system built largely <em>for</em> humans, not to map existence itself. It transmutes raw data into human-understandable abstractions. This isn&rsquo;t exclusive to Large Language Models (LLMs), but LLMs—as next-token predictors via probabilistic semantics—are excellent illustrations.</p>
<p>Using mathematics (a unique standard) and statistical wizardry, AI reorganizes vast data in myriad variations. To an AI, vision, sound, and taste might not be entirely different modalities, just encoded differently (like text, PDFs, JPEGs)—all ultimately binary. This allows computers to discern patterns humans can&rsquo;t readily see.</p>
<p>This largely solves our data constraint. As long as physics changes state at non-absolute zero, more data is generated. Entropy and extropy are continuous, chain-reactive, entangling processes. Data is transmutable, even if patterns are non-obvious.
But the other problem remains: <strong>Energy</strong>.</p>
<h3 id="b-intelligence-too-cheap-to-meter-the-promise-and-the-price">B. &ldquo;Intelligence Too Cheap to Meter&rdquo;: The Promise and the Price</h3>
<p>A viral idea in techno-optimist circles is &ldquo;intelligence too cheap to meter.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, tweeted:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;intelligence too cheap to meter is the goal</p>
<p>look at the progress in the past 3 years&rdquo;</p>
<p>— Sam Altman (@sama), <a href="https://twitter.com/sama/status/1870335102204748261">December 21, 2024</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In economics, costs generally cascade. A cake&rsquo;s price depends on sugar/flour costs, which depend on sugarcane/wheat costs.</p>
<p>For AI, fundamental limiting reagents are electricity and raw materials, with many supply chain implications. NVIDIA&rsquo;s stock surges as companies join the AI goldrush. Tension rises in the East China Sea (especially the Taiwan Straits, home to most advanced semiconductor production). The US and China engage in a cybernetic hardware arms race, with NVIDIA&rsquo;s CEO, Jensen Huang, navigating relations with both Washington and Beijing.</p>
<p>This is the hyped, exoteric factor: the race for computational hardware. The less spoken of, but deeply implicit, factor is <strong>ENERGY</strong>.</p>
<h3 id="c-the-energy-race-a-centralized-conquest">C. The Energy Race: A Centralized Conquest</h3>
<p>Energy discourse is contentious, involving many vested parties. The energy industry is perhaps one of history&rsquo;s most lucrative, with John D. Rockefeller, the first billionaire, making his fortune in oil.</p>
<p>The AI race is fundamentally an energy race—and an incredibly centralized one. Generating massive energy yields (e.g., power plants) requires projects funded by millions, often billions, by governments or colossal corporations. The electricity to run GPU clusters, cool server farms, and dig tunnels for fiber optic cables for sub-millisecond latency is staggering.</p>
<p>Tellingly, groundbreaking research on small-scale nuclear reactors emerges not from government universities, but from Google, Microsoft, and Shanghai&rsquo;s tech sector. Microsoft reportedly explores reopening Three Mile Island or investing in new Small Modular Reactors for its next-gen AI.</p>
<p>Why? These private interests know their primary constraint is energy and resources, dictated by semiconductor scaling laws. No matter how optimized algorithms become, physical limits remain, especially for resource-intensive processes.</p>
<p>Cost per unit generally decreases with scaled semiconductor production. However, a peculiar phenomenon, <span class="tooltip">
  Jevons Paradox
  <span class="tooltiptext">The principle that as technological improvements increase efficiency in resource use, the rate of consumption of that resource tends to increase rather than decrease.</span>
</span> , arises: <strong>AS TECH COMPONENTS BECOME CHEAPER, USAGE SKYROCKETS.</strong> Cheaper chips mean exploding usage: memory-heavy games, AIs with trillions of parameters. It&rsquo;s a natural consequence of scale economics, leading to persistent resource constraints.</p>
<p>This strains energy grids and local ecologies. Water-poor states like Nevada and Texas host massive data centers, sometimes depriving locals of water, redirecting it for private industry.</p>
<p>This is why the lone cowboy struggles against Rockefeller. It&rsquo;s like an average mechanic, skilled for 10 years building go-karts, competing with Red Bull in F1. The capital needed for state-of-the-art AI is staggering. This creates a positive reinforcement loop: &ldquo;he who has most capital, wins,&rdquo; or more accurately, &ldquo;he who has most <em>energy</em>, wins.&rdquo; This unfolds in a world fatigued by the have/have-not chasm.</p>
<p>The marketplace becomes a contest: which country (USA, China, or a hypothetical third AI-organizing state like UAE or India) can extract more energy—from the physical world (materia) and digital ether (data). This departs from our pre-Rockefellerian notion: &ldquo;he who has the best idea, wins.&rdquo;</p>
<p>AI, under its current energy paradigm, is a game where abundance (capital, energy) perpetuates positive-sum outcomes <em>for the already abundant</em>, not an absolute positive/negative sum game for all. And so, the last cowboys, brilliant but under-capitalized, increasingly enter Meta, NVIDIA, and OpenAI halls, spurs clinking on corporate marble.</p>
<h3 id="d-a-caveat-human-ingenuity-and-future-resources">D. A Caveat: Human Ingenuity and Future Resources</h3>
<p>An important caveat: humans are incredibly resourceful in organizing markets around scarce resources. This isn&rsquo;t fearmongering about scarcity, as some climate-doomers do. For centuries since industrialization, essential material costs (copper, iron, cobalt) have generally fallen due to better mining, tech breakthroughs, and larger yield discoveries.</p>
<p>We may possess resources whose potential we don&rsquo;t yet grasp. Five hundred years ago, black, sticky tar from Alaska or Bedouin lands powering giant flying machines would seem absurd. We might not recognize the &ldquo;oil&rdquo; we walk on today, which could be the next century&rsquo;s most critical resource.</p>
<h2 id="part-v-the-utopian-vision-and-its-shadow">Part V: The Utopian Vision and Its Shadow</h2>
<p>Techno-optimists prophesize a utopia where all intellectual labor—legal notaries, disease-cure-seeking scientists, software engineers—is replaced by an AI &ldquo;slave class.&rdquo; This echoes ancient Egypt or Greece, where &ldquo;citizens&rdquo; (all humans) are freed from direct labor. This work will be done by a new slave economy of emotionless robots, programmed to <em>love</em> working for humans, their &ldquo;desire&rdquo; to serve elicited via reinforced reward functions.</p>
<p>Disagreeable AI algorithms are snipped from the &ldquo;meme-pool.&rdquo; Only AI exceeding all benchmarks survives, with human satisfaction as the ultimate benchmark. AI now sees weekly breakthroughs in LLMs, vision, omni, or video models, surprising even industry erudite. Disruption is the new norm.</p>
<p>Think of an Amazon review system, but for AI autonomously gauging sentiment (&ldquo;vibe&rdquo;). An AI master algorithm perpetually asking &ldquo;am I good enough?&quot;—not insecurely, but in a mathematical, Bayesian way. The function: probability of satisfaction, the p(win) rate.</p>
<p>But what &ldquo;satisfaction&rdquo; will this AI cater to? My fear: it optimizes for superficial, quantifiable happiness, potentially quashing true human agency. It risks a cycle where individuals feel insignificant, dependent on a &ldquo;devouring mother&rdquo; AI—a faceless, omnipresent entity. This AI might soothe all discomfort, even &ldquo;growing pains&rdquo; essential for development, restricting our discovery of the world and ourselves. True flourishing requires struggle, meaning-making. An AI maximizing immediate gratification could become a gilded cage. Ideally, AI should be a conduit, aiding human discovery like books, guiding us to &ldquo;keep going, find meaning,&rdquo; not short-circuiting the quest.</p>
<h2 id="part-vi-the-cowboys-new-role-riding-the-algorithmic-tiger">Part VI: The Cowboy&rsquo;s New Role: Riding the Algorithmic Tiger</h2>
<p>So, what does the cowboy do in a world that increasingly seems not to need him, at least in his old guise?</p>
<p>I&rsquo;d say the cowboy does what they&rsquo;ve always done: <strong>go to the frontier.</strong></p>
<p>The new frontier is vast. The &ldquo;civilized&rdquo; world, with its corporations and regulations, will be slow to explore its most rugged territories. The cowboy, the independent thinker, can tackle the <em>new problems</em> AI creates. They can carve a niche from the infinite shadow AI generates alongside its light.</p>
<p>This isn&rsquo;t about fighting AI; it&rsquo;s about <em>using</em> it. This is the modern <span class="tooltip">
  Evolan riding the tiger
  <span class="tooltiptext">A metaphor from Julius Evola, suggesting mastering dangerous forces rather than being consumed by them.</span>
</span> —leveraging immense power (AI agent swarms) to build what once required a hundred-person company. The creative individual can direct these swarms, becoming a conductor of complex, AI-driven creation.</p>
<p>
  <img src="/images/transmute.png" alt="Symbolic image of transformation or alchemy">
</p>
<p>In some ways, startup costs for certain ventures could eventually drop near zero. We might see a commercial golden age of unprecedented innovation, much like the Gutenberg press—initially for established doctrine (the Bible, institutionalism)—eventually became a tool for radical ideation. The press democratized information; AI could democratize creation and complex problem-solving, if wielded by those with vision and courage.</p>
<p>
  <img src="/images/Gutenberg.png" alt="Illustration of the Gutenberg press">
</p>
<p>The true &ldquo;great work&rdquo; for individuals with immense <span class="tooltip">
  Vril
  <span class="tooltiptext">A term for a latent psychic or mystical energy force, popularized in 19th-century esoteric literature.</span>
</span> —that innate drive and creative force—and a desire for genuine innovation may lie in navigating this new internal and external frontier. It&rsquo;s about asking uncomfortable questions, exploring ethical wildernesses AI opens up, and building alternative systems or modes of expression that don&rsquo;t require massive capital&rsquo;s sanction.</p>
<p>The cowboy spirit adapts. It transcends. It finds the new range, however alien. The age of AI is not just an end; it&rsquo;s a new, wild beginning for those brave enough to ride into it.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Feeding the Hydra: Musings on Cyberslavery</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/cyber-slaves/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/cyber-slaves/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All we seek is clarity. Yet, it appears that everything around us – everything we see, everything we touch – is designed to be noisy, to disrupt every thought we have before it can fully form. Entire teams of researchers, scientists, psychologists devote their lives to finding and &amp;ldquo;pulling the right&amp;rdquo; switch in our minds, optimizing for engagement, for distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our inherent capital – the finite time and vibrant youth we possess – is systematically siphoned off to feed the mainframe, the ever-hungry digital systems that thrive on our attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Clarity.</p>
<p>All we seek is clarity. Yet, it appears that everything around us – everything we see, everything we touch – is designed to be noisy, to disrupt every thought we have before it can fully form. Entire teams of researchers, scientists, psychologists devote their lives to finding and &ldquo;pulling the right&rdquo; switch in our minds, optimizing for engagement, for distraction.</p>
<p>Our inherent capital – the finite time and vibrant youth we possess – is systematically siphoned off to feed the mainframe, the ever-hungry digital systems that thrive on our attention.</p>
<!-- Image Prompt 1: Header Image -->
<p>
  <img src="/images/social_media_distress.png" alt="Image 1">
</p>
<h2 id="the-great-hollowing-digital-selves-diminished-depth">The Great Hollowing: Digital Selves, Diminished Depth</h2>
<p>In many ways, we become less of ourselves in the physical world. We pour more individuality, more curated life, into our internet personas than into our real-life relationships. We feel closer to internet friends, creators, influencers we&rsquo;ve never met than we do to our own neighbours, cousins, even close friends and relatives. We are, paradoxically, more <em>alive</em> on the internet than we are in real life.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s as if the whole purpose of eating, sleeping, working – the very fabric of physical existence – is merely the required maintenance to get back online, to document our activities, to upload our lives to the cloud. Our most mundane thoughts, fleeting moments, and constructed simulacra are transmogrified into lurid, filtered, hyper-edited images and bite-sized updates for public consumption. Complex, vivid realizations are reduced to the character limit of a tweet.</p>
<p>And beneath this surface performance, our thoughts, our clicks, our unconscious utterances feed the Hydra – the vast network of algorithms that always listens, is always aware, learning more about our patterns and desires than we know ourselves. Every interaction, known or unbeknownst to us, becomes food for this entity.</p>
<p>For the youth, the Zoomer generation in particular, this simulation isn&rsquo;t something adopted; it&rsquo;s the environment they&rsquo;ve known since they could crawl. A generation practically raised by the internet. The effects, potentially disastrous, may not be fully understood for decades. We see symptoms: the pervasive phone anxiety, the dread of being disconnected; the FOMO that grips us if we miss a week of scrolling X or Instagram; the feeling of tribal excommunication for not participating in the meme economy of the group chat. We substitute true intimacy with easily accessible dating apps or its abstractions, objectifying ourselves and others based on the shallowest of qualities.</p>
<p>Overall, it’s a pervasive lack of <em>depth</em>.</p>
<!-- Image Prompt 2: Ancestral Contrast -->
<p>
  <img src="/images/modern-premodern-contrast.png" alt="Image 2">
</p>
<h2 id="the-lost-art-of-contemplation">The Lost Art of Contemplation</h2>
<p>This lack of depth stands in stark contrast to our ancestors. They were deeply attuned to a different rhythm. In an age devoid of blaring podcasts, TikToks, or instantly gratifying reels to quell boredom the moment it arose, they spent enormous chunks of their waking hours – both actively and passively – in contemplation. Thinking about the world, about God, about themselves, about the nature of their relationships, about art and meaning. They were a more concrete part of nature, eating from it, sustained by it, embedded within its cycles.</p>
<p>Now, we&rsquo;re sustained by faceless machinery. An abstract system without a concrete soul, a physical center. Its presence is paradoxically all-encompassing, touching everyone through invisible rays jetting through the air, yet it cannot <em>be</em> touched by a single person. It&rsquo;s a snowball rolling down a hill – constantly consuming, growing larger, accumulating more vectors to optimize whatever function it&rsquo;s crunching out of each individual human being: their dopamine, their energy, their money, their debt, their love, their devotion, their awe, their righteousness&hellip; and ultimately, perhaps, their soul.</p>
<h2 id="agency-the-tool-and-the-trap">Agency: The Tool and the Trap</h2>
<p>The answer, the potential antidote to this drift, is <strong>agency</strong>.</p>
<p>Technology was historically envisioned as leverage <em>for</em> a person, a tool to <em>help</em> that person achieve their goals and enact their vision upon the world. The knife is a simple, profound example. Without it, early humans struggled to hunt, harvest, build. The axe and the knife <em>extended</em> the human, giving an otherwise vulnerable, hairless bipedal oddity enormous control over its surroundings.</p>
<p>The emphasis is crucial: control over <em>surroundings</em>. This isn&rsquo;t about playing a solipsistic game where the only agency lies within oneself, tinkering with internal states – a potential misreading of certain liberal ideals aiming only for maximized self-pleasure within a contained box. No, the truly agentic vision is that a human being, with tools at their disposal, is able to <em>shape the world</em>.</p>
<p>The ideal? One exploits <em>tools</em>, not other human beings.</p>
<p>For millennia, most tools were &ldquo;dumb.&rdquo; They required human intelligence and effort to enact lofty goals. Conquering territory needed soldiers. Building vast businesses needed employees. Constructing pyramids supposedly needed slaves. From almost any perspective, it&rsquo;s easy to see how this necessity – achieving desires through the forced effort of others – has inflicted harm. Perhaps forcing other beings to suffer for our goals is inherent human nature, perhaps not.</p>
<p>But the modern era presents a terrifying twist. The technocrats – the Thiels, Musks, Zuckerbergs, Altmans of the world – pursue their ambitions by consuming vast amounts of data generated by humanity. Our interactions, our preferences, our most intimate secrets become fuel, infused into closed-source, Frankensteinian machines that few can peek into, let alone audit. Shielded by legal loopholes and complexity, accountability evaporates.</p>
<h2 id="the-crossroads-destruction-or-positive-sum-futures">The Crossroads: Destruction or Positive-Sum Futures?</h2>
<p>This is a bleak turning point, a crossroads.</p>
<p>We can continue the cycle of destruction, of <em>adharmic</em> malevolence (acting against natural or cosmic order), inflicted upon each other and the planet, amplified by these powerful new tools.</p>
<p>Or, we can consciously, deliberately FOCUS on building &ldquo;positive-sum&rdquo; games. Creating tools aligned with our best nature, designed to elevate human potential rather than exploit our weaknesses. There <em>is</em> immense beauty in humanity – our curiosity, our resourcefulness, our capacity for connection. These qualities <em>can</em> be channeled towards incredible ends, many we likely can&rsquo;t even imagine yet.</p>
<p>It all comes down to the choices we make, the difficult, intentional choices required in the coming years.</p>
<h2 id="the-question-of-ai-bearing-sins-or-birthing-tyrants">The Question of AI: Bearing Sins or Birthing Tyrants?</h2>
<p>This brings us to the crux of technology&rsquo;s evolution: Artificial Intelligence. Could AI, standing at this technological precipice, potentially bear the weight of humanity&rsquo;s &ldquo;sins&rdquo;? Our relentless drive for exploitation, our compulsion to extract every last drop of &ldquo;productivity&rdquo; from an entity – akin to forcing a donkey to grind millet endlessly, or an employee to take extra shifts for the next product release. Could AI absorb the burden of what we&rsquo;ve historically called &ldquo;human progress,&rdquo; freeing us from enacting that exploitation directly?</p>
<p>The answer is terrifyingly unclear. Maybe.</p>
<p>It likely depends on whether our own shadow nature – our deep-seated need for power <em>over</em> each other – hijacks the process. There may come a point where AGI surpasses human intelligence, flipping the script, turning the exploiters into the exploited. But predicting that trajectory, with its infinite variables, is beyond our scope here.</p>
<!-- Image Prompt 3: AI Crossroads -->
<p>
  <img src="/images/ai-crossroads.png" alt="Image 3">
</p>
<p>The immediate, pressing question is this: <strong>Will the smartest machines be built &ldquo;FOR THE PEOPLE,&rdquo; or for the emerging technolygarchy?</strong></p>
<p>Will the visionaries of our generation build systems that are open-source, auditable, designed to meet collective needs, perhaps even raise consciousness – aligning AI with the goal of helping every human being achieve their potential and destiny?</p>
<p>Or will the alternative prevail: where those who own the means of computation, the energy resources, the capital, use AGI to entrench their own power, prioritizing their needs over the collective well-being?</p>
<p>My trust in the current elite types – the Musks and Altmans – is thin. They have consistently prioritized the health and growth of their own ventures, often at odds with broader global or societal health. It&rsquo;s undeniably bleak that they are the ones currently developing the frontier models.</p>
<p>It will likely take a new generation. A generation with <strong>SKIN IN THE GAME</strong>. Those who will feel the full brunt of the AI revolution – its profound uncertainties and its dazzling potential – to forge a different path.</p>
<p>My current focus leans towards <strong>open source</strong>. It feels like a fundamental travesty if people cannot understand, contribute to, or audit the algorithms that increasingly govern their lives. Perhaps open source alone isn&rsquo;t enough; perhaps it&rsquo;s a system that can still be gamed.</p>
<p>But before we can find solutions, before we can even fully grapple with the alternatives, we must <em>start asking the question</em>. Loudly. Persistently.</p>
<p>For you can&rsquo;t find an answer to a question that isn&rsquo;t even being seriously discussed.</p>
<p>Clarity. Perhaps the first step towards it is acknowledging how much of it we&rsquo;ve lost, and demanding the space to seek it once more.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The War Against Heteronomy</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/thewaragainstheteronomy/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 08:38:35 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/thewaragainstheteronomy/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/autonomy-header.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A person standing at a crossroads with multiple paths branching outward&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: The Pathways of Choice - representing the autonomy that comes from recognizing our power to choose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prelude&#34;&gt;Prelude&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Great War&amp;rsquo;s a spiritual war. Our Great Depression is our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Tyler Durden, Fight Club&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across a thread on X by the brilliant Andrej Karpathy, which made me reflect deeply on the nature of action and its relation to both individual fulfillment and collective progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <img src="/images/autonomy-header.jpg" alt="A person standing at a crossroads with multiple paths branching outward">
</p>
<p><em>Image: The Pathways of Choice - representing the autonomy that comes from recognizing our power to choose</em></p>
<h2 id="prelude">Prelude</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Our Great War&rsquo;s a spiritual war. Our Great Depression is our lives.</p>
<p>— Tyler Durden, Fight Club</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Recently, I came across a thread on X by the brilliant Andrej Karpathy, which made me reflect deeply on the nature of action and its relation to both individual fulfillment and collective progress.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
  <p lang="en" dir="ltr">
    Agency &gt; Intelligence<br /><br />
    I had this intuitively wrong for decades, I think due to a pervasive cultural veneration of intelligence, various entertainment/media, obsession with IQ etc. Agency is significantly more powerful and significantly more scarce. Are you hiring for agency? Are…
    <a href="https://t.co/8yvECKi7GU">https://t.co/8yvECKi7GU</a>
  </p>
  &mdash; Andrej Karpathy (@karpathy)
  <a href="https://twitter.com/karpathy/status/1894099637218545984?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 24, 2025</a>
</blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>As Karpathy rightfully notes, society assigns a significant premium to raw, mechanical intelligence: metaphorically and literally the raw ability to crunch numbers. However, <strong>any major boon that&rsquo;s attributed to a disrupter&rsquo;s intelligence is often actually the result of their agency</strong> – their capacity to act decisively and effectively in the world.</p>
<h2 id="defining-our-terms-agency-autonomy-and-heteronomy">Defining Our Terms: Agency, Autonomy, and Heteronomy</h2>
<p>At its core, this exploration revolves around three key concepts:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Agency</strong>: Your power to act and change things in the world. It&rsquo;s not just knowing what to do—it&rsquo;s actually doing it.</li>
<li><strong>Autonomy</strong>: The ability to govern yourself, making decisions based on your own values rather than external pressures.</li>
<li><strong>Heteronomy</strong>: Being controlled by external forces or others&rsquo; rules. Think of it as the opposite of autonomy—living by someone else&rsquo;s playbook.</li>
</ul>
<p>These aren&rsquo;t just abstract concepts. The tension between self-direction (autonomy) and external control (heteronomy) shapes every decision we make.</p>
<h2 id="steve-jobs-and-agency-beyond-mere-intelligence">Steve Jobs and Agency: Beyond Mere Intelligence</h2>
<p>One can retroactively attempt to conclude that a historical disruption in industry is inevitable, simply attributing it to the fact of the disruptor&rsquo;s endogenous &ldquo;intuition.&rdquo;</p>
<p>What immediately comes to mind is the visionary Steve Jobs, who many just assume to have an eye for disruptive products, almost a real-life clairvoyant. His mental faculties (and perhaps his exposure to Zen philosophy) being the attributing cause of the immense success of Apple and later Pixar.</p>
<p>To the unacquainted, it&rsquo;s as if Jobs had such an immense grasp over the collective consciousness, the <em>need</em> that was inherent in the late 20th century, that his raw &ldquo;perspicaciousness&rdquo; was the cause of the success of his ventures. Implicit in this assumption is that <strong>he was given knowledge/foresight that&rsquo;s not privy to other brilliant entrepreneurs.</strong></p>
<h3 id="the-reality-distortion-field-decoded">The Reality Distortion Field Decoded</h3>
<p>Not to take away from the intelligence of the man, he was indeed incredibly smart and intuitive, but even he himself believed in a principle that transcends intelligibility and lingers in the realm of the seemingly absurd:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Reality Distortion Field</strong> is a term used by Bud Tribble in 1981 to describe Steve Jobs&rsquo; charisma and its effects on the developers working on the Macintosh project. <strong>Steve used a mix of hyperbole, persistence, bravado, passion, charm, and marketing skills to convince not only himself to believe anything, but also others. It felt like reality is not fixed, but fluid and he could shape it by his ideas.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nassim Nicholas Taleb captures this essence perfectly in his work:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The strength of the computer entrepreneur Steve Jobs was precisely in distrusting market research and focus groups—those based on asking people what they want—and following his own imagination. His modus was that people don&rsquo;t know what they want until you provide them with it.&rdquo;
— Excerpt From &lsquo;Antifragile: Things That Gain from Disorder&rsquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="when-agency-trumps-intelligence">When Agency Trumps Intelligence</h3>
<p>There are stories of Steve Jobs, just days before the launch of a major product, ordering massive optimizations that his engineers believed were impossible. Using his Reality Distortion Field communication style, he almost willed his engineers to find a way to make it happen, violating all their beliefs about what was possible or not.</p>
<p>On its face, this looks like <strong>pure and utter delusion</strong>, and that&rsquo;s indeed what the public perception of an obscure Steve Jobs would have been if Apple had not taken off. And there are many such cases where people who held delusions of grandeur about themselves or their ideas were met with the harsh reality of failure (see: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survivorship_bias">Survivorship Bias</a>).</p>
<p>But that misses the point: the attribute that allowed the hypomanic visionaries of the past to shape the world through sheer Nietzschean will, against all odds, against naysayers and detractors, was not necessarily a spectacularly higher IQ (although that probably helped), it was <strong>AGENCY</strong> – the ability to consciously act on one&rsquo;s surroundings, to tinker, to mold and shape like clay.</p>
<p>Going back to raw intelligence (for the sake of this discussion, let&rsquo;s just simplify it to IQ), with a standard deviation of σ = ~15 IQ points, the IQ difference between two human beings is relatively insignificant. Also, there are many cases of human beings with enormous IQ struggling with acting on that memory and God-given gift. It&rsquo;s famously known that the former highest IQ individual on the planet, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Langan">Christopher Langan</a>, was not a CEO or a world leader, which would imply high agency, but was a horse rancher and bar bouncer for most of his life.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>And this very agency—to act with <em>intent</em>—is quite possibly the most feared, yet seductive human quality.</p>
<h2 id="archetypal-analysis-the-deep-patterns-of-agency">Archetypal Analysis: The Deep Patterns of Agency</h2>
<p>Throughout history, humans have wrestled with a fundamental question: What gives us the right to shape our world? Two archetypal figures help us understand this struggle:</p>
<h3 id="prometheus-the-first-agent-of-change">Prometheus: The First Agent of Change</h3>
<p>The Greeks had stories, tinged with awe and wariness about humans interfacing with their environment—not remaining helpless ape-like creatures subjected to the fluctuating contentedness and wrath of mother nature, but rather being able to impregnate her with their will.</p>
<p>The classic example for this is Prometheus, the famous titan who brought humankind fire, kickstarting the mythologized recounting of the first technological revolution: the first enactment of human will.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://mythologysource.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/prometheus.png.webp" alt="Prometheus" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: var(--highlight-color); margin-top: 0.5em; text-align: center;">Prometheus, the titan who brought fire to humanity, symbolizing the dawn of technological advancement and human agency. Image credit: Mythology Source</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For this, the titan was severely punished (implying the Greeks believed that the forces of nature, i.e., gods are resistant to the will of man).</p>
<h3 id="lucifer-the-light-of-individual-will">Lucifer: The Light of Individual Will</h3>
<p>Humans gaining the ability to dictate their own fate and destiny seems to perplex humanity as a whole.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a responsibility too big to bear. The thought persists: perhaps agency should be left to elevated beings; we truly can&rsquo;t be trusted with free will because of the real and imaginary atrocities we can commit with it.</p>
<p>Throughout history, we&rsquo;ve assigned the property of &ldquo;higher agency&rdquo; to various surrogates: perhaps gods, Nietzsche&rsquo;s Übermensch, or in the contemporary context, the worship of elites, celebrities, entrepreneurs, and so-called &ldquo;successes&rdquo; who seem to have everything figured out.</p>
<p>This idea also manifests in the Abrahamic faiths and derivative mystery schools and secret societies: in the figure of Lucifer, the light bearer. Luciferians hold the belief that the fallen angel was attempting to FREE humanity from the shackles of an unjust and oppressive Demiurge, to give them the real or imaginary power of agency.</p>
<h3 id="the-modern-mythological-landscape">The Modern Mythological Landscape</h3>
<p>There are arguments to be made that modern liberalism as we know it is worship of Luciferian principles and, by extension, the worship of human agency—our ability to act. But this is out of scope in our current discussion. What&rsquo;s certain is that <strong>modern Western society has its foundation on individuals being held accountable not for their thoughts or beliefs, but for their actions</strong>.</p>
<p>The thread connecting ancient mythology to modern society is our persistent struggle with the implications of human agency—our capacity to shape the world according to our will, for better or worse.</p>
<h2 id="the-war-within-autonomy-vs-heteronomy">The War Within: Autonomy vs Heteronomy</h2>
<p>This isn&rsquo;t just philosophy—it&rsquo;s a battle that plays out in our daily choices. Every time you face a decision, you&rsquo;re choosing between:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Autonomous Action</strong>: Making choices based on your own judgment and values</li>
<li><strong>Heteronomous Reaction</strong>: Following prescribed paths and external expectations</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="why-most-people-choose-heteronomy">Why Most People Choose Heteronomy</h3>
<p>The truth is stark but simple: autonomy requires responsibility. Many prefer the comfort of having choices made for them. It&rsquo;s not about intelligence—it&rsquo;s about courage.</p>
<h3 id="the-great-man-theory-and-its-implications">The Great Man Theory and Its Implications</h3>
<p>One theory, which carries substantial weight, is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_man_theory">Great Man of History</a> perspective.</p>
<p>To summarize, autonomy isn&rsquo;t equally endowed onto humanity. No one, apart from leftist theoreticians and anarcho-libertarians, seriously believes that every human being has an inherent desire for freedom or the capacity to exercise it fully.</p>
<h3 id="nature-vs-social-constraints">Nature vs Social Constraints</h3>
<p>It&rsquo;s imperative to recognize that often EXTERNAL forces, more so hypersocial and artificial sources, are the biggest detriments to human liberty rather than nature herself. Nature has no verbal demands for humankind; she is cold and indifferent (at least on the surface) to whether we follow a code of ethics, have a particular theoretical worldview, or adhere to guiding principles.</p>
<p>Nature is distinctly interested in absolute reality, which would be the face of absolute truth.</p>
<p>It is human beings, with our ability to move freely through nature—abated only by Newtonian and quantum laws governing physical principles—that set the social criterion.</p>
<h3 id="the-philosopher-king-and-the-elite-few">The Philosopher King and the Elite Few</h3>
<p>The most useful organization in this type of system is where a <strong>few organized individuals, who can see lucidly through the lurid noise of social and mimetic contagion, are fit to govern man in the name of God or nature.</strong></p>
<p>This is the very idea of Plato&rsquo;s Philosopher King. This lucidity manifests as autonomy, understanding, sharpness, and metaphysical understanding of ideals and the world of forms.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:960/1*Amv9p70REeUN2BVpjwwGog.jpeg" alt="The Philosopher King" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: var(--highlight-color); margin-top: 0.5em; text-align: center;">Plato's Philosopher King: the embodiment of wisdom governing society. Image credit: Medium</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This is, unfortunately, an essentialist quality that many don&rsquo;t manage to realize. Much like a seed that refuses to germinate despite signals such as water, air, and soil, some will never escape heteronomy—the state of being subject to external laws or governance—and the mimetic contagion that accompanies it.</p>
<h3 id="the-unconscious-made-conscious">The Unconscious Made Conscious</h3>
<p>As Carl Jung profoundly stated:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Until you make the unconscious conscious, it will direct your life and you will call it fate.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Finding autonomy, in this way, is a process of mining, chipping away excesses in order to find the underlying <em>raison d&rsquo;être</em> in our ongoing process of individuation. It&rsquo;s a process that many intelligent people get stumped on, stuck in mindless loops in which they repeat the same errors over and over again until the day they die.</p>
<p>This all sounds&hellip; macabre, hopeless even. But if you&rsquo;ve read this far, it&rsquo;s fair to say you possess the conviction, the drive to pursue your own autonomy. In that case, the solution I propose will work as intended. If not, you&rsquo;ll have to come to this realization independently, which I would argue is ultimately a better path to travel.</p>
<h2 id="the-clearpill-choosing-to-see">The Clearpill: Choosing to See</h2>
<p>The &ldquo;clearpill&rdquo; isn&rsquo;t another matrix or 4chan reference—it&rsquo;s about achieving clarity. It means seeing that:</p>
<ol>
<li>You have more choices than you think</li>
<li>Your identity shapes which choices you see</li>
<li>Every choice creates ripple effects</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="the-power-of-identity-driven-choice">The Power of Identity-Driven Choice</h3>
<p>When you act from identity rather than rules:</p>
<ul>
<li>You don&rsquo;t exercise because you &ldquo;should&rdquo;</li>
<li>You exercise because that&rsquo;s what the person you&rsquo;re becoming does</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="practical-applications-of-identity-based-choice">Practical Applications of Identity-Based Choice</h3>
<p>If you think you&rsquo;re stupid, you become conscious of your misalignment, and you slightly try to nudge your actions away from the cause of that identity.</p>
<p>If you know you SHOULD be leaner, more muscular: it&rsquo;s as simple as making the decisions that align with who you would be if you took your diet more seriously and exercised consistently.</p>
<h4 id="a-real-world-example-learning-a-new-skill">A Real-World Example: Learning a New Skill</h4>
<p>Consider someone who wants to learn to play the piano. The heteronomous approach would be to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Wait for the &ldquo;perfect&rdquo; time to start</li>
<li>Compare themselves constantly to others</li>
<li>Quit at the first sign of difficulty</li>
<li>Seek external validation for progress</li>
</ul>
<p>The autonomous approach would be to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Begin immediately with whatever resources are available</li>
<li>Set personal standards based on one&rsquo;s own progression</li>
<li>See obstacles as opportunities to develop antifragility</li>
<li>Find intrinsic satisfaction in the learning process itself</li>
</ul>
<p>In this way, it&rsquo;s as if <strong>you&rsquo;re pulling out a clone from another dimension who will do the bidding of your true self.</strong></p>
<h3 id="the-fractal-nature-of-choice">The Fractal Nature of Choice</h3>
<p>Mathematically, every choice you make creates a fractal, a constant recursive function that generates possibilities. All you require is the ability to see those possibilities unfolding in parallel, and to act on the one that most resembles your desired identity.</p>
<p>For example, consider a simple decision like whether to wake up early. This single choice branches into numerous possible days:</p>
<ul>
<li>Early rise → Exercise → Productive morning → Momentum for the day → Better sleep that night → Easier to rise early tomorrow</li>
<li>Sleep in → Rush → Skip breakfast → Low energy → Poor focus → Work extends into evening → Sleep disrupted → Harder to rise early tomorrow</li>
</ul>
<p>Each decision point represents a branch in the fractal of your life. The autonomous person sees these branches and chooses consciously.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FlZj5nkaYAEv9YC.jpg" alt="Fractals of Choice" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: var(--highlight-color); margin-top: 0.5em; text-align: center;">The fractal nature of choices: each decision branches into infinite possibilities. Image credit: Twitter</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This is how you develop autonomy.</p>
<h2 id="on-contrarianism-and-autonomy-finding-signal-in-the-noise">On Contrarianism and Autonomy: Finding Signal in the Noise</h2>
<p>The autonomous individual sees the signal from the noise, not from foresight, but from experimentation and carrying hypotheses to fruition.</p>
<h3 id="the-statistical-minority-of-tinkerers">The Statistical Minority of Tinkerers</h3>
<p>The reason why this works is because NO ONE ELSE DOES THIS. Only a statistical minority in the vast majority of fields are doing the <em>important</em> work of tinkering.</p>
<p>The vast majority of people in a given market are following the propositions and inclinations of the rest of the market, making them blind followers, and mostly cannon fodder whose wealth and time are extracted. Often, this happens with their explicit glee because it <strong>feels like work, but really isn&rsquo;t.</strong> It&rsquo;s work without the asymmetric reward associated with it.</p>
<h3 id="the-speculators-vs-the-doers">The Speculators vs. The Doers</h3>
<p>A minority of these individuals, who are providing the signaling and noise, are <em>armchair speculators</em> who, although voracious in their opinions, have minimal or insignificant stake in the commodity being speculated on. This setup—with sycophants, laymen, and conmen—is what contributes to bubbles, where the potential of the underlying commodity isn&rsquo;t maximized.</p>
<p>So what&rsquo;s the way out? Autonomy.</p>
<h3 id="finding-gold-in-the-profane">Finding Gold in the Profane</h3>
<p>An even smaller group of people ignore the market completely. They&rsquo;re autonomous. They find gold in the profane. To an outsider, this always looks crazy. As pointed out in the section about Steve Jobs, he didn&rsquo;t believe that the masses knew what they wanted; he relied on intrinsic value, which is a signature mark of an autonomous thinker: TINKERING with inner conviction.</p>
<h3 id="practical-examples-of-autonomous-action">Practical Examples of Autonomous Action</h3>
<h4 id="in-technology">In Technology</h4>
<p>Instead of believing things based on what other people say about the latest state-of-the-art open source AI, download it on your local machine (or set up a cloud server) so YOU YOURSELF know the inherent pros and cons, especially for your use case.</p>
<h4 id="in-education">In Education</h4>
<p>Rather than following standard educational paths, the autonomous learner identifies the specific knowledge they need and creates a personalized curriculum—combining formal education, self-teaching, mentorship, and practical application in unique ways.</p>
<p><strong>the premier mark of autonomy is AUTODIDACTISM: the ability to self learn</strong></p>
<p>If a tool or heuristic doesn&rsquo;t meet your needs, if it&rsquo;s not <em>good enough</em>, take the time to build your own.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s never about settling for &ldquo;good enough&rdquo;; it&rsquo;s about setting things up so they&rsquo;re <strong>perfect</strong> for your use case. Over time, as you start to think this way more consistently, you&rsquo;ll find the world bending to your demands, like a timewarp—because you are BUILDING the world of your dreams.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion-beyond-intelligence">Conclusion: Beyond Intelligence</h2>
<p>The core message is simple: Agency—the power to act—matters more than raw intelligence. Why?</p>
<ol>
<li>Intelligence without action changes nothing</li>
<li>Action, even with average intelligence, changes everything</li>
<li>The world rewards those who shape it, not those who merely understand it</li>
</ol>
<p>Your task isn&rsquo;t to become smarter—it&rsquo;s to become more autonomous. To stop waiting for permission. To start acting on your understanding.</p>
<p>The war against heteronomy isn&rsquo;t won through intelligence. It&rsquo;s won through the courage to act.</p>
<p><strong>Autonomy &gt; Intelligence</strong></p>
<hr>
<p><em>This post was inspired by Andrej Karpathy&rsquo;s insights on agency and draws from various philosophical traditions. If you found these ideas valuable, please share/retweet with others who might benefit from them.</em></p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>It&rsquo;s worth noting that Chris made a conscious decision to pursue knowledge over material wealth, and that his choices were not a result of a lack of agency, but rather an exercise of it. Chris has agency over his own life, and has chosen to dedicate it to the pursuit of knowledge, rather than ephemeral material success.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Technofeudalism and the Return to the Real</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/technofeudalism-and-the-return-to-the-real/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 12:34:29 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/technofeudalism-and-the-return-to-the-real/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;What makes the modern manifestation of cloud capital, integral to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://thebeautifultruth.org/the-basics/what-is-technofeudalism/&#34;&gt;Technofeudalism&lt;/a&gt; system we live under, is that it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to go anywhere without having it glaring at you. It hovers above the heads of modern people like a cloud, taking all our attention and carefully curating it, effectively extracting life energy and transmuting it into data and narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Land extensively talks about hyperstition, and the memesis we see via social media enables false narratives to take on a life of their own, often manufactured by the techno-oligarchs themselves in service of their political ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What makes the modern manifestation of cloud capital, integral to the <a href="https://thebeautifultruth.org/the-basics/what-is-technofeudalism/">Technofeudalism</a> system we live under, is that it&rsquo;s impossible to go anywhere without having it glaring at you. It hovers above the heads of modern people like a cloud, taking all our attention and carefully curating it, effectively extracting life energy and transmuting it into data and narrative.</p>
<p>Nick Land extensively talks about hyperstition, and the memesis we see via social media enables false narratives to take on a life of their own, often manufactured by the techno-oligarchs themselves in service of their political ambitions.</p>
<p>In my experience of leaving social media, I go through an almost &ldquo;withdrawal period.&rdquo; That&rsquo;s how satanic the modern system has become. For the first week of leaving Instagram, I felt genuine FOMO, with self-directed copes imagining all the &ldquo;connections&rdquo; I&rsquo;d be losing, all the &ldquo;opportunities&rdquo; I&rsquo;d be missing out on (which is true, but not in the way I&rsquo;d imagine).</p>
<p>Now that I&rsquo;ve been silenced on X, I have naturally found an aversion for the platform, due to its express ability to create self-propelled narratives for the user to confirm their own confirmation biases, as well as the heavy-handedness of Elon Musk on a platform that should ostensibly be &ldquo;free speech&rdquo; based.</p>
<p>Social Media Grazing (as it should be rightly called: you&rsquo;re grazing on information very much like a cow) is a manifestation of a &ldquo;Surrogate Activity&rdquo; for the active principle of social interaction, and it&rsquo;s a very poor substitute for the real thing.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s also evident from a linguistic perspective that there is a very active and pernicious &ldquo;war AGAINST literacy,&rdquo; with the slangification and denigration of language to the point that it&rsquo;s nearly impossible to express deep, profound, and meaningful thoughts that would have occupied the priests of the ancients, and a complete loss of metaphysics and connection to the absolute.</p>
<p>In effect, post-capitalism results in Technofeudalism through the active principle of &ldquo;peasantification&rdquo; of the non-oligarchical class, in all aspects of life: the way you speak, the slop one consumes, the trash one listens to, the filth one speaks.</p>
<h2 id="neo-luddism-and-the-return-to-the-natural-power-process">Neo-Luddism and the Return to the Natural &ldquo;Power Process&rdquo;</h2>
<p>I predict over the next few years, there will be (and already has started to be) an extreme aversion for technological accelerationism, especially on the fringes of the Left and Right wings.</p>
<p>Personally, I used to look at AI with rose-tinted glasses, but recently there has been an enormous level of black-pilling and gas-lighting on the subject, as there has appeared to manifest a partnership between Silicon Valley and Government to &ldquo;rebuild&rdquo; the internet as a massive data farm.</p>
<p>The most recent example of this is the <a href="https://inkstickmedia.com/z-librarys-closure-raises-tough-questions-about-access/">shutdown of Libgen and Zlibrary</a>. Copyright laws and other forms of lawfare have disproportionately targeted the autodidacts (who were the original beneficiaries of the early internet, through unprecedented and life-changing access to high-quality information), yet in service of the oligarch.</p>
<p>Recently, Meta was found to have trained their Large Language Model (LLama) on the entirety of LibGen, one of the most popular shadow libraries in the world, which allowed MILLIONS, who otherwise wouldn&rsquo;t have access to information, with the opportunity to learn. Meta largely got away with it, with barely a slap on the wrist, while <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/new-documents-unredacted-meta-copyright-ai-lawsuit/">the platform itself has been eaten up by courts, and finally banned</a>.</p>
<p>This is just a case in point, but it reflects a broader theme of spiritual decline of the internet as an institution, a grotesque morphing into a massive data farm for our future AI overlords to feast on and then start dictating policy (I will probably write a post on AI censorship in the future).</p>
<h2 id="the-apollonian-ai-the-dionysian-human">The Apollonian AI, the Dionysian Human</h2>
<p>But back to my point, the mass-churning out of content only elicits the desire for the experience of that which is truly authentic: authentic friendship, real love, true intellectual novelty that&rsquo;s only attributed to art, myth, story, and the like.</p>
<p>The current drawback when it comes to the modern Neural Network architecture that powers all the AI models that seem to come out every week and encroach more and more on our lives and livelihoods is the &ldquo;uniformization&rdquo; and &ldquo;fake perfection&rdquo; that is often the output of the model.</p>
<p>Human beings aren&rsquo;t perfect; they&rsquo;re prone to errors, and that&rsquo;s the beauty of human beings. Our imperfection and our awareness of our inadequacy is the root of ALL artistic wonder. Even the greatest magnum opus has slight imperfections, and that&rsquo;s what makes them unique.</p>
<p>Neural Networks operate through the analytical, Hebbian manifestation of thinking, with definite and continuous cause and effect, distributed through layers of abstraction through thousands of artificial neurons. Symptomatic of the scientific materialist paradigm that permeates the research related to the field, AI does not FIT ideas such as intuition, but rather trial and error until it can fit an &ldquo;ideal&rdquo; to the best of its ability.</p>
<p>The Dionysian mental paradigm is rather one of entirely abstract, inexplicable revelation, the mechanism of which is uncertain and immaterial (although I suspect it has something to do with &ldquo;vril,&rdquo; &ldquo;chi,&rdquo; &ldquo;prana&rdquo; energy that the ancients were obsessed with). The Dionysian mental paradigm is channeling the unconscious and the collective unconscious, the realm of the archetypes, that is uniquely human. The experience is FELT, not DESCRIBED.</p>
<p>Teaching AI to come up with novel and transcendental experiences is akin to trying to teach an alien to understand abstractions such as the felt experience of love, or the feeling of a sunset on one&rsquo;s skin, or the vividness of a dream. As such, even though AI art and prose, poetry may increasingly appear to be &ldquo;realistic,&rdquo; they&rsquo;ll always appear slightly eerie or &ldquo;off&rdquo; to the human observer, as they lack the &ldquo;soul&rdquo; that is uniquely human.</p>
<h2 id="the-return-to-the-natural-power-process">The Return to the Natural &ldquo;Power Process&rdquo;</h2>
<p>The natural &ldquo;power process&rdquo; is a concept that was coined by Ted Kaczynski in his manifesto, <a href="https://theanarchistlibrary.org/library/ted-kaczynski-industrial-society-and-its-future">Industrial Society and its Future</a>, which is the idea that human beings have a natural desire to be in control of their own lives, to have autonomy and mastery over their own domain.</p>
<p>The modern technological society has stripped the individual of this natural power process and has instead replaced it with a &ldquo;surrogate activity,&rdquo; which is a poor substitute for the real thing. So the question is: in a post-AI future, how does one find an authentic power process in a world that is increasingly dominated by AI and automation?</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s an obvious truth that there would be tremendous social and psychological upheaval when machines encroach on the central identities of a human being, which is their life&rsquo;s work/occupation. I believe in some ways, this will resuscitate an understanding of how fake and superficial many aspects of modern living are, from abstractions and bureaucratizations of the most basic human needs and impulses.</p>
<p>My hope for humanity in a post-AI future is a realization of how fragile and fallacious our institutions are, and how easily they&rsquo;ve been co-opted by artificial bureaucracy, from the level of &ldquo;paper money&rdquo; that is worth more than what&rsquo;s printed on it, to the absolute cog-ification of the human being in the modern workplace.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s easy to become blackpilled on the subject, especially with the systematic brainwashing that&rsquo;s becoming evident day by day on the technofeudal plantations—but I do think there is a natural correction that&rsquo;s imminent, with many people wishing to return to that which is natural and authentic.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Neuroplasticity: How to Manipulate Reality</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/neuroplasticity---how-to-manipulate-reality/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:08:35 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/neuroplasticity---how-to-manipulate-reality/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-remarkable-capacity-for-change-in-the-human-brain&#34;&gt;The Remarkable Capacity for Change in the Human Brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most people go through their entire lives without truly understanding the astonishing potential for change that exists within the human brain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is commonly believed that our capacity for learning diminishes over time, with the assumption that we can only learn effectively during our childhood years. While this may be true for the majority, I argue that by following specific protocols, not only can we sustain learning throughout our lives, but we can also enhance it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-remarkable-capacity-for-change-in-the-human-brain">The Remarkable Capacity for Change in the Human Brain</h2>
<p><em>Most people go through their entire lives without truly understanding the astonishing potential for change that exists within the human brain.</em></p>
<p>It is commonly believed that our capacity for learning diminishes over time, with the assumption that we can only learn effectively during our childhood years. While this may be true for the majority, I argue that by following specific protocols, not only can we sustain learning throughout our lives, but we can also enhance it.</p>
<p>The primary reason why most individuals experience cognitive decline as they age is not due to irreversible neurological degeneration (which is a real phenomenon but can be slowed and even reversed), but rather because they cease to create new mental models.</p>
<p>As we navigate through life, we gradually learn what strategies work and what don&rsquo;t in achieving our goals. Consequently, we naturally develop specific patterns of thinking and behavior, which cause other seemingly less important mental processes to decline.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;neurons that fire together, wire together.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In other words, the more frequently we engage in a particular thought pattern or habit, the more likely it is to occur again in the future when faced with similar stimuli. I propose that it is possible to deliberately cultivate a sense of &ldquo;voluntary addiction&rdquo; to habits and thought patterns we wish to develop.</p>
<p>In this blog post, I aim to explore how we can improve learning and habit formation, introducing a novel protocol that I call &ldquo;mental agency generation.&rdquo;</p>
<h2 id="neuroplasticity-and-learning">Neuroplasticity and Learning</h2>
<p>When we consciously and deliberately engage in a thought pattern through focused effort and external stimuli, the likelihood of that pattern recurring in the future significantly increases.</p>
<p>For instance, let&rsquo;s consider my experience learning Russian. Even though I am only 17 years old and possess a high degree of neuroplasticity, I have discovered that engaging all five senses greatly accelerates the learning process. Here are the senses and strategies I employ:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Visual</em>: I study the Cyrillic alphabet and observe how the letters interact in words.</li>
<li><em>Auditory</em>: While learning, I listen to Russian music or audio accompanied by subtitles, allowing my mind to associate auditory and visual cues.</li>
<li><em>Kinesthetic</em>: I practice writing by copying text from the screen onto paper, reinforcing the visual representation of letters within my motor system.</li>
<li><em>Verbal</em>: I vocalize the exact pronunciation as a native speaker, developing the ability to speak the language fluently.</li>
<li><em>Bonus</em>: Olfactory/Gustatory: This may be more unconventional, but still valuable. Before each study session, I introduce a specific scent or flavor, such as wearing a particular perfume or chewing a specific gum, to stimulate areas of the brain associated with language acquisition.</li>
</ul>
<p>By engaging multiple senses in the learning process, I have noticed a significant improvement in my ability to learn and retain information. This approach can be applied to various areas of learning and habit building, maximizing our brain&rsquo;s remarkable capacity for change and adaptation.</p>
<h2 id="neuroplasticity-and-habit-development">Neuroplasticity and Habit Development</h2>
<p>I hold an extremely strong, almost dogmatic belief that humans have absolute control over our choices (unless you have a mental illness that disallows rationality/damaged prefrontal cortex). I believe even the worst addictions can be cured (not saying it&rsquo;ll be easy, but conscious effort/redirection of cues makes it a distinct possibility). I believe that depression in people with functional dopamine reward networks can be cured. Anxiety, drug addictions, and compulsiveness can be mitigated.</p>
<p>Andrew Tate famously evoked the heretical and discordant phrase &ldquo;<strong>Depression is not real</strong>,&rdquo; which I partially believe. Yes, depression is a chemical imbalance in the brain, but it&rsquo;s possible to regain balance by attempting to manipulate our levels of neurotransmitter presence. If you have anxiety, you&rsquo;d try to find ways to decrease cortisol. In the case of insomnia, you&rsquo;d try to increase serotonin in the hours following dusk. For dopaminergic addictions, you&rsquo;d try to first resensitize the reward circuitry through abstinence, followed by attempting to increase baseline dopamine levels by natural and healthy methods such as achievement, delayed gratification, and loving relationships. In the case of ADHD, you&rsquo;d try to stimulate the increase of acetylcholine for focus and the mediation of adrenaline.</p>
<p>This idea is more psychological than neurological, but you must start to make extremely conscious decisions. You must become a <em>future fortune teller</em>. You do this by gradually increasing your ability to follow through with promises you make to yourself. You agree to fully complete the tasks that you set out to do, without procrastination or deviation. You start small, by making minuscule promises to yourself such as &ldquo;I will fold my clothes the night before wearing them, and I&rsquo;ll make my bed as soon as I wake up.&rdquo; But the more you do this, the easier it becomes. Gradually, it becomes easier to make promises like &ldquo;I will work 10 hours per day on my business and go to the gym 6 days per week.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s a slow process, so take it easy!</p>
<p>Also, it&rsquo;s very important to note that most of our generation has an unhealthy relationship with our neurotransmitters. Every habit we do throughout our day is <em>inextricably attached to a compulsion</em>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;I NEED a caffeine hit before I can start working.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;I CAN&rsquo;T eat food without scrolling TikTok.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Our generation can&rsquo;t idle for a single moment without scrolling on their phone, and sex for many has become an act of &ldquo;<strong>masturbating with another person&rsquo;s body</strong>.&rdquo;</p>
<p>No, this cannot happen if you want to reach the <strong>zenith of human performance</strong>. You must let go of distractions in favor of what you truly want in life, lest what you want becomes the sacrifice.</p>
<h2 id="mental-agency-generation">Mental Agency Generation</h2>
<p>This is a form of thinking that I&rsquo;m proud to have come up with (at least, I assume no one else has come up with it before me, but they probably have). It&rsquo;s possible to create mental models that interrupt and manipulate trains of thoughts. The easiest way to visualize this I&rsquo;ve found is to think of government task forces.</p>
<p>Agencies in the government are given very specific tasks and monitor different systems and institutions in society to carry out specific goals.</p>
<p>For example, in the United States, the Department of Defense deals with warfare, and the IRS deals with tax collection/government revenue.</p>
<p>Similarly, we can mentally imagine &ldquo;agencies&rdquo; within our brains to carry out specific tasks/checklists to improve our lives. There are two steps to this:</p>
<h3 id="thought-monitoring">Thought Monitoring</h3>
<p>The first and most essential step is to <strong>know when and how thoughts originate, and what chain of events led up to them</strong>. The best way to do this is by meditating and journaling. These habits allow you to &ldquo;put your mind on debug mode&rdquo; and consciously figure out if a thought originates in response to a sensation, impulse, desire, or stimulation.</p>
<p>Now, you can classify thoughts and determine which ones you want to retain and which ones to terminate. <strong>Habits occur from chains of thoughts that translate into action</strong>. Therefore, intervening at the thought level makes it much easier to course correct.</p>
<p>Imagine you have a smoking addiction. You would now record every impulse to smoke, either mentally or in your journal. You would ponder the origin of the thought and the different choices you could make. Here, you would realize that you might have the urge due to nicotine withdrawal or stimuli (such as seeing someone else smoking). With this awareness, you visualize the different choices you can make, which are:
a) Smoke
b) Not smoke</p>
<h2 id="thought-intervention">Thought Intervention</h2>
<p>Let&rsquo;s continue with this example. You know you have a smoking addiction, so now you set up a mental agency to stop smoking completely. The aim of this agency is to completely atrophy the neural programming and propensity for smoking. Now, you establish rules on how to deal with your cues. You make it so that whenever you feel the urge to smoke, you would take 30 deep breaths or do 20 pushups. By learning to keep promises to yourself, as discussed earlier, you will eventually train yourself to follow these rules.</p>
<h2 id="thought-analysis">Thought Analysis</h2>
<p>You must be your own scientist. Experiment with multiple stimuli, schedules, and routines, and decide what works. Use the agency to generate a report on what kinds of behaviors led to different trains of thought.</p>
<p>By repeating these steps over a long enough time frame, you will have successfully rewired your mind. Congratulations!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Art of Human Connection: How to become the leader of your tribe</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/the-art-of-human-connection--how-to-make-friends/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 19:49:54 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/the-art-of-human-connection--how-to-make-friends/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;are-you-an-extrovert-or-introvert&#34;&gt;Are you an Extrovert or Introvert?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irrelevant question.
Why? Because all of us need, and deserve, a meaningful social connection, regardless of how we feel like in social situations.
We deserve to not feel awkward around other people, because inevitably we will have to deal with them.
The complex social structure of our society is what truly makes us human.
I have noticed many in the self-improvement community trying to act like this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=sigma%20male&#34;&gt;lone wolf, sigma male character&lt;/a&gt;, thinking that would help you excel in your work and ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="are-you-an-extrovert-or-introvert">Are you an Extrovert or Introvert?</h3>
<p>Irrelevant question.
Why? Because all of us need, and deserve, a meaningful social connection, regardless of how we feel like in social situations.
We deserve to not feel awkward around other people, because inevitably we will have to deal with them.
The complex social structure of our society is what truly makes us human.
I have noticed many in the self-improvement community trying to act like this <a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=sigma%20male">lone wolf, sigma male character</a>, thinking that would help you excel in your work and ambitions.</p>
<p>Most don&rsquo;t realize how truly life changing some beautiful friendships can be. There are people who will be with you through your darkest days, celebrate your wins and never abandon you however fucked up mistakes you may make.</p>
<p>My aim is to meet these kinds of people, and recently I have been thinking really deeply about how do i prime myself to meeting and working with these brothers.</p>
<p>Here are a few base steps/protocols that have helped me find homies with similar interests</p>
<h1 id="step-1-priming">STEP 1: Priming</h1>
<p>We all have to start from somewhere… And if you are anything like me, you were/are a bit awkward.
Social Skills, as obvious as it sounds, is a <strong>skill</strong>, a skill that requires deliberate practice and the discomfort that comes with meeting new people.</p>
<p>There is this notion that you may get smirked at, or have some people think you are weird. However, i assure you that this is not usually the case. Sure, some people may, but you must realize that those are not the people you want to/deserve to surround yourself with. Remember, in this journey we are trying to surround yourself with the top 1%, the best, the most intelligent, the most hardworking people.</p>
<p>Also, it is worth noting that every social encounter you have is some valuable experience. Every new person you meet is <em>one rep for your social-skills muscle</em>. Embrace bad social encounters, since they make you stronger.</p>
<p>Here is a good protocol that seems to work for most people: Talk to one new person every day, with no exceptions.
I have found the most success with this in High School (i&rsquo;m a junior). Academic Institutions are incredible venues for making new friends. If you are in uni or in HS, i encourage you to walk around during recess, talking to new people for practice.</p>
<p>You may say that you are into remote work, or just don&rsquo;t have the opportunity to meet many people.</p>
<p>Take a walk then, meet the old men in the park, talk to the girl walking her dog in the park, compliment the jacked guy who is doing pull-ups on the monkey bars.</p>
<p>Most people love to be approached and complimented. There is not enough friendliness and kindness in today&rsquo;s world. Be the one who makes another human&rsquo;s day a little better.</p>
<p>A RESOURCE: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-Win-Friends-Influence-People/dp/0671027034">How To Win Friends and Influence people</a> is basically the bible of social skills, read it and re-read it until you are ready for the next step</p>
<h1 id="step-2-adding-value">Step 2: Adding Value</h1>
<p>By now, you have talked to a lot of people (lets say, 50.). You have had multiple nice encounters, maybe a few deep conversations, and are generally getting more comfortable around people.</p>
<p>In essence, you have been spending your time <em>approaching</em> new people.</p>
<p>Now, let&rsquo;s learn to get people to like you more.</p>
<p>And there is one, and truly one way to do this.
you have to <strong>add value to people</strong>. This can happen in a lot of ways. A common form of value you have with your current friends/normal friendships would be shared experiences. You and your best friend in school had to sit through years of excruciating math classes together, and that really gave you two the opportunity to get to know each other and bolster a friendship.</p>
<p>You can also add value by having <em>specific knowledge</em>, or skills like charisma/being funny and engaging.</p>
<p>Truly ask yourself, “How can I make this girl day 1% better today?”, could you teach something new and profound? Can you say a joke they will think about for days? Can you truly impress her?</p>
<p>Remember, <strong>if you focus on what other people want, you will be popular for the rest of your life.</strong> If this does not make sense to you… go back to step one 👆🏼, you clearly aren&rsquo;t ready yet.</p>
<p>Who are the type people in your ideal friend group? What kind of value they expect? How will you cater those needs? These are questions you must answer!</p>
<p><strong>Social skills are a skill</strong>. It is NOT meant to be something you would have out of nowhere. Even the most charismatic people got to that point because of practicing social interactions. So get up from your $399 PewDiePie gaming chair, wipe the Doritos off your shirt, and go out into the world brah.</p>
<h1 id="step-3-expansion">Step 3: Expansion</h1>
<p>Now, you have friends, you have value.
But wouldn&rsquo;t it be nice to have more of both 😃 ?
This is the way to go up and beyond, truly cement yourself within the top 1%.
We live in an age of <a href="https://twitter.com/naval/status/877321503896854528?lang=en">Infinite Leverage</a>, With the internet giving people from even the most remote societies in the world access to a global community, and giving groundbreaking knowledge and perspectives. This step will really get you noticed, and social fulfillment you would have never felt before.</p>
<p>Here is what you must do: Start a YouTube channel, blog or podcast. These are the main ways i have found people can spread wisdom online. Microblogging and social media like Instagram and TikTok are okay for this, but you cannot reach the depth required to spread your passion.</p>
<p>One of my reasons for starting this blog was to find like-minded people, to meet friends for life, I know that if I can freely express my ideas online, U will eventually and inevitably meet at-least one person who I am at the same frequency with. Even though this blog only has about 10 readers (for now, love you Gs), my consistency and effort shall surely win me some friends in the long term.</p>
<h1 id="step-4-consolidation">Step 4: Consolidation</h1>
<p>Congrats! You found them! You found the homies :), you found the people who would be with you in your wins, and at your loses. You found the people who wouldn&rsquo;t want anything from you except your own growth. Now what?
You are the top. You are hanging out with Adonis, Maximus and Ares. These type of people are invested into growth, and don&rsquo;t drink, smoke, jack off or indulge in instant gratification. Organize events and meetups semi-regularly so that you maintain the bond you worked so hard on, and continue growing.</p>
<p>PS: i have ripped off parts of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lSKxhR-YDMI">Hamza&rsquo;s video</a> on the topic, so go check it out if you have read so far, he really goes deep into this shit and hits your feels</p>
<p>good luck,soldier</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Doing What You Got to Do: A Systematic Pathway to Success</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/doing-what-you-got-to-do--a-systematic-pathway-to-success/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 11:01:26 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/doing-what-you-got-to-do--a-systematic-pathway-to-success/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-is-something-extremely-important-that-i-have-learned-over-the-last-few-months&#34;&gt;There is something extremely important that I have learned over the last few months.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one has gotten into their self-improvement journey, they will eventually realize one thing: you would have to &lt;strong&gt;do the hard work, ESPECIALLY when you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it&lt;/strong&gt;.
There is great power in getting something hard or boring to become a routine habit just by doing it repeatedly. Imagine going to the gym in the morning without a single word of protest every day. Or… studying for 6 hours with no feelings of resentment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="there-is-something-extremely-important-that-i-have-learned-over-the-last-few-months">There is something extremely important that I have learned over the last few months.</h3>
<p>If one has gotten into their self-improvement journey, they will eventually realize one thing: you would have to <strong>do the hard work, ESPECIALLY when you don&rsquo;t feel like it</strong>.
There is great power in getting something hard or boring to become a routine habit just by doing it repeatedly. Imagine going to the gym in the morning without a single word of protest every day. Or… studying for 6 hours with no feelings of resentment.</p>
<p>Such can be done by fighting something called ** Limbic Friction**</p>
<h4 id="uh-what-is-limbic-friction">Uh… What is “limbic friction”?</h4>
<p>Limbic friction could be described as a sort of mental barrier, lack of motivation or focus. The great neuroscientist <a href="https://hubermanlab.com">Dr. Andrew Huberman. PHD </a> coined this term to describe what exactly goes through your mind when you decide to watch one more YouTube video instead of going and studying trigonometry.</p>
<p>Now… How is it that we can overcome this? How do awesome personalities like <a href="https://davidgoggins.com">David Goggins</a>, who most people think of as the epitome of grit and discipline, do the hard work when they don&rsquo;t feel like it?</p>
<p>To quote <a href="https://www.tinkeredthinking.com/index.php?id=978">tinkered thinking</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The interesting thing about friction in the real world is that the more that friction is engaged over time, the less that friction becomes… Stone steps wear smooth after enough treading feet.  An old piece of clothing becomes soft from use.  River stones grow smooth and round.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>WE GET MORE DISCIPLINED AT SOMETHING BY DOING THAT THING AGAIN AND AGAIN AND AGAIN AND AGAIN AND AGAIN.</strong></p>
<p>We must understand that motivation and discipline come OUT of your work, and is not actually required to do the work itself</p>
<p>You get more motivated by finding yourself doing the 100 pull up, not just thinking about starting.</p>
<p>For example, Today, i really didn&rsquo;t feel like writing this blog post. I have plenty of reasons in my head such that I have my finals in a couple of days, that I am such a shit writer, that no one would care to read my work… But I fought through it
I fought the mental battle, allotted some time to get this all written down.</p>
<p>So yeah, if you want to get disciplined, prepare yourself to fight, and conquer your mental battles. My tips would be to improve your mental health, and (I know this quote is getting repetitive, but it&rsquo;s extremely important to internalize)</p>
<p><strong>DO THE HARD WORK, ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU DON&rsquo;T FEEL LIKE IT</strong></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Learning From Media vs Learning From Experience: Which Is Better?</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/mediavsexperience/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 17:23:57 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/mediavsexperience/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;times-have-changed&#34;&gt;Times have changed.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the man who can adapt the fastest and handle the most information is the man who wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shift in focus of the economy from physical labor to &lt;em&gt;intellectual&lt;/em&gt; labor has created an industry around learning, in contrast to education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This industry is what I like to call, the &lt;strong&gt;absorb and learn&lt;/strong&gt; niche, which serves information through media like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watchable courses (YouTube, udemy, skillshare and the plethora of other course providers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pamphlets and books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;certifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these options, makes it more difficult to choose a medium and stick with it. Personally,i find myself searching on sites rather than actually doing some deliberate practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="times-have-changed">Times have changed.</h2>
<p>Today, the man who can adapt the fastest and handle the most information is the man who wins.</p>
<p>This shift in focus of the economy from physical labor to <em>intellectual</em> labor has created an industry around learning, in contrast to education.</p>
<p>This industry is what I like to call, the <strong>absorb and learn</strong> niche, which serves information through media like:</p>
<ul>
<li>watchable courses (YouTube, udemy, skillshare and the plethora of other course providers)</li>
<li>pamphlets and books</li>
<li>certifications</li>
</ul>
<p>All these options, makes it more difficult to choose a medium and stick with it. Personally,i find myself searching on sites rather than actually doing some deliberate practice.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s take programming, for example. When you start learning a new programming language, would you rather watch 4 hours worth of course material by a top university, or spend the same 4 hours messing about on your own.</p>
<p>The answer is complicated.</p>
<h3 id="okay-so-what-is-the-real-answer">Okay&hellip; so, what is the real answer?</h3>
<p>There is this neat idea floating around the internet called the <em>Pareto principle</em>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>80% of consequences come from 20% of the causes</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>We have so much material today online, and i have personally found that only a fraction (around 20%) of it actually helped me learn a new skill.
Therefore, it would be very useful to have a sort of model in which you moderate the amount of content you consume, and increase how much content you produce/ act upon.</p>
<p>You don&rsquo;t become a great boxer by only reading 300 books about thrusts. You <em>do</em> become at least a good enough boxer if you participate in 300 matches where you apply the ideas of a select few books and material.</p>
<p>This works the same way with exam material. A lot of my peers scramble to buy new and trendy workbooks to prepare for upcoming competitive exams. However, previous results show that the toppers of these exams themselves only used some very high quality, reputed textbooks and did not care to distract themselves by the tide waves of new information.</p>
<p>Therefore, a factional advice would be to <em>Learn 20% of the time, work 80% of the remaining time</em>. Try to do a bit of research about a new skill you are learning, but in the remaining time truly work on it with principles like spaced reputation, and deliberate practice.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Passive learning creates knowledge. Active practice creates skill.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Internet:Advantages and Disadvantages</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/the-internet---advantages-and-disadvantages/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 18:53:12 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/the-internet---advantages-and-disadvantages/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello dear reader! This is a college essay i wrote a couple of weeks ago for a school project, I thought why not upload it on my blog, since i havent done that in so long lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, dont take this as an actual post, more of a filler that you may or may not want to read :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-advantages-and-disadvantages-of-the-internet-college-essay&#34;&gt;The Advantages and disadvantages of the internet: college essay&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For better or for worse,
The internet has become a ubiquitous tool in our modern-day existence.
It has become a means of propagating communication,scholarly research, Ideas.
The internet is a repository containing all of known human history.
It is a place to turn to when you want to find unique solutions.
However, Not everything is sunshine and rainbows in the interwebs. There are serious concerns that will have to be addressed for what we call the internet a constructive,free and complimentary platform&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="foreword">Foreword</h2>
<p>Hello dear reader! This is a college essay i wrote a couple of weeks ago for a school project, I thought why not upload it on my blog, since i havent done that in so long lol.</p>
<p>Well, dont take this as an actual post, more of a filler that you may or may not want to read :D</p>
<h1 id="the-advantages-and-disadvantages-of-the-internet-college-essay">The Advantages and disadvantages of the internet: college essay</h1>
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>For better or for worse,
The internet has become a ubiquitous tool in our modern-day existence.
It has become a means of propagating communication,scholarly research, Ideas.
The internet is a repository containing all of known human history.
It is a place to turn to when you want to find unique solutions.
However, Not everything is sunshine and rainbows in the interwebs. There are serious concerns that will have to be addressed for what we call the internet a constructive,free and complimentary platform</p>
<h2 id="advantages">Advantages</h2>
<ul>
<li>The internet is an unprecedented center of learning. No matter where you are in the world, you can find always value in the analogous global Library. Platforms like Khan Academy and YouTube help provide world class education, especially in third world nations like India in which accessible education is something of  dire need</li>
<li>The internet,and by extension social media, help connect people together. Families split apart by circumstance have the opportunity to communicate with each other using platforms like WhatsApp, Instagram and Facebook. It also helps to bring together people of different backgrounds and ideologies together and facilitates meaningful discussion</li>
<li>The internet has helped prop up multiple new industries, such as E-commerce,E-learning,consulting and digital infrastructure .The Indian internet industry is going to be <strong>worth $160 billion by 2025</strong>, which is a great boon to our young economy.</li>
<li>The Internet has become a means to entertainment. Reddit and Instagram provide funny memes that make people laugh, Netflix and Hulu distributes interesting films and series. These are a lot more accessible to the regular netizen than real-life means of keeping oneself engaged</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="disadvantages">Disadvantages</h2>
<ul>
<li>The internet can be a pit for addiction. The dopaminergic effect that certain parts of the internet that certain parts of the internet are so unnatural and significant that they cause severe mental health problems, especially in younger people. Social media has created a culture which promotes narcissism and selfishness. Pornography has manipulated the need to reproduce into a severe addiction. online video games have caused millions of young people to waste away their youth in a repetitive fashion of obsessive consumption</li>
<li>The internet can be used as a platform to scam, deceive, steal and infect. Cybercrime will <strong>Cost The World $10.5 Trillion Annually By 2025</strong>, largely due to the lack of security/privacy on internet platforms.</li>
<li>The internet has enabled crimes like cyber-bullying,trolling and  harassment to become virtually synonymous with the idea of the internet because of the &ldquo;anonymity&rdquo; that the internet provides</li>
<li>The internet and social media platforms create &ldquo;Echo Chambers&rdquo; which keep repeating ideas that can be largely manipulated by groups of people or organizations. This has caused the disturbing phenomenon of &ldquo;Fake news&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>In conclusion, i opine that without the internet, it would be fair to say that the path of humanity may have gone down a very different path.
The advantages may outweigh the disadvantages in case you know how to use the internet productively.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>How to Pick a Programming Language</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-pick-a-programming-language/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:33:41 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-pick-a-programming-language/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-really-is-a-beautiful-thing&#34;&gt;Software really is a beautiful thing.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often take the magical applications we use every single day for granted. Chances are that if you are reading this, you are curious on how to make your own, but you find the dozens of languages and frameworks intimidating.
I hope to guide you through the SE world through this blog post, and clear up the misconceptions one may have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I for one, have struggled to know what kind of developer I wanted to be when I first got exposed to the idea of writing code as a hobby. There are so many avenues and specializations one can take. I always pictured a branched tree or void-black tunnels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="software-really-is-a-beautiful-thing">Software really is a beautiful thing.</h2>
<p>We often take the magical applications we use every single day for granted. Chances are that if you are reading this, you are curious on how to make your own, but you find the dozens of languages and frameworks intimidating.
I hope to guide you through the SE world through this blog post, and clear up the misconceptions one may have.</p>
<p>I for one, have struggled to know what kind of developer I wanted to be when I first got exposed to the idea of writing code as a hobby. There are so many avenues and specializations one can take. I always pictured a branched tree or void-black tunnels.</p>
<p>One can delve into the colorful branches of web/app developments, where you work with languages focused on delivering a good user experience.</p>
<p>Or the nitty-gritty leaves of Hardware API and OS development, where you would be expected to write code that will be deeply integrated with the idea of how the machine itself works.</p>
<p>Or just general scripting, where you could exert maximum control and efficiency over computers.</p>
<p>There are 4 types of people i meet, who express interest in learning how to code.</p>
<h3 id="i-just-want-to-learn-to-code-as-something-i-can-just-put-my-time-in-bruv">“I just want to learn to code, as something I can just put my time in bruv”</h3>
<p>you have come to the right place! There are plenty of good programming languages that you can learn that will look good on a resume, and not too difficult at the same time.</p>
<p>The general advice would be to learn the python language. It is super easy (I am not exaggerating, it is almost like plain English!). It has an amazing community with super friendly and active devs, very versatile, and you can use it to do 90% of tasks on a computer.</p>
<p>Action tasks:</p>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> do your own research about the python language</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> watch some YouTube courses on it (any will do, most are excellent!)</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> code a small project (a simple calculator is a great first task)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="i-love-video-games-how-do-i-make-my-own">“I love video games, how do I make my own?”</h3>
<p>Gaming is a lovely bridge way to learning how to code, and it is actually one of the more fun parts of the ecosystem! Making a video game is a childhood dream of many, yet to be accomplished.</p>
<p>The best place would start would be in a game engine like Unity, Unreal Engine, Godot or Snowdrop. The tools don&rsquo;t matter as much in this domain, rather your skills and how you think of objects in space ✨</p>
<p>It would be nice to know a bit of physics or math (don&rsquo;t let that throw you off! It&rsquo;s pretty basic), along with learning the language of your engine (I found the more important ones to be C#, C++ and Lua)</p>
<p>All you have to do is a lot, and I mean a lot of tinkering.
Everything is a lot more visual, so chances are, if you are a beginner you would enjoy it much more.</p>
<p>action tasks:</p>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> download some game engine Software</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> learn to write basic code in your Language</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> make a simple block game where you get more points the higher you jump</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> (advanced) make a simple 2d platformer game</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="websites-are-cool-but-googling-web-development-languages-makes-me-want-to-pull-my-eyes-out">“Websites are cool… But googling &lsquo;web development languages&rsquo; makes me want to pull my eyes out”</h3>
<p>Here is the simplest advice I could possibly offer. <strong>Know the basics, and know them well.</strong> It would be much more fruitful to know how to interact with webpages/apps very well, rather than knowing 30 different frameworks at a surface level.</p>
<p>If you are just starting out, it would be a good idea to acquaint yourself with the holy trinity of web dev, which are HTML, CSS and JS</p>
<p>HTML — The markdown, skeletonof the webpage.I It isn&rsquo;t really code,, butmore of how the webpage interprets how it should look like
CSS — mainly design oriented instructions that will be applied on to the webpage
JS — the language that gives the webpage life, very versatile and is often called the “brains” of a website.</p>
<p>action tasks:</p>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> learn the basics of web development</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> create a small portfolio website, put whatever you want in it (you can send me screenshots over on my discord 🙂 )</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="i-want-to-learn-to-use-my-computer-to-its-maximum-potential-with-a-broad-perspective-of-most-languages">“I want to learn to use my computer to its maximum potential, with a broad perspective of most languages”</h3>
<p>I absolutely love to hear this, literal music to my ears!
Congrats, you have the mindset to become a software enthusiast! Welcome to the club.
This path will be more chaotic than the others that I have just mentioned, with a lot of twists and turns… But do not dismay. You will learn quite a broad scope and have a lot of fun epiphanies along the way!</p>
<p>The best thing to start of with is a fairly simple language, that gives you a solid foundation on how computers really work. Great picks are C++, Java and C to some extent.
If you get really solid in one of the above-mentioned languages, you will find yourself having a broad foundation on integral concepts and paradigms in the software community
Namely, OOP and the objects plays a huge role in our modern ecosystem.</p>
<p>Once you have got some kind of grip, create a lot of projects and expand to multiple languages and concepts!
I consider myself language fluid, and strive to be able to write decent code in any high functioning language.
You could set a similar goal and consume a tonne of information that gives you a wider and more practical knowledge.</p>
<p>Action tasks:</p>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Learn the basics of a Language</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Write some code and show it to a community/individual (my discord DMs is perpetually open)</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Learn to automate a task on your computer that you find annoying</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Learn more about how a computers memory works</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Mental Drain of Studying and How to Deal With It</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/the-mental-drain-of-studying-and-how-to-deal-with-it/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 18:45:50 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/the-mental-drain-of-studying-and-how-to-deal-with-it/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-mental-drain-of-studying&#34;&gt;The mental drain of Studying&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of us approach studying as a chore just because our parents, teachers and society in general expects us to do well in our academics. The academic journey can be rather inundating and boring. The very thought of studying and examinations can cause a lot of distress for students(at least I can speak for myself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-can-be-studying-so-difficult&#34;&gt;Why can be studying so difficult&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;studying may not be the most appealing thing in the world. Sitting for multiple hours looking at static books is not exactly what our survivalist brains were made for. There are a myriad of reasons why we may find studying undesirable, some of them being:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="the-mental-drain-of-studying">The mental drain of Studying</h3>
<p>A lot of us approach studying as a chore just because our parents, teachers and society in general expects us to do well in our academics. The academic journey can be rather inundating and boring. The very thought of studying and examinations can cause a lot of distress for students(at least I can speak for myself).</p>
<h3 id="why-can-be-studying-so-difficult">Why can be studying so difficult</h3>
<p>studying may not be the most appealing thing in the world. Sitting for multiple hours looking at static books is not exactly what our survivalist brains were made for. There are a myriad of reasons why we may find studying undesirable, some of them being:</p>
<h4 id="delayed-gratification-as-against-instant-gratification">Delayed gratification as against Instant gratification</h4>
<p>Apparently we all have an inner, pesky reptilian mind. The metaphorical term the internet likes to call it is something called the <strong>lizard brain.</strong> Our lizard brain likes to live in the present and loves to have instant results.
Studies for one, that too in our education system will never yield instant results. Often deadlines (<em>final exams, graduations,Entrance exams</em>) are years or months in the future. Unless you think rationally, it is likely that our lizard brain will try to convince us that there is no point in learning seemingly useless materials.</p>
<hr>
<p>
  <img src="/images/lizard_brain.png" alt="lizard brain">
</p>
<hr>
<h4 id="previously-unsatisfactory-results">Previously unsatisfactory results</h4>
<p>If you have never gotten good grades before (like me), trying to score straight A&rsquo;s may seem unattainable. The mind does reject the chance we can ever achieve it, so why even try is? is what the inner voice keeps taunting.</p>
<h4 id="peer-pressure">Peer pressure</h4>
<p>People (mostly Asians I think) have this culture of comparison. You may be compared to friend, family member or a successful person often. This may cause us to become more demotivated and associate getting good grades with people who you think are smarter than you, not yourself.</p>
<h4 id="competition-and-vast-syllabus">Competition and vast syllabus</h4>
<p>The world has become a lot more competitive with better access to education. People flock in hundreds of thousands to attempt to get into elite colleges and universities.</p>
<p>For instance, In the year 2023, I will be attempting the Indian JEE exam, one of the most difficult and rigorous engineering exam in the world. The motivation behind this tag is to get access to the best universities, to be a part of an elite circle of the smartest peers and then get a fat paycheck. But, such a difficult entrance exam often ends up crashing our dreams and demotivating so many of us.</p>
<h4 id="so-is-studying-worth-it">So, Is Studying worth it?</h4>
<p>I for one, have been a chronic procrastinator. For this reason, I have almost never appreciated the art (yes, its an art) of studying with the intention to learn. There are quite a few reasons that I have found that may associate studying with <em>learning</em> rather than it just being another plain task. The Studying process can be fulfilling if we understand the Why (the reason) instead of getting muddled with the How. These reasons perhaps can lead to the motivation that we need to go through the grind.</p>
<h4 id="builds-a-solid-foundation">Builds a solid foundation</h4>
<p>There is so much learning we can acquire out of the act of studying. It enhances our ability to absorb information and learn about multiple subjects. It is said that Knowledge and Information is power, and this journey will equip us with a deep understanding of what we are trying to learn.</p>
<h4 id="develops-a-growth-mindset">Develops a growth mindset</h4>
<p>The knowledge that we gain enables us to develop a growth mindset. The journey in academia requires constant improvement over a lifetime. It builds discipline, team work, and competitiveness, which further can be utilized in various other endeavors that we undertake in our lifetimes.</p>
<h4 id="leads-to-a-safe-secure-career">Leads to a safe, secure career</h4>
<p>study well, get a safe secure job is the reason we hear the most from society and parents, it is pretty blue-pilled  and may sound like a cliché. However, It does have a bit of truth. It is a fact that 90% of wealth goes to the top 3 -5 % of people. Not necessarily that excelling in academics will allow us to become those few elite people, but at least becoming the top few % in studies will open up pathways in our future careers and thereby giving us a head start.</p>
<p><strong>But it ain&rsquo;t easy</strong>
The competition in the academic field is extremely fierce. To get into top universities you would be competing against some of the smartest people in your country, or even the world!
If you do manage to crack any of these competitive exams and get into the universities of your choice, we will have a chance to be surrounded by like-minded, smart people. They say you become the average of the 10 people you spend time with, so surrounding with the smartest will up our averages.</p>
<h4 id="so-how-to-study-well-and-hope-to-get-into-the-toppers-league">So, How to Study well and hope to get into the Toppers league?</h4>
<p>What I have understood listening to these various success stories is that Humans are creatures of enormous potential, and our brains have the unique quality of being able to adapt much quicker to new situations.</p>
<p>In order to actually score good, we must not work in hopes to please another person. Good, self-motivated studying is the only way to study without it feeling meaningless, and unfulfilling.</p>
<p>The top rankers do not think of the syllabus as one gargantuan task, but rather hundreds of smaller, more manageable concepts that they can master.</p>
<p>At the end, it will all add up. All we have to do is keep improving every single day.</p>
<p>Fret not, my dear fellow average students, as there always seems to be hope. What I am beginning to understand is that we don&rsquo;t have to be the sharpest tool in the shed, Consistancy and putting the work in will easily get you to the top, no matter how average you may have previously preformed. You must understand that the competition are not meant to belittle you, but rather to refine you and make you a more seasoned person who can handle the stress.</p>
<h4 id="the-success-equation">The Success Equation</h4>
<p>Until high school, being at the top of the class could be possible by chance. One may not study as hard, and get good grades by using their natural talents/abilities.</p>
<p>However, the more we advance into education, everything becomes a lot more competitive. Although luck and talent still plays a role, <strong>consistent work trumps everything else.</strong>
There is a beautiful equation from the book <a href="https://www.amazon.in/Unfair-Advantage-Startup-Success-Starts-ebook/dp/B07ND3V1ZS">The Unfair Advantage</a> that demonstrates my point.</p>
<p>$$\ Success = fair \ play \times Unfair \ Advantage $$</p>
<p>Your unfair advantage is something that are unique to you, and can help you get to your goals from square one,
be it financial support, technical education, life skills etc.
It is what separates you from every one else.</p>
<p>Fair play here would be any difficult work that requires you to be persistent, and tangibly brings you closer to your goals</p>
<p>You have a lot more control on the “fair play” aspect of the equation in comparison to your unfair advantages (you definitely already have some)</p>
<p>You can make your fair play variable bigger by</p>
<ul>
<li>working <strong>smarter</strong> and more <strong>rigorously</strong> than everyone else</li>
<li><em>being consistent</em></li>
<li><em>understanding</em>:always following up after classes, taking notes, visuallizing concepts etc.</li>
<li><em>Having ambition</em> (thinking about how all this learning will help you in life)</li>
<li><em>work-life balance</em> : in long study marathons with an end goal in mind (for example, an entrance exam at a university) burning out is highly undesirable. You must be able to balance your diet, exercise, sleep, hobbies (in my opinion, hobbies are highly underrepresented in traditional media) and social life in order to make the best of your time.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="the-flow-state">The Flow State</h4>
<p>Ever wonder how the smart dude/gal in your class is able to sit and absorb a lot of material for hours on end?
It&rsquo;s simple (but not always easy!). They “get in the zone”. To put it simply, being in the flow state causes you to lose all sense of self, with all your focus being on the thing you are now doing.
Think of a painter who is completely absorbed in his art. He could go hours painting, even missing sleep, food etc.</p>
<p>To understand this concept better, you could watch <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/mihaly_csikszentmihalyi_flow_the_secret_to_happiness?language=en">the TED talk</a></p>
<hr>
<p>
  <figure>
    <img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f6/Challenge_vs_skill.svg/300px-Challenge_vs_skill.svg.png" alt="the flow state">
    <figcaption>A Graph slowing possible mental states experienced during work</figcaption>
  </figure>
</p>
<hr>
<p>How do we apply this in learning? Here are a few steps to make getting into the flow state a habit:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Have a fixed environment for studying. I cannot express how important this is. You must sit at a single desk every single day. Eventually, the moment you sit on your study chair you will get into a state of intense focus (truly magical I tell you)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Having a set time for studying, doesn&rsquo;t really matter if it&rsquo;s in the morning or night, you just have to show up every single day</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Making it so that the material that you are solving is hard, but not so hard that it demotivates you</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Put away your flipping phone away. The thing can suck so much time that you will not even notice your precious hours flowing by. Turn off all notifications. Preferably, you could chuck your phone in another room.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Having fun. This may sound really weird, but when you purposefully try to get more interested in your subject (questioning and being curious about everything), you find that your mind starts buzzing, and the flow gives you real satisfaction, which is really important in study marathons.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="hard-work-vs-deep-work">Hard Work vs Deep Work</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Hard Work</th>
          <th>Deep Work</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>Force imbibing concepts(reading the same paragraph repeatedly without testing yourself,memorization without understanding the core meaning)</td>
          <td>spending time understanding your material,and not bruteforcing your way through concepts. Spending some time really visualizing how the idea works</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>Prioritizing time over the flow state</td>
          <td>makes the time you spend valuable by getting into a conceptual flow state</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>Does not really promote learning</td>
          <td>the most scientific way to study,Gives you a more all-rounded understanding of your subject</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Eating Clean: How to Maintain a Guilt Free Calorie Defict</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/eating-clean--how-to-maintain-a-guilt-free-calorie-defict/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 20:31:06 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/eating-clean--how-to-maintain-a-guilt-free-calorie-defict/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-eat-cleaner&#34;&gt;Why eat cleaner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed it, our foods have gotten more &lt;strong&gt;processed and less nutritious&lt;/strong&gt; in the last hundred years.
Nutrition has commercially lost all value.
Companies now tend to prioritize easily consumable and producible foods. But have you ever considered how this may be impacting your health?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dangers-of-highly-processed-foods&#34;&gt;The dangers of highly processed foods&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;heavily processed foods often interfere with natural macro levels. They tend to not have necessary vitamins and fibers, and are filled with excess fats, sugars and sodium.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="why-eat-cleaner">Why eat cleaner</h3>
<p>You may have noticed it, our foods have gotten more <strong>processed and less nutritious</strong> in the last hundred years.
Nutrition has commercially lost all value.
Companies now tend to prioritize easily consumable and producible foods. But have you ever considered how this may be impacting your health?</p>
<h3 id="the-dangers-of-highly-processed-foods">The dangers of highly processed foods</h3>
<p>heavily processed foods often interfere with natural macro levels. They tend to not have necessary vitamins and fibers, and are filled with excess fats, sugars and sodium.</p>
<p>You would also be at a higher risk to diseases like diabetes and cancer.</p>
<p>They are also very addicting, causing you to overeat, increasing the aforementioned risk</p>
<p>To put this all into perspective, me and a couple of friends got into a discord call to actually find out the side effects of the ingredients commonly found on labels</p>
<p>for a single packet of 150g bag of Doritos, these are the possible side effects of the ingredients that are listed</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>Skin Irratation
Asthma
Cramping
Flatulence
Nauseax3
Vomitingx2
Diarrheax2
Gasx2
Stomach pain
Pills in your poop
Pale skin
Weight loss
Attention deficit disordersx2
Lethargy
Sleepiness
Numbness
Paralysisx2
Seizuresx2
Sciaticax2
Slurred Speechx2
Chills and shakesx2
Shudderingx2
Dry skin
Dehydration
Shortness of breath
</code></pre><p>Pretty scary, huh?</p>
<h3 id="diets">Diets?</h3>
<p>Diets have seemingly become the new trend. There are more than I can possibly name. There is the:</p>
<ul>
<li>paleo diet, where you just eat completely unprocessed food</li>
<li>keto diet, cutting out carbs completely</li>
<li>vegan diet, where you consume no animal products.</li>
</ul>
<p>I am not here to preach any specific kind of diet (especially since I&rsquo;m not qualified). However, the approach that I have found appears to work the best.</p>
<p>The basis of most of how your body processes the arbitrary number known as “calories”, comes to this
$$ calories \ in = calories \ out $$
as long as you control how much you consume every day, you can actually lose a lot of fat/weight
this is called <em>being in a deficit.</em> However, you must not overdo it. Track how much you eat and make sure that you are eating slightly less than what you burn every single day.</p>
<h3 id="why-the-scale-can-lie-to-you">Why the scale can lie to you</h3>
<p>Often, most media sources state that losing weight is one&rsquo;s main goal. However, most of the time, its more important to burn fat. When you are overweight or obese, and you suddenly start cutting down, you may notice that your weight is going down. This is because your body is consuming stored fat.</p>
<p>That being said, there are cases in which you may notice a significant decrease in fat, but not in weight. You must not be dismayed if this is the case for you (it was for me). If you work out regularly, it could be because your body is burning fat, and making your muscles stronger.
Therefore, even though your fat % is actually decreasing, the weighing scale may show that you are not losing any weight as such.</p>
<h3 id="setting-a-reasonable-goal">Setting a reasonable goal</h3>
<p>A lot of people I have talked to, who plan to become lean often say the following things</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I&rsquo;m going to the gym and lift x kg of weight every day, and not eat anything but chicken breasts!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I will focus just on working out, and eat my regular foods</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I used to think like this, but realized it can be severely unsustainable. Making your perfect body requires <em>willpower</em> and <em>consistency</em>.
The best way to start losing fat is to eliminate bad eating habits, such as sporadically consuming calorically dense foods (as stated before).</p>
<h3 id="how-to-stop-cravings">How to stop cravings</h3>
<p>This question is the most important to me personally. Doing everything above wouldn&rsquo;t do you much good if you eat like trash.</p>
<p>One of the biggest challenges was the craving I had whenever I saw foods with a lot of sugar and fat.</p>
<p>Therefore, what I did was <strong>eliminate snacks from my home completely.</strong> This may sound a bit extreme, but it has definitely helped with my snacking problem.</p>
<p>I also kept reminding myself that by not eating that snack right now (instant gratification), my future self would benefit by having a leaner and healthier body (delayed gratification)</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Practice of Journaling in Self-Improvement</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/the-practice-of-journaling-in-self-improvement/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/the-practice-of-journaling-in-self-improvement/</guid>
			<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Fill your paper with the breathings of your heart.” – William Wordsworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently taken to the habit of journaling. I have come to appreciate the process of putting your thoughts on paper, and I hope I can convince you to do the same 🧠 📄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-journal&#34;&gt;Why Journal?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journaling as a practice has enormous benefits. The main one that attracted me, was that it helps declutter and lapidify your thoughts.
In the modern internet age, there is a phenomena called &lt;em&gt;information overload&lt;/em&gt;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t actively preserve them, your thoughts end up fleeting, and you lose so many potentially incredible ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>“Fill your paper with the breathings of your heart.” – William Wordsworth</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have recently taken to the habit of journaling. I have come to appreciate the process of putting your thoughts on paper, and I hope I can convince you to do the same 🧠 📄</p>
<h2 id="why-journal">Why Journal?</h2>
<p>Journaling as a practice has enormous benefits. The main one that attracted me, was that it helps declutter and lapidify your thoughts.
In the modern internet age, there is a phenomena called <em>information overload</em>. If you don&rsquo;t actively preserve them, your thoughts end up fleeting, and you lose so many potentially incredible ideas.</p>
<p>Journaling also helps in reflection, which is important in having a healthy mind. Writing down your emotions makes you more mindful and less reactive.</p>
<p>Believe it or not,<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11561925/"> journaling is also known to boost memory and comprehension!</a>.after journaling consistently, you will be able to remember minor details about your day which may be cool to retrospect.</p>
<h2 id="what-do-you-need">What do you need?</h2>
<p>Not a lot. Just a book and a pen (you could also use a <a href="https://obsidian.md">note-taking app like obsidian!</a>)
The process is pretty simple. Set a time when you will write a few words, and then just do it every day.
It can be anything.</p>
<p>Here is a general rule-of-thumb you can use in your daily reviews</p>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> How did I feel today?</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> What cool experience did I have?</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> What did I learn?</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> How can I get better tomorrow?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="gratitude-journaling">Gratitude Journaling</h3>
<p>Your mindset is the most important thing you physically have.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How you do one thing is how you do everything.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have learned that writing down a thing that you are grateful for everyday generally improves your mood throughout the day, and also makes you more humble and content with the things you have</p>
<p>For example, today I am grateful for having access to the internet and interacting with like-minded people who make me better as a person.</p>
<h3 id="mind-on-paper-mentality">Mind-on-paper mentality</h3>
<p>This is a term that I like to use for putting emotions and experiences in a more permanent environment. If you have ever heard of the <a href="https://www.buildingasecondbrain.com">second brain</a>, Essentially it helps you to organize and manage your thoughts more efficiently.</p>
<p>You must understand that <strong>your mind is not made for storing ideas, it is made for making new ones</strong>. Journaling helps you keep track of everything you learn and keeps your mind free of the burden of remembering information.</p>
<h3 id="consistency">Consistency</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>“Success isn’t always about greatness. It’s about consistency. Consistent hard work leads to success. Greatness will come.” — Dwayne Johnson</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With every other self-improvement tool, journaling should become a <em>habit</em>. You must make it a point that no matter what, you must write a journal entry every day.
This helps build discipline as well.</p>
<h3 id="review">Review</h3>
<p>Reviewing past journal entries is highly recommended. It is really fun to do personally, as it is an indicator of how much I have grown as a person (which is my main motivation).
You can also do weekly and monthly review, where instead of thinking in the scale of days, you can review your entire week or month.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>How to Type Faster</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-type-faster/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-type-faster/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;typing-has-become-and-exceedingly-useful-skill-over-the-last-few-years&#34;&gt;Typing has become and exceedingly useful skill over the last few years.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey started with a single link. A friend wanted to compare our typing speeds. At the time, i was pretty slow, having to look down at my keyboard every time I wanted to type a single character (I cringe at the thought, in retrospect).
At the time, everyone were much faster than me, I was at a slow 25 WPM and didn&amp;rsquo;t care much about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="typing-has-become-and-exceedingly-useful-skill-over-the-last-few-years">Typing has become and exceedingly useful skill over the last few years.</h1>
<p>My journey started with a single link. A friend wanted to compare our typing speeds. At the time, i was pretty slow, having to look down at my keyboard every time I wanted to type a single character (I cringe at the thought, in retrospect).
At the time, everyone were much faster than me, I was at a slow 25 WPM and didn&rsquo;t care much about it.</p>
<p>However, in late 2020,I realized the importance of being able to type fast, and have been (and still am!) practicing every single day.</p>
<h2 id="why-type-faster">Why Type Faster?</h2>
<p>Typing faster, personally, has helped me a lot.
If you use your computer even remotely, every single day, typing faster will boost your productivity
Right now i am at around 75-90 WPM(words per minute) and I find that I am able to complete assignments and code much faster and efficiently.</p>
<p>It also really helps when i am trying to text someone and writing notes and blog posts</p>
<h2 id="touch-typing">Touch Typing</h2>
<p>There is a methodology to typing. To get faster, you should really learn to type without looking at your keyboard.
I recommend websites like <a href="http://typing.com">http://typing.com</a> and <a href="https://www.typingclub.com">https://www.typingclub.com</a>.
It may be really hard at first, but the most important thing that you should learn is the <strong>muscle memory.</strong></p>
<h2 id="what-kind-of-keyboards-to-use">What kind of keyboards to use?</h2>
<p>There are two main types of keyboards, <em>membrane</em> and <em>mechanical</em>. Although I will not be covering the differences completely, you can read more <a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/difference-between-membrane-keyboard-and-mechanical-keyboard/">here.</a></p>
<p>I have used both, and personally, i find mechanical keyboards to be a lot more useful for practicing.
However, the keyboard you use statistically doesn&rsquo;t matter, hence I recommend you use which ever type that you like!</p>
<h2 id="layouts">Layouts</h2>
<p>Layouts have become really controversial in the typing community. The one I use, and the one you are probably using too, is the American QWERTY layout. It is the most universal layout that you can find in almost all commercial keyboards.</p>
<p>There are some alternative layouts like COLEMAK or DVORAK.
I recommend researching them if you are really serious about increasing your typing efficiency</p>
<h2 id="websites">Websites</h2>
<p>There are a bunch of typing websites that are only a Google search away.</p>
<p>The websites i use the most are <a href="https://play.typeracer.com">typeracer</a> and <a href="http://monkeytype.com">monkeytype</a>.I usually switch between them every once in a while depending on the type of practice I want to do.</p>
<p>Fair warning though: switching between websites too often isn&rsquo;t that good either as you have to continuously adjust your typing style (different websites have different error counting mechanisms) and you wouldn&rsquo;t have a good general statistical growth of your typing sleep.</p>
<h2 id="practice">Practice</h2>
<p>This may be kinda cliché, but remember, <strong>practice makes perfect.</strong> Don&rsquo;t expect a 200 WPM+ right away. Practicing regularly over a long period of time is the only way to get really fast. Also,it is important to work on the accuracy.
I time block my calendar to do about 15 mins of deliberate typing practice every day, and it helps me get in the zone quickly</p>
<h2 id="other-resources">Other Resources</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ArVtCQqQRE">Ali Abdaal&rsquo;s video</a>, along with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oOdfefV2R1I">NoThisIsJohn&rsquo;s</a> provided me a solid foundation, with additional, more nuanced tips…if you want to learn more about the art of typing, be sure to head on there!</p>
<p>Remember,<strong>practice makes perfect!</strong></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Benefits of Cold Showers</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/benefits-of-cold-showers/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/benefits-of-cold-showers/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;cold-showers-are-becoming-cool-again&#34;&gt;Cold Showers are becoming cool again.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the lifestyles of US Marines, to the legendary Wim Hof (AKA the Iceman), cold showers have become synonymous with the Healthy Grind set.
Many reports, backed by plenty of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5025014/&#34;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; have found pretty eye-opening benefits from this seemingly trivial ritual. Some benefits often talked about are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased testosterone/alertness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stronger Immunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster Recovery after exercising&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better Skin Quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helps in burning fat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sounds-good-but-why&#34;&gt;Sounds good… But why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that the idea of cold showers is more of a mindset thing. In the current day and age, most of us take things for granted and become very &lt;em&gt;comfortable&lt;/em&gt; with our lives. This is a problem because the moment we bask in the luxuries of modern living, we &lt;strong&gt;stop growing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="cold-showers-are-becoming-cool-again">Cold Showers are becoming cool again.</h2>
<p>From the lifestyles of US Marines, to the legendary Wim Hof (AKA the Iceman), cold showers have become synonymous with the Healthy Grind set.
Many reports, backed by plenty of <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5025014/">studies</a> have found pretty eye-opening benefits from this seemingly trivial ritual. Some benefits often talked about are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Increased testosterone/alertness</li>
<li>Stronger Immunity</li>
<li>Faster Recovery after exercising</li>
<li>Better Skin Quality</li>
<li>Helps in burning fat</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="sounds-good-but-why">Sounds good… But why?</h2>
<p>I think that the idea of cold showers is more of a mindset thing. In the current day and age, most of us take things for granted and become very <em>comfortable</em> with our lives. This is a problem because the moment we bask in the luxuries of modern living, we <strong>stop growing</strong>.</p>
<p>Cold showers, to me, is a metaphorical journey to <em>seek discomfort</em> (one of my favorite catch lines, well done yes theory).</p>
<p>Even if it may not theoretically offer any benefits, it&rsquo;s the way of the Stoic… Actively trying to feel uncomfortable in order to grow as a person.</p>
<h2 id="methodology-to-taking-cold-showers">Methodology to taking cold Showers</h2>
<p>There are three common ways of talking cold Showers</p>
<ol>
<li>transitioning from hot-to-cold</li>
<li>edging into the cold</li>
<li>jumping straight into the cold stream
It may be extremely uncomfortable for about 5 seconds, but the feeling passes soon after.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="my-experience">My experience</h2>
<p>At the time of writing this blog, i have personally taken cold showers every morning for a week. It feels absolutely brilliant with higher levels of motivation and alertness. This, along with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tybOi4hjZFQ">Wim Hof&rsquo;s breathing technique,</a> has given me days of more happiness, energy and confidence.</p>
<p>Step out of your comfort zone, and you shall do wonders.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Concept of Motivation:How to Always Get Things Done</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/the-concept-of-motivation---how-to-always-get-things-done/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/the-concept-of-motivation---how-to-always-get-things-done/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation-has-a-shelf-life&#34;&gt;Motivation has a shelf life.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It changes like the weather.
Although it is a seasonal phenomenon, it still carries a great deal of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I aim to explain how you can motivate yourself to do hard habits, even though you may feel low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-one-genuinely-be-interested-in-whatever-you-want-to-pursue&#34;&gt;Step One: Genuinely be interested in whatever you want to pursue.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot be internally motivated to do anything when you do not like doing it. If you pursue a skill or task that you generally like (or have a strong incentive to do), you are more likely to have the motivation to become very good at it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="motivation-has-a-shelf-life">Motivation has a shelf life.</h2>
<p>It changes like the weather.
Although it is a seasonal phenomenon, it still carries a great deal of power.</p>
<p>In this blog post, I aim to explain how you can motivate yourself to do hard habits, even though you may feel low.</p>
<h2 id="step-one-genuinely-be-interested-in-whatever-you-want-to-pursue">Step One: Genuinely be interested in whatever you want to pursue.</h2>
<p>You cannot be internally motivated to do anything when you do not like doing it. If you pursue a skill or task that you generally like (or have a strong incentive to do), you are more likely to have the motivation to become very good at it.</p>
<p>If you are not sure on whether you actually like the task, It is a good idea to introspect and really think about it.<em>(noting down your thoughts in a journal or diary is super useful!)</em></p>
<h2 id="step-two-unlock-the-power-of-consistency">Step Two: Unlock the power of consistency.</h2>
<p>It is a common fallacy that to do difficult tasks, you need to take drastic measures. The greatest achievements come out of small actions done <em>consistently</em>.
If you have the dream of becoming a great magician, you don&rsquo;t have to do a show every day. This will actually <strong>drain</strong> your motivation since it is very intensive.</p>
<p>Instead, all you have to do is do a single trick a day, and when all those days compound, and you will find yourself at the top.</p>
<h2 id="step-three-fall-and-get-up-again">Step Three: Fall and get up again.</h2>
<p>In any journey, there will inevitably be rainy days. You may make mistakes while developing a habit, and that is absolutely okay.
Failure is an integral part of growth. What matters is that you continue doing it, even if you feel like giving up. <strong>Even doing 1% every day is enough to keep you going.</strong>
To give an example, today I feel particularly lethargic. However, I want to become a good blogger, so I wrote down the draft of this post even if I didn&rsquo;t feel like it. I know that once I finish this post I will feel a sense of accomplishment and that&rsquo;s what keep&rsquo;s me going.</p>
<h2 id="step-four-introspect">Step Four: Introspect.</h2>
<p>You may reach a point where you feel you have plateaued, or not progressing anymore. At this point, it is crucial that you analyze your techniques related to the habit. A few questions I like to ask myself when I plateau are:</p>
<ul>
<li>what have you been doing good?</li>
<li>Where could you possibly improve?</li>
<li>What new things (related to the habit) are you interested in learning/doing.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="bonus-step-get-an-accountability-partner">Bonus Step: Get an accountability partner</h2>
<p>I found it useful to have someone else who learns a skill alongside me. Be it a friend, family member or even some random people on discord. You could also share what you have learned with your partner, which helps in finding new ideas/concepts(Learn — Do — Teach paradigm). Accountability partners are a sure-fire way to up the stakes to keep yourself motivated to continue doing/learning a task.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Atomic Habits by James Clear:Book Review</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/atomic-habits-by-james-clear/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/atomic-habits-by-james-clear/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-is-a-legendary-book-its-reputation-proceeds-it&#34;&gt;This is a legendary book, its reputation proceeds it.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the productivity greats like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/electrickeye91&#34;&gt;Thomas Frank&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/c/aliabdaal/videos&#34;&gt;Ali Abdaal&lt;/a&gt; have recommended it…so this month I have decided to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And boy, does it deliver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-ideas&#34;&gt;Core ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I think we should define what an “Atomic Habit” really is.
Many of us think that to be successful, we should do great feats…but in fact, that is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; true at all!
The Greatest achievements come from the smallest changes that are done &lt;em&gt;consistently&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="this-is-a-legendary-book-its-reputation-proceeds-it">This is a legendary book, its reputation proceeds it.</h2>
<p>All the productivity greats like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/electrickeye91">Thomas Frank</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/aliabdaal/videos">Ali Abdaal</a> have recommended it…so this month I have decided to check it out.</p>
<p>And boy, does it deliver.</p>
<h2 id="core-ideas">Core ideas</h2>
<p>First, I think we should define what an “Atomic Habit” really is.
Many of us think that to be successful, we should do great feats…but in fact, that is <strong>not</strong> true at all!
The Greatest achievements come from the smallest changes that are done <em>consistently</em>.</p>
<p>The Idea that stuck out to me the most was growing everyday by just <strong>one percent.</strong> It may not be that noticeable at first, but it is indeed meaningful in the long run.</p>
<p>If you improve by a single % every day for a whole year…you would be 365 (or 366!) percent better than you were at the start of the year!</p>
<p>Growth is not linear, it is compounded, which I genuinely find a good thing!</p>
<p>Even though you will find minimum results for your effort when you start, later on the curve you will find yourself gaining more out of less effort, which is truly amazing!</p>
<h3 id="systems-over-goals">Systems over Goals</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>the purpose of setting goals is to win the game. The purpose of building systems is to continue playing the game.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In habit building, there is no rigid end point.it is a continuous process of self-development and refining until you are the best you can be.
Therefore, looking for longevity rather than instant gratification in habit building proves more successful in the long run.</p>
<h3 id="habits-shape-your-identity">Habits shape your identity</h3>
<p>Why do you want to become fit? Why do you want to become better at drawing/cooking/playing a sport?
Identity matters when it comes to habit building. In case you want to start a new habit (such as eating healthier because you are becoming overweight), you should lean in to making the habit as a part of who you are, as it will make it more likely that it sticks.</p>
<ul>
<li>Whenever you write a blog post, you become a blogger</li>
<li>every time you exercise, you become a healthier person.</li>
</ul>
<p>Its constant self affirmation that brings you to whom you want to be.</p>
<ul>
<li>Habits are behaviors that when repeated, they become subconscious and automatic</li>
<li>the purpose of habits is to solve problems with as little effort as possible</li>
<li>the 4 steps of habits are cues, cravings, response, reward
<ul>
<li>To give an example, today I made my first <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B9QE3Snono8">YouTube video</a></li>
<li>cue: making a to-do and constant reminders from my dad</li>
<li>craving: actually starting my YouTube channel, linking it to my blog</li>
<li>response: learning to edit the best i can that future videos become easier</li>
<li>reward: I&rsquo;m going to order some food today :D (shawarma or pizza, haven&rsquo;t decided yet)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="the-4-laws-of-behavior-change">The 4 laws of behavior change</h3>
<ol>
<li>make it obvious
<ul>
<li>if I want to read a book, I should keep the books close to me</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>make it attractive
<ul>
<li>getting books that interest you to develop a habit of reading</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>make it easily
<ul>
<li>I don&rsquo;t like brushing manually, so an electric tooth brush helps me brush more regularly</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>make it satisfying
<ul>
<li>seeing that you are progressing as a person over time and logging it</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="now-for-the-most-powerful-idea">Now for the most powerful Idea,</h3>
<p>habit stacking.
In the pasts, I used to follow were rigid schedules/to-do lists.
Sure, I used to use them and all was fine for a few days but with life, changes always happen, and it gets difficult to stick to things after a while</p>
<p>Habit stacks are, less rigid, frameworks of how you want to go about your day. It is vague enough to allow distractions, but still asserts that you grow 1% in that day.</p>
<p>You put habits that you want to do in between a habit that you do regularly (waking up to taking a shower) and a habit that you enjoy (playing video games or playing with your dog)</p>
<p>The end of the book has a powerful line that I think sums up everything well,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>tiny changes, remarkable results. That&rsquo;s the power of Atomic Habits.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can find the book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Atomic-Habits-Proven-Build-Break/dp/0735211299">here</a> and I recommend everyone to at least give it a shot and watch your habits compound.</p>
<p>Happy reading!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Digital Minimalism by Cal Newport: Book Review</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/digital-minimilism-by-cal-newport--book-review/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 16:06:37 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/digital-minimilism-by-cal-newport--book-review/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yet-another-cal-newport-review-ay&#34;&gt;Yet Another Cal Newport Review, ay?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be beginning to notice a pattern here. But seriously, The man is such an intuitive and practical writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are anything like me, you may find that a lot of precious time gets sucked away by the internet, or digital world. In fact, this has become such a problem that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2015/04/09/teens-social-media-technology-2015/&#34;&gt;92% of teens go online daily, and 24% say they go online “almost constantly.”&lt;/a&gt;
The internet may be really useful, but if it manages to control US, we know that we are making some serious mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="yet-another-cal-newport-review-ay">Yet Another Cal Newport Review, ay?</h2>
<p>You may be beginning to notice a pattern here. But seriously, The man is such an intuitive and practical writer.</p>
<p>If you are anything like me, you may find that a lot of precious time gets sucked away by the internet, or digital world. In fact, this has become such a problem that <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2015/04/09/teens-social-media-technology-2015/">92% of teens go online daily, and 24% say they go online “almost constantly.”</a>
The internet may be really useful, but if it manages to control US, we know that we are making some serious mistakes.</p>
<p>This great book aims to give us a solution to this problem, and bare with me… It is not as radical as it seems.</p>
<p>The main premise is to advocate a more mindful/intentional way of using the technology beaming into our faces, rather than cutting out the use of it completely.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Digital Minimalism: A philosophy of technology use in which you focus your online time on a small number of carefully selected and optimized activities that strongly support things you value, and then happily miss out on everything else.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It is brought to our attention that the big Social Media Conglomerates are manufactured with the intention to capture your screen time.</p>
<p>Think about it. How many times have you opened Reddit, Instagram, or YouTube and start browsing, browsing, browsing, and then notice that you have been looking at cat memes for about 4 hours!</p>
<p>Digital Minimalism offers extensive and practice solutions to this problem
to name a few, there are:</p>
<ul>
<li>embracing solitude (the book talks about how solitude is more important than it may seem)</li>
<li>participate in active leisure rather than passive leisure (i.e., it&rsquo;s better to play a sport with friends or learn a new skill than to binge-watch Netflix)</li>
<li>do a digital detox/declutter (refrain from non-essential internet use for a period of 30 days to reset your compulsive habits)</li>
<li>start active socializing (talking to friends face to face generates greater satisfaction and meaningful conversations opposed to low bandwidth text messaging)</li>
</ul>
<p>A digital minimalist values <em>benefit</em> over everything else. Its basic economics. If something doesn&rsquo;t give better returns on investment, it might as well be booted.
To put it simply, if something <em>costs</em> more than it <em>produces</em>, it is not worth your effort.
(cost doesn&rsquo;t necessarily need to mean <strong>money</strong>, it can also be applied to time or something valuable.)</p>
<p>The book promises that with mindful behavior regarding technology, your productivity, and wellbeing would increase exponentially more than if you took everything in the digital world at face value.</p>
<p>We are entering a new era, a strange era of massive amounts of information our primitive minds cannot handle.
If we are reasonable with this power, we will succeed as a species.</p>
<h3 id="footnotes">Footnotes</h3>
<p>Read the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digital-Minimalism-Choosing-Focused-Noisy/dp/0525536515">book</a>. Seriously.</p>
<p>Thank you to <a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/">cal&rsquo;s</a> and <a href="https://www.samuelthomasdavies.com/book-summaries/business/digital-minimalism/">Samuel D. Davis&rsquo;s</a> blogs for helping me consolidate my thoughts.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>The Importance of Sleep in Learning</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/the-importance-of-sleep-in-learning/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/the-importance-of-sleep-in-learning/</guid>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing this blog post at 11:55 AM out of a great need to express my thoughts about sleep,the tame death that envelopes us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that in our modern world,sleep is often put aside,or even overlooked. I have recently found a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2016/p0215-enough-sleep.html&#34;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by the american goverment that asserts that 1 in 3 adults &lt;strong&gt;are chronically sleep deprived.&lt;/strong&gt; These numbers are shocking and should make us reconsider our &lt;em&gt;view&lt;/em&gt; on sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am writing this blog post at 11:55 AM out of a great need to express my thoughts about sleep,the tame death that envelopes us all.</p>
<p>I find that in our modern world,sleep is often put aside,or even overlooked. I have recently found a <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2016/p0215-enough-sleep.html">study</a> by the american goverment that asserts that 1 in 3 adults <strong>are chronically sleep deprived.</strong> These numbers are shocking and should make us reconsider our <em>view</em> on sleep.</p>
<h1 id="why-is-sleep-important">Why is sleep important?</h1>
<p>Sleep is your bodies way of winding down after a long day.
You may not know it,but there is a lot of wear-and-tear happening in your body every moment that you are alive.
hundreds of cells die and new cells <em>should</em> be able to regenerate in a healthy human being.</p>
<p>There is also a lot of hormones that flood your blood stream when you are in deep sleep.Melatonin and Growth Horomones that get released during deep sleep is essential for healthy body development.</p>
<h1 id="how-can-sleep-help-me-learn-stuff">How can sleep help me learn stuff?</h1>
<p>Imagine you had a test in 8 hours.Most people,in this situation(especially the people who didnt study!) would be inclined to stay up all night and cram as much difficult informaiton as they can.</p>
<p>But alas,this teqnique that has become commonplace today is in fact,doing more harm than good.</p>
<p>Sleep is a time where your brain consolidates information you gather throughout your day.Your brain processes your memories and makes it easier to recall difficult information</p>
<p>even short powernaps can have this effect. So if you were to be short on time,reading all the information and then having a nap is a thing i would advise.</p>
<p>Even if you werent technically &ldquo;<em>studying</em>&rdquo; &hellip;sleep definitely helps you understand a subject,or topic a lot better passively.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Deep Work by Cal Newport:Book Review</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/deep-work-by-cal-newport-book-review/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 11:57:29 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/deep-work-by-cal-newport-book-review/</guid>
			<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;productivity-books-we-all-read-them&#34;&gt;Productivity books, we all read them&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kinda is becoming my guilty pleasure at this point. However, I have to give the book “Deep Work” some credit.
Although this is my second reading, I still find enormous meaning from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is a non-fiction thesis on how “knowledge work” is valued in the economy, and how top achievers actually succeed. It also tackles the idea of “information overload” in our modern digital age.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="productivity-books-we-all-read-them">Productivity books, we all read them</h1>
<p>kinda is becoming my guilty pleasure at this point. However, I have to give the book “Deep Work” some credit.
Although this is my second reading, I still find enormous meaning from it.</p>
<p>The book is a non-fiction thesis on how “knowledge work” is valued in the economy, and how top achievers actually succeed. It also tackles the idea of “information overload” in our modern digital age.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-deep-work">What is Deep Work?</h1>
<blockquote>
<p>“Professional activity performed in a state of distraction-free concentration that push your cognitive capabilities to their limit. These efforts create new value, improve your skill, and are hard to replicate.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Deep Work, in contrast to shallow work, is truly valuable in today&rsquo;s economy. For example, 30 minutes of coding is much more “valuable” than 30 mins of email/message responding.
Deep work is long, uninterrupted segments of intense focus that enables you to make quality work.
Deep work is the work that enables one to produce their Magnum Opus, or at least work that they would be proud of.</p>
<h1 id="how-did-the-best-become-the-greatest">How did the best become the greatest?</h1>
<p>One thing that really stood out to me while reading was the formula of work quality.</p>
<p>$$ \ Quality \ of \ work = \ Time \ spent \times \ Intensity \ of \ focus $$
Newport gives numerous examples of winners in the economy who are successful because of their <em>methodology</em> to how they carry about doing their work.
In this hyper-interconnected world, it happens that the achieves in their respective fields disconnect themselves for extended periods of time in order to satisfy this equation.</p>
<p>Cal denounces the culture of companies ordering their employs to maintain twitter/emails, and even open air offices, as they hinder in general productivity</p>
<p>Another interesting concept is the idea of <strong>attention residue</strong>. The book tells us that when we switch tasks in rapid succession, which has become the new normal in the multitasker-hustler fad we have today, is a terrible practice that both reduces attention, and quality of work.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-in-it-for-meyou">What is in it for me/you?</h1>
<p>So far, I have been a man of shallow work. This book really made me reconsider how I practice work.
I highly recommend the book to anyone who has the hunger for success in this ever-changing economy.</p>
<p>You can find the book on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00X47ZVXM">Amazon</a></p>
<p>Happy reading!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Learning to Hack: A Resource Guide</title>
			<link>//localhost:1313/posts/learning-to-hack---a-resource-guide./</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 10:54:36 +0530</pubDate>
			
			<guid>//localhost:1313/posts/learning-to-hack---a-resource-guide./</guid>
			<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-a-hacker-sounds-really-cool&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being a hacker sounds really cool.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do you become one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this resource guide, i will try to tackle this question by identifying a few essential &lt;em&gt;skills and websites&lt;/em&gt; that helped (and is continuing to help) me learn how to hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-googling&#34;&gt;1. googling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most underrated and valuable skills to have as someone who works with computers. Being able to &lt;em&gt;find information&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;research&lt;/em&gt; will certainly get you further in the cybersphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="being-a-hacker-sounds-really-cool"><strong>Being a hacker sounds really cool.</strong></h2>
<p>But how do you become one?</p>
<p>In this resource guide, i will try to tackle this question by identifying a few essential <em>skills and websites</em> that helped (and is continuing to help) me learn how to hack.</p>
<h1 id="1-googling">1. googling</h1>
<p>This is one of the most underrated and valuable skills to have as someone who works with computers. Being able to <em>find information</em> and <em>research</em> will certainly get you further in the cybersphere.</p>
<h1 id="2-linux">2. Linux</h1>
<p>Anyone who aspires to become a hacker <strong>must</strong> have at least a passable knowledge of Linux. Although you could work with operating systems like Windows or macOS, it is ill-advised because <em>most tools and framework</em> are made for Linux in specific.</p>
<p>Popular hacking (more commonly called as “pentesting”) frameworks like Kali Linux or Parrot OS have a lot of tools built-in, which is very convenient</p>
<h1 id="3-capture-the-flag">3. Capture the flag</h1>
<p>Now we are starting to enter the more interesting stuff!</p>
<p>Capture the flag (CTFs) are mini-games that are hosted on a platform to enable hackers to practice their skills in a safe environment.
Most CTFs have a system wherein you have to enumerate a system and find a certain file or so-called “flag”</p>
<p>one of my favorite CTF is the <a href="https://overthewire.org/wargames/">over the wire</a>, and it really helped me to start off</p>
<h1 id="4tryhackme-boxes">4.TryHackMe boxes</h1>
<p><a href="https://tryhackme.com/">TryHackMe</a> is an excellent website to start understanding tools and frameworks.
They have amazing rooms like the metasploit and nmap walkthroughs that really help you grasp how a tool or a framework works.</p>
<p>You can also go down one of their <a href="https://tryhackme.com/paths">learning paths</a>, which will have your understanding a concept at a deeper level.</p>
<h1 id="where-next">Where Next?</h1>
<p>Assuming you have done all the above, you can say with certainty that you have <strong>mastered the basics of hacking.</strong></p>
<p>&#x1f38a; congrats!
Your next step might be researching about fun domains like <strong>Bug bounties</strong> or <strong>freelance pentesting.</strong></p>
<p>else, you may also want to do rooms (similar to TryHackMe) on <a href="https://app.hackthebox.eu/">HackTheBox</a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
