<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Aban Hasan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:57783/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Aban Hasan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 17:23:57 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:57783/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning From Media vs Learning From Experience: Which Is Better?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:57783/posts/mediavsexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 17:23:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:57783/posts/mediavsexperience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;times-have-changed&#34;&gt;Times have changed.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, the man who can adapt the fastest and handle the most information is the man who wins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This shift in focus of the economy from physical labor to &lt;em&gt;intellectual&lt;/em&gt; labor has created an industry around learning, in contrast to education.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This industry is what I like to call, the &lt;strong&gt;absorb and learn&lt;/strong&gt; niche, which serves information through media like:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;watchable courses (YouTube, udemy, skillshare and the plethora of other course providers)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;pamphlets and books&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;certifications&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All these options, makes it more difficult to choose a medium and stick with it. Personally,i find myself searching on sites rather than actually doing some deliberate practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Drain of Studying and How to Deal With It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:57783/posts/the-mental-drain-of-studying-and-how-to-deal-with-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 18:45:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:57783/posts/the-mental-drain-of-studying-and-how-to-deal-with-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-mental-drain-of-studying&#34;&gt;The mental drain of Studying&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of us approach studying as a chore just because our parents, teachers and society in general expects us to do well in our academics. The academic journey can be rather inundating and boring. The very thought of studying and examinations can cause a lot of distress for students(at least I can speak for myself).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-can-be-studying-so-difficult&#34;&gt;Why can be studying so difficult&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;studying may not be the most appealing thing in the world. Sitting for multiple hours looking at static books is not exactly what our survivalist brains were made for. There are a myriad of reasons why we may find studying undesirable, some of them being:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Sleep in Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:57783/posts/the-importance-of-sleep-in-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:57783/posts/the-importance-of-sleep-in-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing this blog post at 11:55 AM out of a great need to express my thoughts about sleep,the tame death that envelopes us all.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I find that in our modern world,sleep is often put aside,or even overlooked. I have recently found a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2016/p0215-enough-sleep.html&#34;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by the american goverment that asserts that 1 in 3 adults &lt;strong&gt;are chronically sleep deprived.&lt;/strong&gt; These numbers are shocking and should make us reconsider our &lt;em&gt;view&lt;/em&gt; on sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
