<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Society on Aban Hasan</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/society/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Society on Aban Hasan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Silicon &amp; Six-Shooters: AI as Manifest Destiny</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/cowboys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/cowboys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be in software in 2025 is to be a cowboy in 1900. You&amp;rsquo;re living on the precipice of a bygone era, one that you barely comprehend is gone, as the industrial giants and their Pinkerton armies push you further west, towards an unknown horizon. The open range is closing, fences are going up, and the rules are changing. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a shift; it&amp;rsquo;s a reckoning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/cowboy_city.png&#34; alt=&#34;A lone cowboy gazing at a futuristic city skyline&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeding the Hydra: Musings on Cyberslavery</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/cyber-slaves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/cyber-slaves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clarity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All we seek is clarity. Yet, it appears that everything around us – everything we see, everything we touch – is designed to be noisy, to disrupt every thought we have before it can fully form. Entire teams of researchers, scientists, psychologists devote their lives to finding and &amp;ldquo;pulling the right&amp;rdquo; switch in our minds, optimizing for engagement, for distraction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our inherent capital – the finite time and vibrant youth we possess – is systematically siphoned off to feed the mainframe, the ever-hungry digital systems that thrive on our attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Grain Trap: How Diet Shapes Destiny Through Lamarckian Lenses</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/grain-vitality-and-the-lamarckian-lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/grain-vitality-and-the-lamarckian-lens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/grain-vitality-header.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ancient grains scattered across a weathered wooden surface, representing the historical relationship between human civilization and cereal cultivation&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The substrate of civilization: grain has shaped not just our agriculture, but our very biology and consciousness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-uncomfortable-truth&#34;&gt;The Uncomfortable Truth&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a statement that makes people squirm: &amp;ldquo;The most emaciated, low-vitality cultures that racists berate eat the most grain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before you recoil, pause. What if we flipped this from an ugly stereotype into a &lt;strong&gt;scientific hypothesis&lt;/strong&gt;? What if the apparent &amp;ldquo;low vitality&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t about racial essence, but about &lt;strong&gt;environmental programming&lt;/strong&gt;—a neo-Lamarckian process where persistent dietary inputs literally reshape human biology, microbiomes, and cultural institutions across generations?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
