<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>well-being on Byte Geek</title>
    <link>/tags/well-being/</link>
    <description>Recent content in well-being on Byte Geek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/well-being/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Practice of Journaling in Self-Improvement</title>
      <link>/posts/the-practice-of-journaling-in-self-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-practice-of-journaling-in-self-improvement/</guid>
      <description>“Fill your paper with the breathings of your heart.” – William Wordsworth
 I have recently taken to the habit of journaling. I have come to appreciate the process of putting your thoughts on paper, and I hope I can convince you to do the same 🧠 📄
Why Journal? Journaling as a practice has enormous benefits. The main one that attracted me, was that it helps declutter and lapidify your thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Cold Showers</title>
      <link>/posts/benefits-of-cold-showers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/benefits-of-cold-showers/</guid>
      <description>Cold Showers are becoming cool again. From the lifestyles of US Marines, to the legendary Wim Hof (AKA the Iceman), cold showers have become synonymous with the Healthy Grind set. Many reports, backed by plenty of studies have found pretty eye-opening benefits from this seemingly trivial ritual. Some benefits often talked about are:
 Increased testosterone/alertness Stronger Immunity Faster Recovery after exercising Better Skin Quality Helps in burning fat  Sounds good… But why?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Sleep in Learning</title>
      <link>/posts/the-importance-of-sleep-in-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 23:49:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-importance-of-sleep-in-learning/</guid>
      <description>I am writing this blog post at 11:55 AM out of a great need to express my thoughts about sleep,the tame death that envelopes us all.
I find that in our modern world,sleep is often put aside,or even overlooked. I have recently found a study by the american goverment that asserts that 1 in 3 adults are chronically sleep deprived. These numbers are shocking and should make us reconsider our view on sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
