<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self Improvement on Aban Hasan</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/self-improvement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self Improvement on Aban Hasan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:08:35 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neuroplasticity: How to Manipulate Reality</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/neuroplasticity---how-to-manipulate-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:08:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/neuroplasticity---how-to-manipulate-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-remarkable-capacity-for-change-in-the-human-brain&#34;&gt;The Remarkable Capacity for Change in the Human Brain&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most people go through their entire lives without truly understanding the astonishing potential for change that exists within the human brain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is commonly believed that our capacity for learning diminishes over time, with the assumption that we can only learn effectively during our childhood years. While this may be true for the majority, I argue that by following specific protocols, not only can we sustain learning throughout our lives, but we can also enhance it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing What You Got to Do: A Systematic Pathway to Success</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/doing-what-you-got-to-do--a-systematic-pathway-to-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 11:01:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/doing-what-you-got-to-do--a-systematic-pathway-to-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;there-is-something-extremely-important-that-i-have-learned-over-the-last-few-months&#34;&gt;There is something extremely important that I have learned over the last few months.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If one has gotten into their self-improvement journey, they will eventually realize one thing: you would have to &lt;strong&gt;do the hard work, ESPECIALLY when you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;There is great power in getting something hard or boring to become a routine habit just by doing it repeatedly. Imagine going to the gym in the morning without a single word of protest every day. Or… studying for 6 hours with no feelings of resentment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Practice of Journaling in Self-Improvement</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/the-practice-of-journaling-in-self-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/the-practice-of-journaling-in-self-improvement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Fill your paper with the breathings of your heart.” – William Wordsworth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have recently taken to the habit of journaling. I have come to appreciate the process of putting your thoughts on paper, and I hope I can convince you to do the same 🧠 📄&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-journal&#34;&gt;Why Journal?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Journaling as a practice has enormous benefits. The main one that attracted me, was that it helps declutter and lapidify your thoughts.&#xA;In the modern internet age, there is a phenomena called &lt;em&gt;information overload&lt;/em&gt;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t actively preserve them, your thoughts end up fleeting, and you lose so many potentially incredible ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
